翻譯：彼岸荼蘼
翻譯：愛卿遛小鳥
翻譯：小蠻腰
翻譯：windend7
翻譯：章魚埃克斯
翻譯：ntexplorer
翻譯：CiciXT
翻譯：Reginamoon
翻譯：薄荷小瑾
翻譯：小英的小號
翻譯：德尼
翻譯：通信小王子
校對：CiciXT
校對：吃貨丁小七
校對：木淺薰
后期：松子
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特股份有限公司
華爾街
投資者的世界就像叢林
The world of investing can be a jungle.
牛市  熊市
Bulls. Bears.
危機四伏
Danger at every turn.
我們斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的員工
That's why we at Stratton Oakmont
作為叢林之王感到無比自豪
pride ourselves on being the best.
我們有訓練有素的專業人員
Trained professionals to guide you
引領您穿越金融領域的荒野險境
through the financial wilderness.
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特
Stratton Oakmont.
堅實可靠
Stability.
誠實經營
Integrity.
讓您引以為傲
Pride.
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特股份有限公司
一
One!
二
Two!
三
Three!
第一個扔中靶心的混蛋我白送兩萬五千塊
Twenty-five grand to the first cocksucker who nail a bull's-eye!
來吧  開始
Come on! Let's go!
一
One!
二
Two!
三
Three!
我叫喬丹·貝爾福
My name is Jordan Belfort.
不是他
Not him.
是我  沒錯
Me. That's right.
我以前是個中產階級
I'm a former member of the middle class
父母都是會計
raised by two accountants
在皇后區貝賽的一個小公寓里長大
in a tiny apartment in Bayside, Queens.
我26歲那年
The year I turned 26,
作為老總在自己的經濟公司
as the head of my own brokerage firm,
賺了4900萬
I made $49 million,
說來還真讓我不爽
which really pissed me off
還差300萬就是一周賺100萬了
because it was three shy of a million a week.
不不不   我的法拉利是白色的
No, no, no. My Ferrari was white,
和《邁阿密風云》里唐·約翰遜的一樣
like Don Johnson's in Miami Vice.
不是紅的
Not red.
看見那座莊園了嗎
See that humongous estate down there?
那是我的房子
That's my house.
我妻子內奧米
My wife, Naomi,
布魯克林灣脊區的女公爵
the Duchess of Bay Ridge, Brooklyn,
以前是模特  拍過美樂淡啤的廣告
a former model and Miller Lite girl.
沒錯
Yeah.
剛在法拉利里給我口交就是她
She was the one with my cock in her mouth in the Ferrari.
所以把你的老二塞回褲襠里吧
So put your dick back in your pants.
除了內奧米和兩個可愛的孩子
In addition to Naomi and my two perfect kids,
我還有一座豪宅  一架私人飛機
I own a mansion, a private jet,
六輛豪車  三匹駿馬
six cars, three horses,
兩處度假別墅和一艘170英尺長的游艇
two vacation homes, and a 170-foot yacht.
起錨了
Anchors aweigh!
我還賭博成癮  嗜酒成性
I also gamble like a degenerate. I drink like a fish.
一周能上五六次小姐
I fuck hookers maybe five, six times a week.
三所不同的聯邦機構盯著想起訴我
I have three different federal agencies looking to indict me.
我還酷愛嗑藥
Oh, yeah, and I love drugs.
再來一輪
One more round.
-你喜歡嗎  -喜歡
- Oh, you like it? - Yeah.
當夜晚些時候...
拉起來  快拉起來
Pull up. Pull up!
快墜機了  老天
We're gonna crash, for Christ sake!
放松
Relax!
別緊張
Just relax.
-你還好吧  -沒事
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm all right.
好樣的
Good job.
回去小心
You get in there safe, all right?
下次見  老兄
Till the next time, brother.
下次見
Till next time.
我每天吃的藥量足夠把
Yup, on a daily basis I consume enough drugs
曼哈頓  長島和皇后區放倒一個月
to sedate Manhattan, Long Island and Queens for a month.
喬丹先生
Okay, Mr. Jordan.
我每天吃10到15片安眠酮緩解"背疼"
I take Quaaludes 10 to 15 times a day for my "Back pain,"
一種治療注意力缺失的藥
吃阿得拉好集中注意力
Adderall to stay focused,
吃佳樂定抗焦慮  抽點大麻放松
Xanax to take the edge off, pot to mellow me out,
嗑點可卡因清醒一下  再來點嗎啡
cocaine to wake me back up again and morphine, well,
因為那玩意真是一級棒
because it's awesome.
早上好  奈森
Good morning, Nathan.
但是世界上所有的藥中
But of all the drugs under God's blue heaven,
有一種我最為愛不釋手
there is one that is my absolute favorite.
嗑夠了這鬼東西你就所向披靡了
You see, enough of this shit'll make you invincible.
足以征服全世界
Able to conquer the world,
殺得敵人片甲不留
and eviscerate your enemies.
我說的不是這個
And I'm not talking about this.
我說的是這個
I'm talking about this.
金錢不僅能給你帶來更好的生活
See, money doesn't just buy you a better life,
更精美的食物  更好的車  更美的妞
better food, better cars, better pussy.
還能讓你成為更好的人
It also makes you a better person.
你可以慷慨資助教會
You can give generously to the church
或你支持的政黨
or political party of your choice.
錢甚至能拯救瀕危的斑點貓頭鷹
You can save the fucking spotted owl with money.
我一直都想當富翁
I always wanted to be rich.
回頭看看過去
So let me go back.
22歲的我  剛結婚
I'm 22 years old, newly married,
就已經是個追名逐利的小混蛋了
and already a money-crazed little shit.
那我怎么辦呢
So what do I do?
我去了唯一一個
I go to the one place on earth
能滿足我野心的地方
that befit my high-minded ambitions.
我愛你
I love you.
你的地位還不如水藻
You are lower than pond scum.
有什么意見嗎
You got a problem with that,
喬丹
Jordan?
沒  完全沒有
No. No problem at all.
很好  因為你現在就這地位
Good. Because that is what you are.
水藻
Pond scum.
你的工作是聯絡員
Your job is connector,
也就是說
which means
你每天要打500多次電話
that you'll be dialing the phone over 500 times a day
想法讓我聯系上有錢的大老板
trying to connect me with wealthy business owners.
在你考下證券經紀人執照前
And until you pass your Series 7,
你他媽也只能干這個  坐下
that is all you're gonna fucking be doing. Sit.
坐下
Sit!
我告訴你  我去年賺了30多萬
Now just so you know, last year I made over $300,000.
你的另一個頭兒  他賺了100多萬
The other guy you'll be working for, he made over a million.
100萬
A million dollars?
可想而知那家伙得多變態
I could only imagine what a douchebag that guy must be.
-喬丹·貝爾福  -是  先生
- Jordan Belfort. - Yes, sir.
-我是馬克·漢納  -很高興認識您
- Mark Hanna. - A pleasure to meet you.
我也是
And you as well.
我看你已經見過那個地頭蛇了
I see you've already met the village asshole.
撥號并微笑
Smile and dial.
1點前別他媽抬頭
And don't pick up your fucking head until 1:00.
甭管他
Hey, fuck him.
我才是高級經紀人
I'm the senior broker here.
他就是個當差的
He's just a worthless piker.
來給我吹個簫吧  漢納
Why don't you blow me, Hanna?
你真在面試的時候賣出去一股嗎
Now did you really pitch a stock in your job interview?
想脫穎而出總得干點實事
I had to do something to stand out.
是吧  先生
Right, sir?
就喜歡你這樣的
I fucking love that.
-中午一起吃飯  -好
- Lunch. Today. - Yeah.
如果我們不在9點半整立刻開始打電話
We don't start dialing at 9:30
我們的客戶就占線了
because our clients are already answering the phone.
三  二  一
Three. Two. One.
干起來吧
Let's fuck!
你想知道金錢聽上去什么樣嗎
You want to know what money sounds like?
去華爾街的交易大廳聽聽吧
Go to a trading floor on Wall Street.
操這個日那個的
"Fuck" This, "Shit" That.
婊子  雞巴  屁眼什么的
"Cunt," "Cock," "Asshole."
這些人說的話簡直讓我難以置信
I couldn't believe how these guys talked to each other.
-這一攬子交易真他媽好  -爛狗屎
- Good fucking package... - Piece of shit!
我當時就著迷了
I was hooked in seconds.
跟打了雞血似的
It was like mainlining adrenaline.
混賬  看看今天股票怎么樣
Yeah. Fuckface, look at where the stock's at today, huh?
日你媽
You motherfucker,
要是44你什么也撈不到
you can't get any at 44...
-快他媽打電話去  -抱歉
- Pick up the cocksucking phone! - Sorry...
你真是個臭傻逼  漢納
You are such a fucking douchebag, Hanna.
我們才不管什么技術
We don't give two shits about how technology works
我們只關心他媽怎么能賺錢
because all we care about is getting fucking rich.
-定了  2000  -喬丹·貝爾福
- Solid, 2,000. - Jordan Belfort.
成功了
Done!
該抬價了[以不正當手段哄抬股價]
Time to paint the tape.
微軟  2000股  上鉤了
2,000. Microsoft. Going in the hole!
過來
Come on.
直播  拿著  小心燙手
Live. Live. Hold on, that is hot.
放進去  把那玩意關上  關上關上
In. In. Shut that motherfucker. Shut it! Shut it! Shut it!
成交了
Sold!
可卡因來點
Tootski?
不用了  謝謝
Oh, no. Thank you, though.
漢納先生
Mr. Hanna,
這么美好的午后  您要來點什么
what can I bring for you on this glorious afternoon?
赫克托  我告訴你怎么玩
Well, Hector, here's the game plan.
給我們上兩杯馬丁尼
You're gonna bring us two Absolut Martinis.
你知道我的口味  要純的
You know how I like them. Straight up.
整7分半后
And then precisely seven and one half minutes after that,
再上兩杯
you're gonna bring us two more.
然后每5隔分鐘上兩杯
Then two more after that every five minutes
直到我倆喝倒一個為止
until one of us passes the fuck out.
這想法不錯  先生
Excellent strategy, sir.
我現在喝水就好
I'm good with water for now.
謝謝
Thank you.
他今天剛來華爾街工作
It's his first day on Wall Street.
他會習慣的
Give him time.
-謝謝  -謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
漢納先生
Mr. Hanna?
你白天嗑了藥
You're able to do drugs during the day
還能正常工作嗎
and then still function, still do your job?
不然你以為怎么正常工作
How the fuck else would you do this job?
就憑可卡因和妓女了  哥們
Cocaine and hookers, my friend.
是
Right.
我想說
Well, I got to say,
能加入你們我真的很高興
I'm incredibly excited to be a part of your firm. I mean...
你們的客戶實在是...
The clients you have are absolutely...
去他媽的客戶
Fuck the clients.
你唯一的職責就是引他們上鉤
Your only responsibility is to put meat on the table.
你有女朋友嗎
You got a girlfriend?
我結婚了
I'm married. I have a wife.
我妻子叫泰瑞莎  理發的
Her name is Teresa. She cuts hair.
-恭喜  -謝謝
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
多想想泰瑞莎
Think about Teresa.
你要干的就是
Name of the game.
把你客戶兜里的錢揣到你兜里
Move the money from your client's pocket into your pocket.
是
Right.
但如果同時能幫客戶賺錢
But if you make your clients money at the same time,
不是互惠互利嗎
it's advantageous to everyone. Correct?
不
No.
華爾街第一要義
Number one rule of Wall Street.
沒有人
Nobody...
不管你是沃倫·巴菲特也好
I don't care if you're Warren Buffett
吉米·巴菲特也好
or if you're Jimmy Buffett.
沒人知道股票是漲是跌
Nobody knows if a stock is gonna go up, down,
是持平還是兜圈子
sideways, or in fucking circles.
股票經紀人更不知道  懂嗎
Least of all stockbrokers, right?
都是掩的  你知道什么叫掩吧
It's all a fugazi. You know what a fugazi is?
"贗"嗎  就是假的
Fugayzie. It's a fake.
什么掩啊贗啊  嫖啊飄啊的
Fugayzi, fugazi, it's a whazy, it's a woozy, it's...
都是虛無縹緲的  根本不存在
Fairy dust. It doesn't exist.
看不見摸不著
It's never landed. It is no matter.
元素周期表上找不到
It's not on the elemental chart.
根本都他媽是假的
It's not fucking real.
-對不  -對
- Right? - Right.
繼續聽我講
Stay with me.
我們屁都不創造  什么都不建
We don't create shit. We don't build anything.
的確
No.
所以假設你有個客戶花8塊買了一股
So if you got a client who bought stock at eight
現在漲到16了  他樂開花了
and it now sits at 16, he's all fucking happy.
就想兌現清算
He wants to cash in, liquidate,
拿上錢打包走人
take his fucking money and run home.
-這可不行  -好的
- You don't let him do that. - Okay.
-因為那樣就成真錢了  -是
- 'Cause that would make it real. - Right.
那該做什么
No. What do you do?
你得繼續給他出金點子
You get another brilliant idea.
額外的想法
A special idea.
制造另一種"情況"
Another "situation."
讓他拿收益再投一支股票  不斷投
Another stock to reinvest his earnings and then some.
他每次也一定會投
And he will, every single time.
因為他們全都他媽是癮君子
'Cause they're fucking addicted.
你就一直這么干
And you just keep doing this,
延綿不斷  無休無止
again and again and again.
他這時覺得自己要成土豪了
Meanwhile, he thinks he's getting shit rich,
理論上他的確賺了
which he is, on paper.
但我們這些經紀人
But you and me, the brokers,
從中收的傭金
we're taking home cold hard cash
可都是實打實的現金  學著沒
via commission, motherfucker.
是
Right.
這太神奇了  老板
That's incredible, sir.
我都激動的無以言表了
I can't tell you how excited I am.
你就該興奮
You should be.
做經紀人這行的成功要素有兩點
There's two keys to success in the broker business.
首先
First of all...
-你得淡定  -是
- You gotta stay relaxed. - Yeah.
你平時擼嗎
Do you jerk off?
擼...擼嗎
Do I... Do I jerk off?
擼  擼啊  我當然擼
Yeah. Yeah, I jerk off. Yeah.
每周幾次
How many times a week?
三四次吧
Like three or four.
三四次  有時五次
Three or four times, maybe five.
你得多擼啊
Gotta pump those numbers up.
干這行  你這次數太菜鳥了
Those are rookie numbers in this racket.
我本人吧  每天至少兩發
I myself, I jerk off at least twice a day.
早晨健身之后來一發
Once in the morning right after I work out,
午飯后再來一發
then once right after lunch.
真的嗎
Really?
我喜歡擼  但我擼不是因為喜歡
I want to. That's not why I do it.
全他媽是被逼的
I do it 'cause I fucking need to.
你想想  你是跟數字打交道的
Think about it. You're dealing with numbers.
整天都是什么小數點啊  高頻交易啊
All day long, decimal points, high frequencies.
全他媽是數
Fucking digits.
每天重任在肩  喘不過氣啊
All very acidic above-the-shoulders mustard shit.
對吧
All right?
太讓人抓狂了  是吧
It kind of wigs some people out. Right.
所以就得多擼  保持血液流通順暢
You got to feed the geese to keep the blood flowing.
私底下控制住節奏
I keep the rhythm below the belt.
懂了
Done.
我這可不是提醒你  我給你開處方呢
This is not a tip, this is a prescription.
相信我
Trust me.
你不這么干  就沒法平衡了
If you don't, you will fall out of balance,
差額搞不清楚你就載了
split your differential and tip the fuck over.
還有更糟的
Or worse yet,
我親眼見過  猝死
I've seen this happen, implode.
別介  我可不想猝死  老板
No, I don't want to implode, sir.
當然  沒人想
No. No, you don't.
我干這行看得很長遠的
I'm in it for the long run, you know?
-猝死可不是什么好事  -是
- Implosions are ugly. - Yeah.
所以有空就去洗手間來一發
Pop off to the bathroom, work one out any time you can.
等你擼順手了
When you get really good at it,
一邊擼著
you'll fucking be stroking it
一邊腦子里想的都是錢
and you'll be thinking about money.
干這行成功要素之二
Second key to success in this racket
就是這瓶子里的寶貝
is this little baby right here.
叫可卡因
It's called cocaine.
是
Right.
能讓你耳聰目明
It'll keep you sharp between the ears.
還能讓你撥號指速如飛
It'll also help your fingers dial faster.
你猜怎么著
And guess what?
你撥號快了  我就賺了
That's good for me.
好了  先生
Yes, sir.
周轉不息  明白嗎
Revolutions. You follow?
周轉不息
Revolutions.
讓客戶坐上摩天輪
Keep the clients on the Ferris wheel.
我們就開賺
And it goes.
游樂園365天全天候給他開著
The park is open 24/7, 365,
十年如一日  百年也他媽這樣
every decade, every goddamn century.
就這么回事
That's it.
這就是游戲規則
The name of the game.
嘗嘗希臘橄欖
Halkidiki?
謝謝
Thank you.
一起來
Come on.
我們是公分母
We're the common denominator.
繼續
Keep it up for me.
你懂這回事
You've seen the echo
我們談著錢
And the money comes in
游行進了城
The parade comes to town
走到百老匯
Going down Broadway
不管往哪去
It's a one-way street
都沒回頭路
Whichever way I go
之后的六個月
The next six months,
我開始了解華爾街的門道
I got to know the ins and outs of Wall Street.
邊賺小錢邊準備考執照
Earning shit money as I geared up to take my Series 7.
真他媽爽
Oh, fuckers.
百老匯120號
后來我終于拿下了執照
Then I was a licensed broker at last,
準備開始掙大錢了
ready to make my fortune.
那天起我開始向未來宇宙之王邁進
My first day as a future Master of the Universe.
1987年10月19日
六個月前埃克森還是86塊2毛5
I have Exxon at 86 and a quarter six months ago.
埃克森美孚  美國著名石化公司
現在都跌到36塊5了
Today it is trading at 36 and a half.
先生  先...
Mr...
他們管那天叫黑色星期一
They called it Black Monday.
1987年10月19日星期一  世界股市價格暴跌
真不是鬧著玩的
No shit.
下午4點  股市已經暴跌了508個點
By 4:00 p.m., the market had dropped 508 points.
是自1929年大蕭條以來
The biggest plummet
最嚴重的一次崩盤
since the crash of '29.
我了解你的家庭  你也了解我的
I know your family, you know mine.
我不知道  歐洲某個傻逼國家干的
No, I don't know. Some fucking country in Europe took a shit.
讓他們玩兒蛋去吧
Let them do what they want to fucking do.
我們的市場固若金湯
Our market's solid.
你不該賣掉這個
This is not something that you want to sell.
你知道怎么回事嗎  簡直金融海嘯
You know what happened? A fucking tsunami.
我覺得你這樣以后要后悔的
I think you're making a big mistake.
好  我可以和你妻子談
Yes, I will talk to your wife.
相信我  別接電話
Trust me, do not answer the phone.
會有許多人給您致電
A lot of people are gonna be calling you,
要挖您的家丑
trying to get your dirty laundry.
我們不知道怎么回事
We don't know what's going on here.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我了個
Holy
大操
fucking shit!
難以置信
Unbelievable.
我剛當上經濟人就這么操蛋
My first shitty day as a broker.
不到一個月
Within a month,
L.F.羅斯柴爾德
L.F. Rothschild,
一所始建于1899年的投資銀行
an institution since 1899,
美國著名商業投資銀行機構
1987年股市風暴中倒閉
關門大吉了
closed its doors.
華爾街把我吃干抹凈
Wall Street had swallowed me up
又把我拉出來了
and shit me right back out again.
實在不行我們可以把訂婚戒指當掉
We could pawn my engagement ring if we needed to.
-親愛的...-我不介意
- Babe... - Because I don't mind.
我是說實在不行的話
If we needed to, I'm saying...
-能聽我說嗎  -好吧
- Will you listen to me? - Okay.
什么都不用典當  好嗎
You're not pawning anything. Okay?
-好  -我一直怎么跟你說的
- Okay. - What do I always tell you?
你會成為百萬富翁
You're gonna be a millionaire.
沒錯  讓我再看看
That's right. Okay? Just let me look.
會找到工作的
We'll find something.
-這個怎么樣  -什么
- How about this? - What?
奇才必勝  那個電器店
Nobody Beats the Wiz, the electronics store.
存貨管理員
電器  電視  音響
奇才           必勝
貨品管理員  你覺得呢
Stock boy. What do you think?
你不能去那地方工作
You're not gonna work at that place.
但是先從...
Yeah, but, you know, you start off...
喬丹  你去那兒的話
Jordan, you're gonna be miserable at that place
-會痛苦死的  -我知道
- if you go there. - I know.
先是做銷售  就能一路爬到總經理了
It's sales. You work your way up, you'll be a general manager.
-你不能做貨品管理員  -為什么
- You're not gonna be a stock boy. - Why not?
因為你是股票經紀人
'Cause you're a stockbroker.
你知道現在沒人雇股票經紀人了吧
You understand that nobody's hiring stockbrokers right now?
你知道吧
You understand that?
好嗎
Okay?
培養法律醫療人才
秘                   書
股票經紀人
因1987年業務發展需要  投資者中心長島辦公室招聘人才
應聘請致電
這地方要
This place is.
-什么  -上面寫什么
- What? - What's that say?
股票經紀人
"Stockbrokers."
在長島
In Long Island?
-去長島做股票經紀人  -對
- Stockbrokers in Long Island? - Yeah.
是在長島  那又如何
It's in Long Island. So what?
我找投資者中心
Hey, I'm looking for Investor's Center.
那是什么  你要投股票嗎
What's that? You want to invest?
不  投資者中心  我找投資者中心
No. Investor's Center. I'm looking for Investor's Center.
對對  就是我們  就是這兒
Yeah, yeah, that's us. Hey. This is it. This is it.
-我叫德維恩  -你就是德維恩
- I'm Dwayne. - You're Dwayne?
你好  德維恩  我們在電話里談過
Hi, Dwayne. We spoke on the phone.
我是喬丹·貝爾福
I'm Jordan Belfort.
那個紐約羅斯柴爾德的經紀人
I'm the broker from Rothschild in New York.
是  請坐  你好嗎
Yes, yeah. Have a seat. How are you?
我們談過...
We had a conversation...
我們之前講過電話  對吧
We spoke on the phone earlier, right?
-兩小時前  -對
- Two hours ago. - Right.
沒錯
Yeah.
它們都是潛力股  就是這意思
They're up and comers. That's what that means.
一股3分錢  就是3塊錢
It's three cents a share, that's $3!
你個小氣鬼
You cheap fuck!
那么
So...
你們的科特龍在哪呢
So where are your Quotrons here?
-科特龍  -對  就是電腦
- Quotrons? - Yeah. Your computers.
不  我們這兒不用電腦
No, no. We don't even need computers here.
就在這些粉色股票單上交易
We just trade right off the pink sheets here.
-粉色股票單  -對  都是仙股
- Pink sheets? - Yeah, they're penny stocks.
就那些資金不足  沒法在納斯達克
You know, companies that can't get listed on NASDAQ,
全稱國家證券業者自動報價系統協會
上市的公司
they don't have enough capital?
這些股票就在這兒交易
Their shares trade here.
-仙股  -對
- Penny stocks? - Yeah.
這個艾洛帶因就是家非常有意思...
This one, Aerodyne, is a really interesting...
還是叫艾洛泰因來著
Or Aerotyne...
艾洛泰因  對
Aerotyne, yeah.
艾洛  艾洛泰因
Aero... Aerotyne...
艾洛泰因  沒錯
Aerotyne. Yeah.
現在炙手可熱
Very hot stock right now.
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
是幾個兄弟在車庫里
They're just a couple of brothers that are making
造的雷達探測器
radar detectors out of their garage.
在迪比克市
They're out in Dubuque.
也許是微波爐  我也不清楚
Maybe it's microwaves. I'm not sure.
但撥他們公司的主機
But you call the company's main line,
是他們的媽媽多蘿西接  人特別好
their mom, Dorothy, answers and she is so sweet.
-真是家好公司  -我都不知道還有什么
- Good company. - I actually don't know what else to...
除了這些  我對他們一無所知
I don't know anything else about them other than that.
一股6分錢嗎
Six cents a share?
拜托  這種垃圾誰買
Hey, come on. Who buys this crap?
其實買主大多是些蠢貨
Well, I mean... Honestly, mostly schmucks.
郵差  總少不了郵差
Postmen, there's always postmen.
管道工
Plumbers.
在《皮條客》和《大眾機械》的封底
They see our ads in the back of
看到我們的廣告
Hustler and Popular Mechanics.
我們廣告寫著能快速致富
Our ads actually say they can get rich quick.
-《皮條客》  -對
- Hustler? - Yeah.
就那種色情雜志
You know, those girlie magazines.
是啊  裸女雜志
Yeah, yeah. Nudie mag.
一絲不掛
A lot.
我們要幫他們買房
We're helping them finance houses,
給老婆買鉆戒
we're helping them buy their wife a diamond ring...
也可能是買船
a boat maybe.
這地方有人管嗎  還是你們...
Is this... Is this stuff regulated or are you guys...
你們這是干什么呢
What are you doing here?
算是吧
Sort of.
Sort of?
天哪  這買賣差額好大
Jesus Christ, the spread on these is huge.
是  重點就在這兒
Yeah. And that's the point, that's...
你叫什么來著
What's your name again?
我  叫喬丹·貝爾福
Mine... Jordan Belfort.
喬丹  藍籌股你賺多少傭金
Jordan, what do you get on that blue chip stock?
1%  我原來賺1%
I make one percent. Or I did make one percent.
粉色股票單上你賺50%
Pink sheets, it's 50.
50%
It's 50%?
50%的傭金嗎
50% commission?
-沒錯  -為什么
- Yup. - For what?
這就是我們服務的加價
It's our markup for our services.
這么說  如果我
And so if I... If I...
一支股賣出去一萬塊錢
If I sell a stock at $10,000,
我的傭金就是5000塊
my commission is 5,000 bucks?
如果你這支股賣出去1萬塊錢
If you sell $10,000 worth of this stock,
我親自免費給你吹簫
I will personally give you a blowjob for free.
我翹首以盼
And I hope it happens.
你好  約翰  今天怎么樣
Hello, John, how are you doing today?
你幾周前寄了一張明信片到我公司
You mailed in my company a postcard a few weeks back
咨詢上漲潛力巨大
requesting information on penny stocks that had
下跌風險極小的仙股嗎
huge upside potential with very little downside risk.
還記得嗎
Does that ring a bell?
我好像的確寄過
Yeah, I may have sent something.
太好了  約翰  我今天打電話給你
Okay, great. The reason for the call today, John, is,
因為我剛剛發現一支潛力股
something just came across my desk, John.
大概能算我半年來見過最棒的一支
It is perhaps the best thing I've seen in the last six months.
我想跟你聊聊
If you have 60 seconds,
只要60秒  1分鐘好嗎
I'd like to share the idea with you. You got a minute?
我其實現在...
Actually, I'm really very...
公司名叫艾洛泰因國際
The name of the company, Aerotyne International.
這是中西部一家尖端高科技公司
It is a cutting edge high-tech firm out of the Midwest
艾洛泰因 IND.
馬上就將獲得下一代
awaiting imminent patent approval
雷達探測器的專利許可
on the next generation of radar detectors
現在這種雷達探測器的
that have both huge military
軍用和民用價值都非常高
and civilian applications now.
就是現在  約翰
Right now, John,
直接交易股價10美分一股
the stock trades over-the-counter at 10 cents a share.
還有  約翰  我們的分析師
And by the way, John, our analysts indicate
認為這支股票日后能漲上天
it could go a heck of a lot higher than that.
你只要投資6000塊
Your profit on a mere $6,000 investment
就能賺到6萬塊的收益
would be upwards of $60,000!
老天  我住房按揭就6萬
Jesus! That's my mortgage, man.
沒錯  你就能還清按揭了
Exactly. You could pay off your mortgage.
這股票能幫我還清房貸
This stock will pay off my house?
約翰  就算股市這個樣子
John, one thing I can promise you,
我也能向你保證一件事
even in this market,
那就是我從不讓客戶
is that I never ask my clients
關注我賭對的股
to judge me on my winners.
我讓他們看我賭輸的股票
I ask them to judge me on my losers
因為我賭輸的太少了
because I have so few.
至于艾洛泰因
And in the case of Aerotyne,
基于目前所有的技術因素  約翰
based on every technical factor out there, John,
這絕對是滿貫全壘打
we are looking at a grand slam home run.
行  投吧  我投4000塊
Okay, let's do it. I'll do four grand.
4000美金  那就是4萬股  約翰
$4,000? That'd be 40,000 shares, John.
我現在就去下單
Let me lock in that trade right now
然后讓我秘書聯系你
and get back to you with my secretary
確認信息  可以嗎  約翰
with an exact confirmation. Sound good, John?
-行  很好  -好極了
- Yeah, sounds good. - Great.
約翰
Hey, John.
感謝您的信任
Thank you for your vote of confidence.
歡迎加入投資者中心
And welcome to the Investor's Center.
非常感謝  老兄
Yeah, thanks a lot, man.
再見
Bye-bye.
你他媽怎么做到的
How'd you fucking do that?
我就這樣賺了2000塊
Just like that, I made two grand.
其他人都目瞪口呆地看著我
The other guys looked at me
好像我剛發現了如何取火
like I'd just discovered fire.
好  那更好了
Great! Even better!
買入
長期股權
我把垃圾股賣給垃圾人
I was selling garbage to garbage men
自己賺了個盆滿缽滿
and making cash hand over fist.
你將來只有一個問題
The only problem you're gonna have
就是當初買太少了
is that you didn't buy more.
-我賣給別人的都是垃圾  -加油
- So I was selling them shit. - Way to go.
但在我看來
But the way I looked at it,
他們的錢在我口袋里更好
their money was better off in my pocket.
我更懂得怎么花錢
I knew how to spend it better.
不好意思  停車場里那輛車是你的嗎
Excuse me. Is that your car in the lot?
是
Yeah.
-真漂亮啊  -謝了
- It's a nice ride. - Thanks, man.
我叫唐尼·亞速
Donnie Azoff.
我叫喬丹·貝爾福
Hey. I'm Jordan Belfort.
-幸會  -你好
- Nice to meet you. - How you doing?
我常看到那輛車
You know, actually, I see that car around.
-經常看到  -是嗎  在哪看到的
- I see it around a lot. - Oh, yeah, where?
我們好像住同一棟樓
I think we live in the same building.
-真的假的  -真的
- No shit? - Yeah, yeah.
-你住12樓吧  -是啊  你住幾樓
- Twelfth floor? - Yeah. What floor are you on?
4樓
Fourth floor.
-我有兩個孩子  老婆很丑  -這樣啊
- I have two little kids. Ugly wife. - Right.
你做什么的  兄弟
What do you do, bro?
什么叫  我做什么的
What do you mean, what do I do?
工作  你做什么工作的
For work, what do you do?
我是股票經紀人
I'm a stockbroker.
-股票經紀人  -對
- Stockbroker? - Yeah.
我賣兒童家具的
Children's furniture.
不錯啊
Oh, good for you.
還行吧
It's all right.
你賺錢多嗎
You make a lot of money?
我自己覺得還不錯吧
Yeah, I do all right for myself.
我就想理理清楚
I'm trying to put it together.
你開輛這么炫酷的車
You got your fucking nice car,
還跟我住同一棟樓里
we live in the same building. I just...
我有點想不通  你賺多少
I'm not understanding... How much money do you make?
不好說  上個月賺了七萬
I don't know. $70,000 last month.
你他媽
Get the fuck...
你他媽別逗了
Get the fuck out of here.
我認真的
No, I'm serious.
我也是認真的
Yeah, no, I'm serious, too.
說真的  你到底賺多少
Seriously, how much money do you make?
我說了  七萬
I told you. $70,000.
確切來說應該是七萬二
Well, technically, $72,000.
上個月差不多就這么多吧
Last month. Something like that.
你一個月賺七萬二嗎
You made 72 grand in one month?
是的
Yeah.
我跟你說
I'll tell you what.
你把寫著七萬二的工資單拿給我看
You show me a pay stub for $72,000 on it,
我立馬辭職跟你混
I quit my job right now and I work for you.
保利  你好啊
Hey, Paulie, what's up?
不  沒事  都挺好的
No, yeah, yeah. No, everything's fine.
我要辭職
Hey, listen, I quit.
他真的辭職了
And he did quit his job.
我覺得有點怪
Which I thought was a little weird.
我他媽才遇見這家伙
I mean, I just met this fucking guy.
別他媽告訴蘇珊  跟她沒關系
Don't fucking tell Susan. It's none of her business.
這人還不止這一件事奇怪
There were other things about him, too.
比如他白得發光的牙齒
Like his phosphorescent white teeth.
你老婆  我他媽還管你老婆
Wife! I gotta fucking deal with your wife?
他用角制鏡架透明鏡片
The fact that he wore horn rims with clear lenses
就為了看著更像上層階級
just to look more WASP-y.
美國上層階級一些人自稱WASP  意為白種盎格魯撒克遜基督教新教徒
還有那些流言
And then, there were these rumors.
我聽到一些愚蠢的流言  怎么說呢
I heard some stupid shit. I don't know.
我操  我都不想提的  就是...
Fuck, I didn't even want to bring it up. It's just...
-蠢透了  -有關我的流言
- It's stupid. - Shit with me?
人們就喜歡說三道四  我都不知道
You know, people say shit. I don't even know.
半數時間我都不會去聽
I don't even listen to it half the time.
他們說什么呢
What are they saying?
說你和你表妹的傳言
Shit about you and your cousin or something like that.
我才不去聽呢
I don't even listen to it.
老兄  不是他們說的那樣
Bro, it's not like that.
不是的
It's not like that.
說你娶了你表妹什么的  沒有嗎
Like you married your cousin or some stupid shit. No?
是  我老婆
Yeah, my wife. Yeah.
我老婆是我表妹
My wife is my cousin, or whatever.
但不是你以為的那樣
But it's not like what you think, or whatever, you know.
她是你的嫡表妹嗎  還是...
Is she like a first cousin, or is she...
對  不是  她是...
Yeah, no, she's, you know...
她爸
Her... Her father
是我媽的弟弟
is the brother of my mom.
不是那樣的
It's not like, what... You know.
我們一起長大
Look, we grew up together.
她出落得很性感  真他媽性感
And she grew up hot, you know. She fucking grew up hot.
我朋友都想上她
And all my friends were trying to fuck her, you know.
我可不會讓別人
And I'm not gonna let someone...
讓這些傻逼上我表妹
You know, one of these assholes fuck my cousin,
我就用表哥的身份接近她
so, you know, I used the cousin thing as like an in with her.
我可不會讓別人上我表妹
I'm not gonna let someone else fuck my cousin.
要有人上我表妹
You know, if anyone's gonna fuck my cousin,
那也得是我  出于尊重
it's gonna be me, out of respect. You know?
我明白
No, I get it. Yeah.
你不怕生孩子出事嗎
I mean, you're not afraid of like the whole kid thing, right?
-什么  跟她生孩子嗎  -是的
- What? Having kids with her? - Yeah.
不怕  我們有兩個孩子了
No. We have two kids.
他們...
And they're... I mean...
這不是人身攻擊  不過他們沒事嗎
I don't want to get personal, but they're okay?
沒有  他們不是弱智之類的
No, they're not retarded or anything like that.
但很有可能吧...
But there's a big chance, right, if...
是啊  大概60%
Yeah, there's like a 60%, you know,
60%到65%的機會孩子會是弱智
60% to 65% chance the kid's gonna be fucking retarded or whatever.
我他媽嚇尿了  老兄
That'd scare the shit out of me, buddy.
不管操的是不是表妹
Look, man, a lot of having a kid, or whatever, takes risk,
生孩子都有風險
whether you're fucking cousins or not.
如果你的孩子真是弱智怎么辦
What if something like that happened?
基本上  孩子要真是弱智
Basically, you know, if the kid was retarded,
我就開車到荒郊野外
I would, you know, drive it up to the country
打開車門然后說
and just, like, you know, open the door and say,
"你自由了"  "自由奔跑吧"之類的
"You're free now." You know, like, "Run free."
你懂的吧
You know?
你他媽逗我玩呢
You're completely fucking with me.
那太可怕了  你才不會...
That's horrible. You're not gonna...
你的樣子好像...不會
You look like you've... No.
我們會帶孩子去特殊機構什么的
We would take it to, like, an institution or somewhere
或是專門負責撫養孩子的地方
that's handled to, like, you know, raise the kid or whatever.
如果你很開心  那上帝保佑你
You know what? If you're happy, God bless you, buddy.
不  我他媽哪里開心了
No, I'm not fucking happy. No one who's married is fucking happy.
誰他媽結婚了還會開心啊
No one who's married is fucking happy.
聽你這么說很遺憾  兄弟
Well, I'm sorry to hear that, buddy.
我真的...
Listen, I'm really, you know...
我真的很感謝你給我這份工作
I'm really appreciative for this fucking job.
我真的很喜歡
I'm really enjoying it.
我很滿意你現在的表現
I'm really happy with what you're doing.
我給你準備了一份禮物
Actually, I got you a little present.
-你給我準備了禮物  -一點小心意
- You got me a present? - I got you something.
媽的  你真好
Oh, fuck. You're sweet.
不過在酒吧后面
Yeah. It's in the back though.
-什么意思  -你得去后面
- What do you mean? - You gotta go out back.
是禮物包起來了嗎
Like it's wrapped up or something?
對  包起來了
It's wrapped up. Yeah.
-我不明白  -我也不明白
- I don't get it. - Neither do I.
快他媽走吧  走吧
Let's fucking go. Come on.
到你了
Your turn.
我才不吸  你他媽瘋了吧
I'm not fucking doing this. You're out of your fucking mind.
-抽點這玩意兒  -不要
- Smoke this shit, bro. - No.
這兒媽逼又沒別人
No one's fucking here, bro.
你他媽...
Get the fuck...
你他媽跟我一起吸可卡因吧  老兄
Fucking smoke crack with me, bro.
老子不干
I'm not fucking doing it.
吸吧  跟我一起吸可卡因吧
Smoke crack. Smoke some fucking crack with me, bro.
-就一口  就這樣  -好
- One hit. One hit. That's it. - Okay.
真他媽瘋了
Fucking nut job.
我們跑步去吧
Let's go run, huh?
我們不能憋在這兒  老兄
We gotta get out of here, buddy.
我們得走了  跑步去吧
We gotta get out of here. Let's go fucking run.
像獅子老虎黑熊一樣奔跑吧
Let's run like we're fucking lions and tigers and bears!
跑起來  快他媽跑起來
Let's run! Let's fucking run!
他媽的快跑  快啊
Let's fucking run! Go!
跑跑跑
Go, go, go, go!
這里是弗蘭克汽車維修
You've reached Frank's Best Auto Body.
我們現在不營業
We're closed right now.
請留言
So please leave us a message.
你好  我叫喬丹·貝爾福
Hello. My name is Jordan Belfort.
我和搭檔想租用你的汽修廠
My partner and I are very interested in renting out your garage.
我和唐尼辭職單干了
Donnie and I were going out on our own.
首先我們需要的就是經紀人
And the first thing we needed was brokers.
有銷售經驗的人
Guys with sales experience.
所以我招募了幾個老鄉
So I recruited some of my hometown boys.
西·奧特  賣肉和大麻的
Sea Otter, who sold meat and weed.
切斯特  賣輪胎和大麻的
Chester, who sold tires and weed.
還有羅比  能弄到什么就賣什么
And Robbie, who sold anything he could get his hands on.
基本都是大麻
Mostly weed.
能給我拿點番茄醬來嗎
Can you bring me some ketchup? Okay?
這是布拉德
This is Brad.
我真想要的就是布拉德
And Brad's the guy I really wanted.
但他不愿意加入我們
But he didn't go along with us.
他賣安眠酮已經賺飛了
He was already making so much money selling Quaaludes,
算是貝賽地區的安眠酮小王子
he'd become the Quaalude king of Bayside.
你這玩意兒操上逼了沒
Getting any pussy with that thing or what?
當然  伙計
Yeah, man, of course.
有空也帶幾個妞兒來我這轉轉
Bring some of them chicks around here sometime, huh?
讓她們瞧瞧
Let 'em watch.
讓她們見識見識  懂我意思嗎
Let 'em watch. Know what I mean?
小老二  代我向你姐姐問好
Hey, Zip! You tell your sister I was asking about her.
下次來我這的時候
Why don't you bring me a pair of her panties
帶條她的內褲吧
next time you come through.
伙計  她說這輩子也不想見你了
Yeah, man. She said she don't want to talk to you anymore, man.
你他媽滾吧
Get the fuck out of here.
媽  今兒有雞肉沒
Hey, Ma, we got chicken or what?
媽
Ma!
聽見沒  比你們想象的還容易
You listening? It's easier than you think.
每個接你電話的人
Every person you're on the phone with,
都做著一夜暴富的夢
they want to get rich and they want to get rich quickly.
都想空手套白狼
They all want something for nothing.
我有次
There was this one time
把口鍋賣給門諾會教徒了
that I was selling pot to this Amish dude.
當代基督新教派別 以追求簡樸生活聞名
就是那種留著鬢須
You know those guys who got like the beard
但嘴唇上不留胡子的
with like no mustache or some bullshit?
他就說他這輩子只想做家具
Well, he says that he only wants to make furniture.
-沒懂你意思  -這和我們說的有什么關系
- I don't understand. - What's that got to do with anything?
你他媽扯哪兒去了
What the fuck are you talking about?
不是我逼你說什么
I'm not putting words in your mouth or nothing,
但你剛說每人都想一夜暴富
but you just said that everybody wants to get rich.
我操  你剛確實說了
Holy fuck, you did just say that.
你們他媽扯哪兒去了
What the fuck are you talking about?
對啊  佛教徒也是  他們才不在乎錢
Yeah, like Buddhists. They don't give a shit about money.
他們只穿僧袍  也沒什么花銷
They're wrapped in sheets. They're not buying shit.
我又不是說佛教徒或門諾教徒
I'm not talking about Buddhists or Amish.
我是說普通人  工薪階級  平凡群眾
I'm talking about normal people, working-class, everyday people.
人人都想賺大錢  我說錯了嗎
Everyone wants to get rich. Am I crazy?
那種超凡脫俗的人根本不存在
There's no such thing as an Amish Buddhist.
-我敢保證  -真的有
- I'm pretty fucking sure. - There could be.
能來點番茄醬嗎  謝謝
Can we get some ketchup, please?
難道你們這幫人也不想掙錢嗎
Do you guys not want to make money?
我想掙大錢啊
I want to make some money.
我他媽當然想掙錢
I want to make some fucking money, okay.
我什么都能賣
I can sell anything.
我都能把安眠酮賣給修道院的修女
Shit, I can sell ludes to a convent full of nuns,
讓她們淫水泛濫高潮迭起
and get them so horny they'd be fucking each other.
要的就是這個態度  沒你賣不掉的東西是嗎
That's the attitude. You can sell anything?
來把這支筆賣給我
Sell me this fucking pen right here.
你不是什么都能賣嗎  試試這個  來
You can sell anything. Sell that. Go ahead.
把這支筆賣給我
Sell me the pen.
等我吃完行嗎  一天沒吃飯了
Can I finish eating first? I haven't eaten today.
布拉德  教教他們該怎么做
Brad, show them how it's done. Boom.
把這支筆賣給我  都看好了  開始
Sell me that pen. Watch. Go on.
你要我把這破筆賣給你
You want me to sell this fucking pen?
這才是我哥們兒  什么都能賣
That's my boy right there. Can fucking sell anything.
幫我個忙
Why don't you do me a favor.
把你名字寫那張餐巾紙上
Write your name down on that napkin for me.
可我沒有筆呀
I don't have a pen.
賣給你了  這叫供需關系  伙計
Exactly. Supply and demand, my friend.
-簡直了  -我說什么來著
- Holy shit. - See what I'm saying?
他知道制造需求
He's creating urgency.
讓他們心甘情愿去買股票
Get them to want to buy the stock.
讓他們相信這是不可或缺的  明白嗎
Convince them it's something they need, you know what I mean?
關鍵就在這
And that's the thing.
修女全是同性戀
All nuns are lesbians.
你他媽又扯到哪兒去了  海獺
What the fuck are you talking about, Otter?
想想看  在修道院釣不到凱子
Think about it. They can't keep a dude
只好玩女人嘍
so they're gonna start fucking chicks.
我喊了四遍了  幾米  第四遍了
Four fucking times, Kimmie! Four times.
他沒跟上我們的思路
He's not with us.
她終于拿來了
Now she runs.
這幫人是沒念過哈佛工商管理碩士什么的
But look. I knew these guys weren't like Harvard MBAs.
羅比·范伯格  外號笨蛋
Robbie Feinberg, the pinhead,
用了5年才高中畢業
took five years to finish high school.
奧爾登·古佛博格  外號海獺  高中都沒念完
Alden Kupferberg, the Sea Otter, didn't even graduate.
切斯特·明  外號頹廢華人
Chester Ming, the depraved Chinaman,
一直以為柔道是以色列人發明的
thought jujitsu was in Israel.
當中最聰明的要屬尼基·克斯考夫
Smartest of the bunch was Nicky Koskoff.
他還真上過法學院
He actually went to law school.
我叫他魯格拉特因為他那頂傻逼假發
I called him Rugrat because of his piece of shit hairpiece.
就算來的是一群年輕  饑渴的蠢貨
Still, give them to me young, hungry and stupid,
要不了多久我都能讓他們發財
and in no time, I'll make them rich.
我的天
Oh, my God.
喬丹  這
Jordan, that...
喜歡嗎  寶貝
You like it, baby?
天哪  太漂亮了
Oh, my God, that's beautiful.
這不是世界上最大的鉆石
They're not the biggest stones in the world,
但我保證這都是上等貨
but I promise they're really high quality.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
真的很漂亮
They're so beautiful.
天哪
Oh, boy.
怎么了
What?
我見過你這副表情  怎么了  說吧
I know that look. What is it? Go ahead.
不知道  就是
I don't know, it's... You know...
這些股票  這些公司
These stocks... These companies...
都是一些不入流的公司啊
They're like crappy companies.
-沒錯  -是吧
- Well, yeah. - Okay.
沒錯  它們都糟透了
Yeah, they're terrible.
別擔心  不是告訴過你嗎
Don't worry about it. I told you,
我做的都是合法生意
what I'm doing is completely legal.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
但那些投資人其實掙不到錢  對嗎
But they're not gonna make anyone money though, right?
時有時無吧
Well, sometimes they do, sometimes they don't.
投資本來就是這樣的
You know how it goes.
那把這種股票賣給
Wouldn't you feel better if you sold that stuff to rich people
不在乎這點小錢的富人不會更好嗎
who can, like, afford to lose all that money?
當然
Of course.
但有錢人是不會買仙股的
But rich people don't buy penny stocks.
事實就這樣
They just don't.
為什么
Why not?
因為他們都混成精了
Because they're too smart, that's why not.
只要是讀過大學的人
I mean, what person with a college education
有誰會相信這群混混呢
would trust this bunch of jerk-offs?
把電話掛了  說一會打回去
Hang up the phone. Tell him you'll call him back.
我他媽這正談著5000塊的生意呢
I got five fucking grand on the phone right now!
不過要是他們聽起來不像混混呢
But what if they didn't sound like a bunch of jerk-offs?
如果我教會他們怎么向有錢人推銷呢
What if I could teach them how to sell to people with money?
真正的有錢人
Real money.
所以我決定重新打造整個公司
So I decided to reinvent the company.
先生們  歡迎來到斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特
Gentlemen, welcome to Stratton Oakmont.
你們現在的目標是拿下美國那1%的首富
You schnooks will now be targeting the wealthiest 1% of Americans.
要撈就要撈大魚
We're talking about whales here.
就他媽《白鯨記》里那種
Moby fucking Dicks.
《白鯨記》美國著名小說
描寫主人公亞哈船長追逐并殺死白鯨莫比·迪克的經歷
這份推銷詞  就是你們的魚叉
And with this script, which is now your new harpoon,
我將教會你們每一個人
I'm gonna teach each and every one of you
如何成為他媽的亞哈船長
to be Captain fucking Ahab.
懂了嗎
Get it? Huh?
什么船長
Captain who?
亞哈船長  就他媽的是
Captain Ahab. From the fucking...
那本書里來的  你這蠢貨  書里的
The book, motherfucker. From the book.
動動你的腦子
Turn your fucking brain on.
-去你媽的  -我操  羅比
- Fuck you. - Jesus fuck, Robbie.
聽我說  我們這家新公司有說法的
Listen to me. We're a new company with a new name.
一家讓客戶放心的公司
A company that our clients can believe in.
一家讓客戶信任的公司
A company that our clients can trust.
一家在華爾街根基深厚的公司
A firm whose roots are so deeply embedded into Wall Street
五月花號是英國移民駛往北美最為著名的一艘船只
當年的創始人乘著五月花號破浪而來
that our very founders sailed over on the Mayflower
將斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特這個名字
and chiseled the name Stratton Oakmont
鐫刻在普里茅斯的堅巖上
right into Plymouth fucking Rock!
普里茅斯巖為新移民踏上美洲大陸的第一塊石頭
明白了嗎
You got it?
我們的具體計劃是
What we're gonna do is this.
我們先推銷像迪斯尼  ATT  IBM
First we pitch 'em Disney, ATT, IBM,
分別為美國電話電報公司  國際商業機器公司
這種藍籌熱門股
blue chip stocks exclusively.
他們熟知的這種大公司
Companies these people know.
等他們放松警惕  我們就開始賣狗屎
Once we've suckered them in, we unload the dog shit.
粉單和仙股才是我們的聚寶盆
The pink sheets, the penny stocks, where we make the money.
我們從中抽五成呢  乖乖
50% commission, baby.
用這種策略盈利的關鍵在于
Now the key to making money in a situation like this
一定要先下手為強
is to position yourself now before the settlement.
等《華爾街日報》都報道了再行動
Because by the time you read about it in The Wall Street Journal,
就為時已晚了
it's already too late.
然后你要做的就是等待
Then you wait.
耐心等待
You wait.
誰先開口誰傻逼
And whoever speaks first loses.
抱歉
Sorry...
感謝您來電告知我
I appreciate the call.
我得考慮考慮
I really have to give this some thought
再和我太太商量一下
and talk to my wife about it.
我想好了再給您答復可以嗎
Can I call you back?
他們在猶豫  對吧  他們得考慮考慮
They don't know, right? They gotta think about it,
得他媽問老婆
they gotta talk to their fucking wives,
或者去問他媽的牙仙什么的
or the fucking Tooth Fairy.
美國民間傳說中的精靈
但那些都不是關鍵
Point is, it doesn't matter what the fuck they say.
唯一讓他們不敢砸錢的原因就是
The only real objection that they have
他們并不相信你們這幫人
is that they don't trust you guys.
公司血統
商機緊迫
他們憑什么相信你們  看看你們自己
And why should they trust you? I mean, look at you.
就一幫沒文化的推銷員  對吧
You're a bunch of fucking sleazy salesmen, right?
那你們該怎么辦呢
So, what do you say?
要是我能讓你7美元買進聯合碳化物
You mean to tell me that if I put you in at Union Carbide at seven
再32美元賣出
and took you out at 32.
11美元買入德州儀器  47美元賣出
Texas Instruments at 11 and took you out at 47.
16美元買入美國鋼鐵公司  41美元賣出
U.S. Steel at 16, took you out at 41.
你現在肯定跟我說
You wouldn't be saying to me right now,
切斯特  快幫我給迪斯尼投幾千股吧
"Chester, pick me up a few thousand shares of Disney!"
立刻  現在  趕快買
"On the spot, right now. Come on."
說真的  凱文  說真的  不是嗎
Honestly, Kevin? Honestly? Seriously?
我都不認識你
I don't know you.
你我陌不相識  你就給我電話陌生拜訪
You cold-called me. You're a total stranger.
我表示完全同意
I am in complete agreement with you.
我們互不相識
You don't know me, I don't know you.
請允許我做個自我介紹  我叫奧爾登·古佛博格
Let me introduce myself to you. My name is Alden Kupferberg.
-我叫羅比·范伯格  -我叫切斯特·明
- Robbie Feinberg. - Chester Ming.
我現在是斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的高級副總裁
I'm Senior Vice President at Stratton Oakmont,
我計劃在明年內成為
and I plan on being one of the...
我公司頂尖的股票經紀人之一
top brokers in my firm next year.
我要邁錯一步可就沒戲了  斯坦利
And I'm not gonna get there by being wrong, Stanley.
我不得不說  你聽起來像是個
I do wanna say that you sound like a...
你像是個實誠人
You sound like a pretty sincere guy.
這投資不會讓你一夜暴富或赤貧
It's not gonna make you rich and it's not gonna make you poor.
但這次交易絕對會成為
But what this trade will do is serve as...
未來交易的標桿  凱文
a benchmark for future business, Kevin.
現在說話舒服多了吧  斯科蒂
You feel comfortable with me now, Scotty?
然后你就能確信了
And then you'll know for sure
自己終于在華爾街找了個能信賴的
that you finally found a broker on Wall Street
股票經紀人
that you can trust,
而且還能保證你穩賺不賠
and who can consistently make you money.
聽起來不錯吧
Sound fair enough?
我猜  是吧
You know what... Yeah.
你的確讓我印象深刻
I gotta say, I'm pretty impressed.
你具體怎么打算的
What are you thinking?
凱文
Kevin.
給我一個機會
You give me one shot here
幫你投個柯達這樣的藍籌股
on a blue chip stock like Kodak,
相信我  凱文
and believe me, Kevin,
之后你唯一會頭疼的問題
the only problem you're gonna have
就是后悔當初沒多買點
is that you didn't buy more.
聽起來不錯吧
Sound fair enough?
該死  我
Shit. My...
我老婆沒準會踹了我  不過
My wife might divorce me, but...
成  來吧
Yeah, let's do it.
明智的選擇  凱文
Excellent choice, Kevin.
這次你打算投多少錢
How much do you want to go for this time?
那就5...5000美元吧
Let's do five... $5,000.
多投點  8000怎么樣  凱文
Can we try 8,000, Kevin?
好吧  干脆投一萬塊
All right. Let's do 10.
-一萬美元  -你覺得可行嗎
- Ten. - You want to do that?
不能再明智了
Excellent choice!
凱文  我先去下單
Kevin, let me lock in that trade right now,
幾分鐘之后再給你回電
and get back to you in a few minutes
進行確認  凱文
with an exact confirmation, Kevin.
歡迎加入斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特
And welcome to Stratton Oakmont.
謝了  伙計  我得去喝一杯
Thanks, man. I'm gonna have a beer.
這還挺有趣的
This is fun.
放輕松  凱文
Take it easy, Kev.
謝了  喬丹  十分...
Hey, thanks, Jordan. Thanks a...
滾他媽的蛋吧
Fuck that motherfucker!
這還差不多
That's what I'm talking about!
真他媽是個傻逼
What a fucking idiot.
這世上我唯一了如指掌的就是航空行業了
The one thing I know about in this world is airlines.
酷尚航空絕對是航空領域的未來之星
And Cuchon Airlines is the future of airlines.
趕緊下手  不然...
Get in now or...
-我叫尼基·克斯考夫  -我叫切斯特·明
- I'm Nicky Koskoff. - Chester Ming.
我是斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的高級副總裁
and I'm a Senior Vice President with Stratton Oakmont.
朱迪  這真是太不幸了
Judy, I am so, so, so sorry for your loss.
他什么時候去世的
When did he pass?
就算我預計錯了  好吧
Just say I'm wrong, right.
股票跌幾個點
And the stock goes down a couple points...
用我我祖父的話說  愿他的靈魂安息
And it makes you, in the words of my grandfather,
這絕對能讓你賺上一坨錢
God rest his soul, "A shit ton of money."
這就像還沒太陽的時候
It's like getting in on fucking sunlight
就投資給陽光  懂嗎
before there was fucking sunlight. You understand?
買8000股怎么樣
Can we do 8,000 shares?
好的  兩萬五千股
Okay, 25,000.
您的決定太明智了
That's a very intelligent decision.
我將把電話轉接給我的銷售助理
I'm gonna transfer you to my sales associate.
朗達
Rhonda!
-朗達  -我現在把電話轉給安德烈
- Rhonda! - I'm gonna put you through to Andrea.
媽的有人看到朗達了嗎
Has anybody fucking seen Rhonda?
大家這周都過得不錯吧
Everybody have a good week?
好
Yeah!
月末結算
The end of the month.
公司傭金凈盈利2870萬美元
$28.7 million in gross commissions,
全是粉單市場賺來的  伙計們
all from pink sheet stock, boys!
為了給本周的縱情聲色助興
And to celebrate with our weekly act of debauchery,
我愿給我們可愛的銷售助理
I have offered our lovely sales assistant,
丹尼爾·哈里森小姐
Danielle Harrison, here,
一萬美元  給她剃個禿瓢
$10,000 to shave her fucking head!
你們想看嗎
Yeah, you want this?
You want this?
剃光頭  剃光頭
Let's scalp her! Scalp her!
開始狂歡吧
Let the scalping begin!
光頭  光頭  光頭
Scalp! Scalp! Scalp!
還有  各位  丹尼爾已經答應
FYI, boys, Danielle has promised to
會用這一萬美元去隆胸了
use this $10,000 for breast implants!
她現在是C罩杯  不過就快變他媽D杯了
She's already got C cups, but now she wants fucking double D's!
還他媽有哪兒比我們公司更棒
Is this a great fucking company or what?
是不是世上最棒的公司
Is this the greatest company in the world?
唐尼
Donnie!
今天要他媽爽爆這個鬼地方
Blow the roof off this motherfucker!
還有香檳
Champagne?
派姑娘們進來
Send in the stripees!
我的
Mine!
整條華爾街都充斥著有關我們的傳聞
Word about us spread throughout Wall Street.
甚至傳到了我不愿傳到的地方
Even the places I didn't want it to.
帕特里克·德納姆  特工
沒過多久華爾街報社中的佼佼者
It wasn't long before Forbes magazine,
《福布斯》雜志社邀請我做個人專訪了
the flagship of Wall Street, called to do a profile on me.
請問你認為斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的未來會怎樣
Let me ask you, how do you see the future for Stratton Oakmont?
一個詞形容嗎
One word?
多樣化經營
Diversification.
挺好  十分感謝  我已經收獲頗豐
Sounds good. Thank you so much. I have more than enough.
-感謝您百忙中抽出時間  -很好
- I appreciate your time. - Fantastic.
能給我們拍張照嗎
Can we get a quick picture?
簡直就他媽是惡意詆毀
A total fucking hatchet job.
喬丹·貝爾福不再賣肉
改銷高風險股票
華 爾 街 之 狼
這幫陰險的小雜種  讀讀這個
This conniving little twat! Look at this!
變 態 羅 賓 漢
他們稱我為"華爾街之狼"
"The Wolf of Wall Street" They call me. Look.
你發型不錯
Your hair looks good.
擅長向輕信的投資者推銷高風險股票
-我的發型是不錯  -是吧
- Well, my hair looks good. - Yeah.
喬丹·貝爾福就像個變態羅賓漢一樣
"Jordan Belfort, sounding like a kind of twisted Robin Hood"
從富人處搶錢然后和一幫
"who takes from the rich and gives to himself,"
經紀人狐朋狗友分贓
"and his merry little band of brokers."
-讀讀  讀讀  -聽著
- Read that. Read it. - Listen.
所有媒體炒作都是好事  親愛的
There is no such thing as bad publicity, sweetheart.
你讀下這篇  寶貝
Read the article, babe.
喬丹  你看著棒極了  你上了大雜志
Jordan, you look great! You're in a huge magazine.
看著棒極了管屁用
Big fucking deal I look great.
貝爾福  請看看我的簡歷
Mr. Belfort! Can you look at my resume, please?
抱歉  抱歉  先生
Excuse me, excuse me, sir!
都他媽消停點兒
Calm the fuck down!
這他媽怎么回事
What the hell's all this?
都怪《福布斯》那篇報道
It's the Forbes article.
現在他們都想為你工作了
They all want to work for you now.
我怎么跟你說的
Hey! What did I say?
我只是想禮貌點
I'm just trying to be nice.
想工作  先找我
Hey, you want a job, you talk to me!
-貝爾福先生  -給我一分鐘就好
- Mr. Belfort! - Give me one minute.
《福布斯》把我炒成了超級巨星
Forbes made me a superstar.
每天有無數做著發財夢的年輕人
Every day, dozens of money-crazed kids
踏破門檻來找我
beat a path to my door.
一旦應聘成功  他們立馬就從大學退學
If we hired 'em, they dropped straight out of college overnight
從生活費里硬摳出一筆錢
and spent whatever allowance they had
買一套斯特拉頓定制裁縫的西裝
on a new suit from our Stratton tailor.
你們他媽是逗我玩嗎
Are you fucking serious right now?
喬丹·貝爾福不再賣肉 改銷高風險股票
華爾街之狼
《福布斯》
我們簡直在親手幫這幫孩子豐衣足食了
I mean, we were literally putting clothes on these kids' backs.
然后就被這個混蛋給盯上了
And here comes this jerk-off sniffing around.
不過這世上每次有人蒸蒸日上時
But, you know, every time someone rises up in this world,
總會有些傻逼想把他們拉下馬
there's always gonna be some asshole trying to drag him down.
數月內  我們的規模就翻了番
Within months, we doubled in size,
遷進了更大的辦公室
moved to even bigger offices.
公司整個就是一瘋人院
It was a madhouse.
各種貪欲的狂歡
A greed-fest,
被可卡因  睪丸酮和體液均分
with equal parts cocaine, testosterone, and body fluids.
鬧得越來越嚴重以至于我得規定
It got so bad, I had to declare the office a fuck-free zone
早9點到晚7點不準在辦公室操逼
between the hours of 9:00 and 7:00.
但我告訴你  這都沒用
But I'm telling you, even that didn't help.
其實我們進駐頭一天就這么瘋了
Actually, the madness started on our very first day,
我們的一個經紀人  本·詹納
when one of our brokers, Ben Jenner,
讓一個銷售助理給他口交
christened the elevator by getting a blowjob
給電梯破了處
from a sales assistant.
她叫帕姆  我得承認
Her name was Pam, and to her credit,
她的確技術超群
she did have this amazing technique,
會那種瘋狂地套弄
with this wild twist and jerk motion.
過了差不多一個月
About a month later,
唐尼和我決定趁周六下午
Donnie and I decided to double-team her
我倆妻子去買圣誕禮服時
on a Saturday afternoon while our wives were out
和她來個二夾一
shopping for Christmas dresses.
后來本娶了她
Eventually, Ben married her,
我們都覺得挺神奇的
which was pretty amazing
因為她給辦公室所有男的都吹過簫
considering she blew every single guy in the office.
本后來因為抑郁3年后自殺了
Then he got depressed and killed himself three years later.
我雇了我爸麥克斯做執行官來維持秩序
Anyway, I hired my dad, Max, to maintain order as the Enforcer.
斯特拉頓自己的蓋世太保
Stratton's very own Gestapo.
我們叫他瘋狂麥克斯因為他的急脾氣
We called him Mad Max because of his hair-trigger temper,
簡直一觸即發
which could be set off by
連電話鈴這點小事都能惹到他
something as innocuous as a ringing telephone.
誰這么厚顏無恥
Who the fuck has the goddamn gall
周二晚上給我家打電話
to call this house on a Tuesday night?
真該死
God damn it!
你要錯過片頭了
You're gonna miss it!
拜托說點新鮮的
Please, tell me something I don't know.
我等一星期就為了看《均衡》
I wait all week for the fucking Equalizer
他們就非得這時候... 你好
and they have to fucking... Hello.
但一接起電話
But as soon as he picked up the phone...
吉尼  最近怎么樣  吉尼
Gene. How are you, Gene?
他就開始用很奇怪的英國腔說話
... he'd affect this weird British accent.
好的  吉尼  那太好了
Right-o, Gene, that'd be great.
回見
Cheerio.
特別的奇怪
It was absolutely bizarre.
這該死的白癡
The fucking halfwit!
-等他掛了電話  -你錯過片頭了
- He'd hang up... - You missed it!
就又變回瘋狂麥克斯了
... and then he's Mad Max all over again.
該死
Damn it!
告訴我剛講什么了  怎么了
All right, tell me what happened. What happened?
他發現是他姑姑
Well, he discovered it was the mother's sister.
他是誰  告訴我是誰
Who's he? Who? Tell me who...
主角啊  你知道主角...
The main guy. You know who the main...
主角
The main guy...
是他姑姑  他發現她死了
It was his mother's sister. She showed up dead.
當然我們在斯特拉做的事情
Of course, Mad Max didn't have to know
不用都讓瘋狂麥克斯知道
everything we were doing at Stratton.
弄一個大的靶子  我們...
And then there's a big target and we...
把他們扔向靶子  然后就粘上了
They get launched at the target. They stick.
靶心里畫個美元符號
There's a bull's-eye and the bull's-eye's a dollar sign.
扔得離靶心最近的
Whoever gets closer to the dollar sign
得分最高
gets the most points.
等著我把那小崩豆扔傻了
I'm gonna throw the shit out of this little fucking thing.
要是他受傷了怎么辦
So if it gets hurt, what happens?
到時我們肯定很瘋狂
'Cause we're gonna get fucking nuts.
我覺得我們傷不到他們  他們可...
I don't think he's gonna get hurt. They're like...
他們都結實得跟超人一樣
They got like superhuman strength.
我覺得他不會有事的
I think he's gonna be fine.
你別瞪著他眼睛看就行
You can't look him right in the eyes.
別瞪著他眼睛看
You can't look him in the eye?
認真的  我看PBS臺說的
That's a fact. I saw it on PBS.
他們會被你看毛然后發瘋的
They get confused and their wires get crossed.
你得看著他們的下巴
You gotta look at their chin.
看著像是我在看你
Like it looks like I'm looking at you
但其實我在看你下巴
but I'm looking at your chin.
我感覺你在跟我說話
I feel like you're addressing me right now,
但你沒在跟我說話吧
but you're not, are you?
他們就像蒙娜麗莎一樣  不管你站哪里
They're like the Mona Lisa. They find eye contact,
他們都能直視你
like, wherever you are standing in the room.
然后就鎖定了
And they lock in.
但我們還是有個限度的對吧
No, but there is a limit to what we can do with them?
可以向他們身上扔東西
We're allowed to throw shit at 'em.
我們可以扔吃的嗎  香蕉
We're allowed to throw food? Bananas.
隨便什么吃的  沒錯
Any food. Correct.
但舉個例子  我就不大會
But, for example, what I wouldn't do is
讓他把雞巴掏出來
maybe like tell him to pull his cock out
然后找幾個妹子
and like get some of the girls to, you know,
玩他什么的
fondle him and shit like that.
那也...不能這么干嗎
That would be... That's unacceptable?
這招我們先留著
Let's keep that in our back pocket.
這人比較適合往靶子上扔
This guy is more about throwing at the dartboard.
對  對  沒錯
Correct. Yes, yes, yes.
他們就適合干這個使
The thing is, this is their gift, okay.
天生就適合被拿來當飛鏢扔
They're built to be thrown like a lawn dart.
跟飛鏢一樣頭重腳輕
They're top heavy like a lawn dart.
就是為了讓你能投準的
So they're built for accuracy.
天哪  我們能把他滾著玩么
Oh, my God. Can we bowl with this guy?
那是他兄弟  羅比
That's his fucking brother, Rob.
羅比才是保齡球
His brother's the bowling ball.
給他身上綁個滑板
The brother, you put a skateboard on him,
把他綁在滑板上
you strap him to a skateboard,
然后順著過道往瓶子上扔
you toss him down an alley at some pins.
-這想法不錯  -絕對的
- No shit. That's interesting. - Swear to fucking God.
-這個我們也要吧  -沒錯我們倆都要
- Can we get that guy? - Yeah, we'll get that guy, too.
但這上面說他兄弟同意露陰
But it says here this guy will show his cock. Yeah.
-他倒是不長高  -他同意嗎
- Instead of growing up. Yeah. - He will?
但他們挺易怒的
They are very ornery by the way,
所以跟這些小不點得悠著點
so you gotta be very careful with these little guys.
安全第一
Safety first.
安全第一  好吧
Safety is first, all right?
在旁邊安排一個人拿著麻醉槍
I want somebody with a fucking tranquilizer gun
出事兒了就擊暈他
ready to knock this fucker out.
-我們要不要弄個...-梅斯催淚  高壓槍
- Do we want to get like a... - Mace. Taser guns.
小氣槍怎么樣
A pellet gun maybe?
不行  小氣槍會傷到他的
No, a pellet gun is gonna hurt him.
我只想弄暈他  暈死就行
I just want him out. Knocked out cold.
要我說我們還是認準法律漏洞
But I say we stick with the loophole. Right? Okay?
要是我們不把他到人看
If we don't consider him a human,
就單純的行為來講  我們就沒事
we just consider it an act, I think we're in the clear.
就像飛天瓦倫達馬戲團
Like The Flying Wallendas.
死了不少人也沒人告他們
You know, a lot of those guys died but they never sued anybody.
重要的是你們得記住
The important thing you guys gotta keep in mind
他們互相會八卦的
is that these things gossip.
聚在一起就八卦
They get together and they gossip.
-這點好  -我們最不希望看到的
- That's a good point. - And the last thing
就是他們聚到一起然后說
that we need is them getting together and saying,
他們嘲笑我們了
"Oh, they made fun of us."
那會抹黑斯特拉頓的
Like, it's gonna make Stratton look bad.
我就愛你這點  能想到這些破事
That's why I love you. You think of shit like that.
等他們來了  就把他們當自己人  好嗎
When they come in, we treat it just like one of us. Okay?
自己人  咕咕咕咕  自己人
One of us. Gooble gobble, one of us.
接納他們  自己人
We accept them, one of us!
咕咕咕咕  自己人
Gooble gobble, one of us.
接納他們  自己人
We accept them, one of us.
咕咕咕咕  自己人
Gooble gobble, one of us!
喬丹  你爸來了
Jordan! Your Dad's coming.
好像是運通卡賬單的事
Something about the American Express bill.
你能別讓他來嗎
Can you get him out of here?
能  你舔蛋去吧
Yeah. Lick my twat.
沒  我認真的
No, I'm serious!
該死  各位  假裝我們在工作
Fuck. Guys, act like we're working.
你他媽有股票單嗎
You got any fucking stock forms?
他來了  他來了
He's coming, he's coming.
隨便編點什么
Make some shit up.
我覺得要是我們把輝瑞制藥...
I think if we short Pfizer...
一個月43萬嗎  喬丹
$430,000 in one month, Jordy, huh?
你他媽的一個月
Four hundred and fucking
居然他媽的花43萬嗎
30,000 fucking dollars in one fucking month!
早上好  那都是商務花費  淡定點
Good morning. They're business expenses. Relax.
-商務花費嗎  -是
- Business expenses? - Yes.
-喬丹  你看你這都是什么  -什么
- Jordy, look what you got here. - What?
看這個  兩萬六美金一頓晚飯
Look at this. $26,000 for one fucking dinner!
不  這我能解釋
Okay. No, no. This could be explained.
爸  我們有客戶的  輝瑞制藥的客戶
Dad, we had clients. The Pfizer clients.
沒錯  阿根廷的上等腰肉牛排
Right. The porterhouse from Argentina.
還得買上等的香檳  都很貴的
Expensive champagne and... We had to buy champagne.
然后你還點了一堆狗屁配菜
And you ordered all the fucking sides.
-你自己跟他說  -我點了配菜  所以
- Tell him about the sides. - I ordered sides, so...
還配菜  26萬塊的配菜嗎
Sides? $26,000 worth of sides?
你這配菜治癌癥的嗎
What are these sides? They cure cancer?
問題是配菜的確治癌癥
The sides did cure cancer. That's the problem.
所以才這么貴
That's why they were expensive.
-你他媽閉嘴吧  -我認真的
- Shut the fuck up. - I'm serious.
-夠了  -還有EJ娛樂
- Stop. - And EJ Entertainment?
EJ娛樂是他媽什么東西
What the fuck is EJ Entertainment?
這個是
Well, that's...
是啊  喬丹  EJ娛樂是什么
Yeah, Jordy, what's EJ Entertainment?
這怎么形容呢
How do I describe this?
喬丹  是什么
Jord, what is that?
-這他媽是賣淫團伙  喬丹  -我知道
- It's a fucking prostitution ring, Jordy! - I know.
-是賣淫團伙知道嗎  -的確是賣淫團伙
- That's what it is! - That is what it is.
你看這么形容合適不
Isn't that the perfect description for it?
的確是這樣  但這都不是我干的
That is what it is. But none of these were charged to me.
這都是他們干的
This is all of them.
-是嗎  都是我們干的  -反正不是我
- Oh, that was all us? - It wasn't me though.
快他媽給他解釋清楚
Fucking explain this shit to him!
這他媽都是你花的錢
These are all of your fucking charges right here!
聯邦稅務部允許旅行女樂花費的  沒事
The IRS, they allow for T&A. It's fine.
旅行娛樂
T&E!
那叫旅行娛樂
是  我說的就是
Yeah. I said T&E.
-不是  你說的旅行女樂  -我沒說
- No, no. You said T&A. - No, I didn't.
你說了
Yeah, you did.
-我什么時候說了  -你說的旅行女樂
- When did I say that? - You said T&A.
那叫旅行娛樂
T&E!
我知道你對那頓飯不滿意
I know you're upset about the dinner,
你有道理生氣
and that makes sense because
因為我們的確花太多了
we did spend too much money.
但我說的就是旅行娛樂
But I said T&E.
別跟我說你說了什么  我都聽見了
Don't tell me what you said. I heard what you said.
-爸  他說的是旅行娛樂  -是嗎
- Dad. He said T&A. - He did?
絕對的  毫無疑問
Absolutely, no question.
我是要...
I'm trying to...
我就差一點
I'm getting this close!
-爸  別急  -我就差這么一點
- Dad, relax. - I'm getting this close.
我就是這意思  我想讓你敞開心扉  麥克斯
That's what I'm saying. I want you to open up more, Max.
你等著他哪天殺了你
He's gonna fucking kill you.
你干嘛憋著  你干嘛都憋著
Why do you hold it in? Why do you...
麥克斯  你干嘛非都憋著
Max, why do you hold it in?
夠了  你他媽給我滾出去
That's it. Get the fuck out of here!
-別  別別  -滾蛋  出去
- No, no, no! - Asshole, get out of here.
嫖什么妓女還能刷信用卡
What kind of hooker takes credit cards?
有錢的
A rich one.
斯特拉頓會雇三種妓女
At Stratton, there were three kinds of hookers.
藍籌股  頂尖好手  當模特的料子
The Blue Chips, top of the line, model material.
得花300到400美金
They cost between $300 and $500
你要是不想帶套就得多給小費
and you had to wear a condom unless you gave them a hefty tip,
當然我每次都給
which, of course, I always did.
然后就是納斯達克股  漂亮但活一般
Then came the NASDAQs, who were pretty, not great.
大概200到300塊錢
They cost between 200 and 300 bucks.
最后就是粉單股的渣子了
Finally, there were the Pink Sheets. Skanks.
大概不到100塊
They cost about 100 or less.
要是你不戴套的話
If you didn't wear a condom,
第二天就得去打青霉素了
you'd have to get a penicillin shot the next day
還得祈禱自己的老二別爛了
and pray your dick didn't fall off.
倒不是說這種我們就不干了
Not that we didn't fuck them, too.
相信我  我們都干了
Believe me, we did.
我又腰椎間盤突出了
It's that slipped disc thing again.
我知道你怎么回事  凈那啥了
I know what it is. You know, too much...
就跟EJ娛樂
...with EJ Entertainment.
爹
Pops.
家里怎么樣
How are things at home?
不是很好
Well, not the best.
她就是有點...你懂吧
She just doesn't... You know what I'm saying?
好像氣味啊
It's like the smell...
有種氣味  吸引力什么的
There's a smell, there's an attraction thing.
過段時間就越來越淡了
After a while it kind of fades away a little bit.
本來就該越來越淡的
Yeah, well. It's supposed to fade away.
-本來就  -婚姻就這樣  知道嗎
- Supposed to? - That's marriage. You know...
我和你媽結婚很長時間了
Your mother and I, we've been married a long, long time.
你難道覺得我們倆
What do you think? We're...
每兩分鐘就得上個床嗎
We're jumping into bed every two minutes?
-那可不行  -我很愛她
- It doesn't work that way. - I love her to death.
爸  我不想離婚  但是
I want to stay married, Dad, but...
現在世道太瘋狂了
It's crazy out there.
有些個姑娘  你真該見識見識
Some of these girls... You should see them.
老天
Oh, my God!
簡直是
They're fucking...
爹  她們現在的活兒
The things they're doing now, Pops.
絕對是更新換代了
I mean... I mean, it's on a whole other level.
-是嗎  -下邊還都剃光了
- Really? - And they're all shaved, too.
-去你的  -全跟白虎似的
- Get out of here! - All shaven.
-你就逗我吧  -沒逗你
- Are you kidding me? - Yeah.
-跟瓷娃娃一樣干凈  -沒毛嗎
- Bald as a china doll. - No bush?
-沒毛  -老天
- No bush. - Oh, my God!
突然之間  就一周
All of a sudden, one week,
所有人下邊就都干凈了
nobody had anything down there anymore.
新世界了
It's a new world.
從眉毛往下就沒毛了
They're bald from the eyebrows down.
一根毛沒有  想激光除過一樣
Nothing. Not a stitch. It's like lasers.
真是新世界了
Wow. A new world.
我真是生早了
I was born too... too early.
其實我從來不喜歡陰毛
I've never been a fan of the bush, to be honest.
-真的嗎  -是
- Really? - Yeah.
無所謂
I don't mind it.
爸
Dad.
我不想讓你為這些操心
I don't want you stressing out about any of this.
我怎么可能不操心
How can I not get stressed out?
看你都找些什么蠢貨給你工作
Look at the knuckleheads you got working for you.
我知道他們是傻瓜
I know they're knuckleheads
但我得讓他們羨慕我的生活  懂嗎
but I need them to want to live like me, you get it?
想過得像我一樣
To live like me.
喬丹
Jordy.
你這么折騰早晚遭報應
One of these days, the chickens are gonna come home to roost.
你覺得我瘋了嗎
You're looking at me like I'm crazy.
瘋了  你這叫傷風敗俗
Crazy? This is obscene.
的確傷風敗俗
It was obscene.
在現實世界中的確如此
In the normal world.
但誰愿意活在現實中
But who the fuck wanted to live there?
一起狂歡到屌炸天吧
Go party your fucking cocks off!
我們將成為華爾街的
We are about to become fucking legends
傳奇
on Wall Street!
我們的規劃將帶領公司
We got plans up here that's gonna take this company
一路沖上平流層
into the fucking stratosphere!
狼仔  狼仔
Wolfie! Wolfie!
去他媽的梅林銀行  管他呢
Fuck Merrill Lynch. Fuck them.
憑什么總讓他們
Why should they be taking
賺走我們的錢
all our fucking money all the fucking time?
這樣我們就是證券承銷商了
This way we become the underwriters.
我們下一步棋
It was our next big move.
就是找公司幫他們做首次公開募股
Finding companies to take public. IPOs.
這有這樣  那些華爾街的小崽子們
It was the only way these Wall Street pricks
才能不把我們當做野雞證券交易所
would ever stop thinking of us as some shitkicker bucket shop.
我們還有阿克利夫國際
We got Arncliffe International.
我們做事比較不尋常
See, we were a little different.
我們談正事的時候
We liked to get as fucked up as possible
喜歡嗑藥并喝得酩酊大醉
during our business powwows
這樣才能才思泉涌
in order to stimulate our free-flowing ideas,
所以我們吃安眠酮就像吃巧克力豆一樣
which is why we were popping these ludes like they were M&M's.
史蒂夫·麥登
Steve Madden.
那家公司歸我們了
We own the fucking companies...
絕對歸我們了
We own the companies...
不知道安眠酮是什么  我告訴你
Don't know what a lude is? I'll tell you.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
貌似安眠酮
Looks like those ludes
正在唐尼身上顯神跡呢
are working their magic on Donnie right now.
鎮定安眠酮
The Quaalude,
一般叫作安眠酮
or lude, as it is commonly referred to,
于1951年由一位印度醫生首次合成
was first synthesized in 1951 by an Indian doctor,
是點紅點的印度人  不是印第安人
that's dots, not feathers,
當時被當做鎮定催眠藥開給
as a sedative, and was prescribed to
壓力大的家庭婦女緩解睡眠障礙的
stressed-out housewives with sleep disorders.
但很快就有人發現
But pretty soon someone figured out
服藥后只要忍住15分鐘不睡
that if you resisted the urge to sleep for just 15 minutes,
就能爽翻天了
you got a pretty kick-ass high from it.
當然沒過多久大家就開始濫用安眠酮了
Didn't take long for people to start abusing ludes, of course.
1982年美國和全世界都把安眠酮
And in 1982, the U.S. Government Schedule 1'd them.
列為了一級管控藥物
Along with the rest of the world.
所以說安眠酮數量有限越吃越少
Which meant there was only a finite amount of these things left.
認真的  買都買不到
No shit, you can't even buy 'em anymore.
你們都慘了
You people are all shit out of luck.
你要說什么
What are you saying? What is it?
史蒂夫·麥登
Steve Madden.
史蒂夫
Steve.
你記得那些廣告嗎
You remember those ads?
那些有鼓眼泡的大頭姑娘
Those giant-headed girls with the bug eyes
穿著笨重的高跟鞋
wearing those big clunky shoes?
上學時是我朋友  史蒂夫·麥登
My friend from school, Steve Madden.
上學時是他朋友  史蒂夫·麥登
His friend from school, Steve Madden.
史蒂夫·麥登是當下炙手可熱的女鞋品牌
Steve Madden was the name in women's shoes at the moment.
整條華爾街的人都想幫他上市
And all of Wall Street was begging to take his company public.
來啊  你要說什么
Go ahead, go ahead, what is it?
但你猜他跟誰是發小
Except, guess who grew up with him?
-女鞋  -女鞋
- Women's shoes. - Women's shoes.
正是我的副主管
My very own Vice President.
女鞋
Women's shoes!
鉆石唐尼·亞速
Diamond Donnie Azoff.
-史蒂夫·麥登  -史蒂夫
- Steve Madden. - Steve.
史蒂夫
Steve.
喬·貝  喬·貝
Hey, JB, JB, JB, JB.
過來瞧瞧這個妞
You gotta come check this fucking chick out.
快看
Look at this. Look.
她要是我妹我一定要了她
I would fuck that girl if she was my sister.
她就是有艾滋病我都愿意
I would let that girl give me fucking AIDS.
看看狼哥如何搞定她吧
You want to see the Wolf handle this?
她好正
She's hot.
克里斯蒂
Cristy.
喬丹  這是我的朋友內奧米
Jordan, this is my friend Naomi.
-你好  -內奧米
- Hi. Nice to meet you. - Naomi.
內奧米  你好
Naomi, nice to meet you.
你家真棒
You got an awesome place here.
這么大的房子我還從來沒見過
I've don't think I've ever been in a house this big before.
-是嗎  -是
- Oh, really? - Yeah.
外面有漂亮的沙灘
Beautiful beach out there.
布萊爾·霍林斯沃思
Blair Hollingsworth.
布萊爾  你好
Hi, Blair. Nice to meet you.
-你叫布萊爾對吧  -是
- Your name's Blair, right? - Yeah.
你喜歡摩托艇嗎
You like to Jet Ski?
我沒開過
I've never done it before.
你從沒開過摩托艇嗎
You've never Jet Ski'd in your life?
是  從沒開過
No, I've never Jet Ski'd.
你從沒坐過摩托艇嗎
You've never been on a Jet Ski?
你要問她多少次
How many times are you gonna ask her?
她沒坐過摩托艇
She's never been on a Jet Ski.
不知道  也許再問幾次吧
I don't know. Might ask her a couple more times.
好吧
Okay. Sure.
我是希爾迪  很高興認識你
Hi. I'm Hildy. Nice to meet you.
喬丹  泰瑞莎讓你去幫忙
Jordan, Teresa needs your help.
我待會兒過去
Yeah, I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
跟她說下我待會過去
Just tell her I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
你干嘛不自己和你老婆說
Why don't you tell your wife that?
我想去  但我現在
I might do that, but I'm having
-在跟別人說話  -你當我是你秘書嗎
- a conversation right now. - What am I, your secretary?
我覺得我們該走了
You know what, I think we should get going.
等等  你們去哪
Wait, wait. Where you guys going?
我們必須走了  還要趕兩場派對
We gotta go. We got two other parties to go to.
-我們可以在這喝一杯  -喝一杯吧
- We can stay for a drink. - Yeah, stay for a drink.
不了  我們還要趕兩場派對
No. We got two other parties we're supposed to get to.
但我們可以在這喝一杯
But we can stay for a drink...
她真是
She's
美爆了
perfect.
-你想喝香檳嗎  -可以
- You like champagne? - I do.
她美爆了
She's perfect.
唐尼  你他媽在干嘛
Donnie, what the fuck are you doing?
你個渣...
You piece of...
請你不要介意  他有點...
You're gonna have to excuse my friend. He gets...
快滾
Get the fuck out!
喬丹  你一定要操她  她太正了
Jordan, you gotta fuck her, bro. She's so hot!
加油  唐尼
Yeah, Donnie!
讓他擼完  希爾迪
Let him fucking finish, Hildy.
這樣太他媽暴力了
That's fucking rude.
淑女點好嗎
Have some fucking manners.
灣脊區  在史坦頓島附近  對吧
So, Bay Ridge, that's near Staten Island, right?
在布魯克林  穿過韋拉札諾海峽大橋
Brooklyn, across the Verrazano Bridge.
《周末夜狂熱》的地盤
Saturday Night Fever territory.
沒錯  幾內亞峽谷
That's right. Guinea Gulch.
我們把韋拉札諾海峽大橋叫做幾內亞跳板
We call the Verrazano Bridge the Guinea Gangplank.
是
Right.
我猜你是意大利人吧
So I presume you're Italian?
我爸爸是
On my dad's side.
我還有荷蘭  德國  英格蘭血統
I'm also Dutch, German, English.
我是混血兒
I'm a mutt.
混血
Yeah. You're a mutt.
我在倫敦還有親戚
Yeah, I still have family over there though, in London.
艾瑪姑姑  她最好了
My Aunt Emma. She's the best.
有種英國范兒  特別優雅
Very British, you know. She's a classy lady.
這就說的通了
That explains it then.
說通什么
Explains what?
你啊  你是女公爵對吧
It explains you. I mean, you're a duchess, right?
灣脊區的女公爵
The Duchess of Bay Ridge.
不好意思
Excuse me.
請給我一根吸管
Could I get a straw, please?
謝謝
Thank you.
真沒想到你會向克里斯蒂要我的電話
So I was a little surprised you asked Cristy for my number.
為什么驚訝
Why is that?
你是有家室的人了吧
Aren't you married?
是  所以呢
Well... Yeah, but what?
有家室就不能有朋友啦
Married people can't have friends?
我們要當朋友啊?
We're gonna be friends?
當然  你不想跟我做朋友嗎
Yeah. You don't want to be my friend?
我們可不會是單純朋友
We're not gonna be friends.
晚上我會做一些服裝設計
And at night I work on my designs.
各種女性內衣
I have an entire line of lingerie.
女用背心  束身胸衣  三角褲
You know, camisoles, bustiers, panties.
她居然還設計三角褲
She designs women's panties, too?
天哪
Oh, my God!
喬丹  快想個上去的借口
Come on, Jordan, think of a way to get up to her apartment.
你想上去喝點茶什么的嗎
You wanna come up for some tea or something?
茶?  好啊
Tea? Yeah.
-熱茶嗎  -是
- Like hot tea? - Yeah.
行啊  聽上去不錯
Oh, yeah. That sounds nice. Yeah.
茶  我太他媽想上去喝茶了
Tea. Fuck, yeah, I wanted to come up for tea.
有大吉嶺茶或洛神花茶之類的嗎
Like Darjeeling or rose hip, something nice like that?
有
Sure.
這是洛基
This is Rocky.
看看這是誰  問聲好  洛基
Oh, who's this? Say hi, Rocky.
你好  小家伙
Hi, sweetheart.
特別好
Okay.
你能點一下火嗎  我馬上就出來
Why don't you light a fire or something and I'll be right out.
-火  在這嗎  -是
- Yeah. Fire, here? - Sure.
畫挺好看的
I like your painting here. It's...
神啊幫幫我  我怎么才能上這姑娘
God, help me. How do I fuck this girl?
你沒事吧
You all right?
沒事  只是在點火
Yeah, yeah. Just trying to light the fire here.
回電話  泰瑞莎
打住  打住  你該走了
That's it. That's it, you're leaving.
別亂來  回家找老婆去
Don't get involved. Go home to your wife.
你也想的到
As you can probably guess,
我把她操翻天了...
I fucked her goddamn brains out...
天啊
Jesus Lord!
總共11秒
For 11 seconds.
你剛剛射了嗎
Did you just come?
是啊  我射了
Oh, yeah, I just came.
你呢  你高潮了嗎
Did you? Did you come?
-沒  -沒有嗎
- No. - No?
好吧
Okay.
我還硬著  給我點時間
I'm still hard so just give me a sec.
好
Sure.
快起來  寶貝  快起來
Come on, baby, come on.
來了  來了
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
天啊
Oh, God!
滾開  洛基  壞小狗
Fuck off, Rocky! Bad dog.
你有餅干之類的東西嗎
You have a biscuit or something like that?
別管它
It's okay.
-繼續  -洛基  一邊玩去
- Just keep going. - Rocky, go play.
邊兒去  洛基  走開  走開
Go play, Rocky. Go, go, go, go.
你真是瘋了
You're crazy.
我無法自拔
I couldn't get enough.
她的陰道就像海洛因
I mean, her pussy was like heroin to me.
其實也不只是因為性
And it wasn't just about the sex, either.
內奧米和我特別合拍  我們
Naomi and I got along. I mean, we...
我們有相同的興趣
We had similar interests and shit.
小火車
Choo-choo train.
我可以  我可以  我可以  我可以
I think I can. I think I can. I think I can. I think I can.
全放在這吸如何
Yeah, yeah. Let's toke it all on there, huh?
爽
Oh, shit!
你
You!
從車里滾出來
Get out of the fucking car!
天啊
Jesus Christ.
死混蛋  操
Son of a bitch! Oh, fuck!
冷靜  親愛的  冷靜
Relax, sweetheart. Relax.
-死混蛋  -好了  好了  天啊
- Son of a fucking bitch! - Okay, okay... Geez!
寶貝  住手
Okay, babe, stop!
求你了
Please.
混蛋
Bitch!
-你干嘛呀  -派對上的那個婊子嗎
- What are you doing... - That whore from the party?
天啊
Jesus Christ!
你他媽怎么了
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我以為你在他媽的海灘
I thought you were at the fucking beach!
我不知道你在這
I didn't know you were here!
你一直都在忙這個嗎
That's where you've fucking been?
忙那個派對婊子
With that fucking whore from the party?
我以為你在海濱別墅
I thought you were at the beach house.
你怎么可以這樣對我
How could you do this to me?
親愛的  別這樣
Sweetie, come on...
你成什么樣了  喬丹
Who the fuck are you, Jordan?
完全變了一個人
You're like a completely different fucking person!
我錯了  我不知道該怎么跟你說
I made a mistake. I don't know what to tell you,
寶貝  我
babe. I...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-對不起  -你就喜歡她那樣的嗎
- I'm sorry. - Is that who... is that what you want?
你愛她嗎
Do you love her?
回答我
Answer me.
我很愧疚
I felt horrible.
3天后我簽了離婚協議
Three days later, I filed for a divorce
并且讓內奧米搬進了公寓
and moved Naomi into the apartment.
隨你怎么說  但女公爵確實有她的一套
Say what you will, but the Duchess did have style.
她帶了一個裝璜師  看了看房子的風水
She brought in a decorator, feng shui'd the whole place.
她還雇了個男同管家
She even hired a gay butler.
聰明  老練  職業
This guy was smart, sophisticated, professional.
非常非常棒
Really, really great.
是茉莉花嗎
Is that jasmine?
是  我還以為能難住你  你太厲害了
Yes, sir. I tried to stump you this evening. Very good.
太厲害了  您鼻子很好
Very good. Great nose.
除了有一次
Except for that one time.
天啊
Oh, my God!
你好
Oh, hey.
已經周三了嗎
Is it wednesday already?
別停
Oh, don't stop.
真的假的啊
What the fuck!
這下完蛋了
That is fucked up!
他一定以為我們
He must have thought we were still
這周還要呆在漢普頓斯
at the Hamptons this weekend, you know.
他們在哪兒做的  親愛的  臥室里嗎
Where were they doing it, sweetheart? In the bedroom?
他們在哪里都做了
They were everywhere.
有兩個在那邊桌子上
There were two guys over there on the table.
這邊還有更多
There were more over here.
有四個就在這里做的
There were four right here.
你他媽不是逗我吧  就在這里嗎
Are you fucking serious? Right there?
你怎么不早說  寶貝
Why didn't you tell me? Sweet.
寶貝  這還不是最糟的
Oh, baby, it gets worse.
他們走了以后  我檢查了下屋子
After they left, I checked the apartment.
然后呢
Right. What?
什么問題  寶貝
What is it, babe? What?
我的錢在哪
Where's my money?
我不知道您的錢在哪
I don't know where your money...
我的錢他媽的在哪  在哪
Where is my fucking money? Where is it?
我不知道錢在哪  貝爾福先生
I don't know where your money is, Mr. Belfort.
-我什么都沒做  -如果你不說
- I didn't do anything. - If you don't get...
他說的全他媽是假話
He's lying through his fucking teeth.
我們從頭開始
Let's start from the beginning.
我們從頭開始好吧
Let's start from the beginning, all right?
你叫了一些朋友來對吧
You invited some friends over, right?
莫名其妙的局勢就失控了
One thing led to another. Things got out of hand.
這我們可以理解
We understand that, we do.
我們也經常犯渾  生活墮落得一塌糊涂
We do blow all the time. We're fucking degenerates ourselves.
瞧瞧我們
Look at us, right?
但有人從我的公寓里偷了錢
But money was stolen from my apartment.
就從我放襪子的抽屜里
Right from my sock drawer. All right?
我說過了  我不知道您的錢在哪
Like I said, I don't know where your money is.
我們從頭開始  都有誰來
Just start from the beginning. Who came over?
那天和平時一樣
It was just a normal day.
我知道你們下一天才回來
I knew you were coming home the next day.
所以不會有問題  我都會清理干凈
So everything would be fine. It'd be cleaned up.
早餐時我磕了點藥
I got a little high at breakfast.
所以我有點小興奮  我吃了些雞蛋
So I got a little happy. I had some eggs,
還吃了點冰淇淋
I had a little bit of ice cream.
然后我想  我有哪個朋友喜歡冰淇淋
And then I said, "Who do I know that likes ice cream?"
魯迪喜歡  所以我叫了魯迪
It's my friend, Rudy. So I called Rudy.
-誰是魯迪  -誰是魯迪
- Who's Rudy? - Yeah, who's Rudy?
-你知道誰是魯迪  -我  我不
- You know who Rudy is. Come on. - Me? I don't...
-你認識  -魯迪他媽的是誰
- You know... - Who the fuck is Rudy?
我不認識叫魯迪的
I don't know anyone named Rudy.
上個月  在棒棒糖俱樂部
Last month. The Lollipop Club.
你認識魯迪的  他就在那兒跳舞
You know who Rudy was. Dancing...
你認識魯迪嗎
You know who Rudy is?
我他媽根本不認識什么
I don't fucking know any...
你想說什么
What do you mean?
他去了棒棒糖俱樂部嗎
So he went to The Lollipop Club?
沒錯  他就在棒棒糖俱樂部
Oh, he was at The Lollipop Club for sure.
在臺上  和其他人一起跳
On the stage, grinding with everybody.
我喝多了  我喜歡跳舞
I got fucked up. I like to dance.
我不知道  也許我見過他  也許沒有
I don't know. Maybe I met him, maybe I didn't.
我他媽的見過很多人
I meet a lot of fucking people.
-你說什么  -有他媽五萬美金
- What are you saying? - $50,000 was stolen
從我抽屜里被偷走了
from my fucking sock drawer!
我女朋友所有的首飾都沒了
All my girlfriend's jewelry is gone.
-東西他媽在哪  -魯迪  什么玩意
- Where the fuck is it? - Rudy. What the fuck?
是不是你的基友魯迪拿了我的東西
Did your fucking little faggot friend Rudy take my shit?
是不是他  回答我
Did he? Answer me!
我知道了  現在我知道為什么了
Okay. Now I get it. Now I get why I'm...
就因為我是同性戀
This is a gay thing.
你們都
See, all of you...
你覺得我們找你是因為你是基佬
You think this is 'cause you're a fag?
我表弟也他媽的是基佬
My cousin's a fucking faggot.
我還跟他和他男友一起去度假呢
And I go on vacation with him and his boyfriend.
我喜歡基佬
I love fags.
這件事責任在你  知道不
You were in charge, right?
沒人能偷我的東西  懂嗎
I will not be stolen from. You get that?
我喜歡同性戀  但我不喜歡你
I fucking like gay people. I don't like you.
他應該雇一個他媽的
He should've hired a fucking
墨西哥人  像我家一樣
Mexican like I have in my fucking house.
操  我操
Shit! What the fuck...
說話  混蛋  說話啊
Talk, you fuck, talk!
我要把你扔下去  你個死基佬
I'm gonna drop you, you faggot!
錢在哪
Where is it?
切斯特和托比對尼古拉斯有些殘暴
Chester and Toby, they went all yakuza on Nicholas.
他們玩嗨了
You know, they got crazy.
我不知道
I don't know!
我不得不叫警察來
I had to call the cops
以免他們把那個可憐的家伙殺了
just to keep them from killing the poor guy.
我給了他們每人1000塊
I gave them each 1,000
告訴他們尼古拉斯做的好事
bucks and told them what Nicholas had done.
結果他們也狠揍了他一頓
Then they kicked his ass.
謝謝  警官
Thanks again, Officer.
其實我不怎么在乎那五萬
It's not like I cared about the 50 grand anyway.
我幾乎每天都能掙那么多
I was making that much almost every day
從隨便哪個老鼠倉里
through one rathole or another.
老鼠倉就是朋友開的戶  比如布拉德
Now a rathole is a friend, like Brad here,
他以他的名義幫我持有股票
who held stock in his name for me.
你是誰  猶太人版杰克·尼克勞斯嗎
Who are you supposed to be, huh? Jack Nickle-Jew?
杰克·尼克勞斯  美國著名高爾夫運動員
我把價格抬上去后
I'd drive the price up then
他把股票賣掉  然后把大部分利潤還給
he'd sell and kick most of the profits back to...
沒錯  給我
You guessed it, me.
都是現金  都不在賬上
All cash. None of it's on the books.
當然是違法的
A big no-no, of course, in the eyes of the law.
我們有了新的證券律師  曼尼·瑞絲金
Enter our new securities attorney, Manny Riskin.
我們付他每小時700元聽他的恐嚇
700 bucks an hour to be the voice of doom.
聽著  你要是招惹了證監會
Listen to me. You piss up the SEC's leg,
一定會吃不了兜著走
you end up with your tits in a wringer.
不過別擔心  證監會的我已經打點好了
Do not worry about it. I have the SEC under control.
這些傻逼們在干嘛
What the fuck are these imbeciles doing?
你們在搞什么玩意兒
What are you doing? Hey!
證監會的人來了
We got the SEC in here.
證券交易委員會
The Securities and Exchange Commission
派了兩名律師來查我們的文件
sent two lawyers down to review our files.
我把他們安排在了會議室
So I set them up in our conference room
放了竊聽器
and I had it bugged
把空調開到最猛
and the air conditioning turned up so high
讓里面冷得像南極一樣
that it felt like Antarctica in there.
這一直都這么冷嗎
Is it always this cold in here?
不知道
I don't know.
當他們在那里
Then, while they were looking
尋找我的罪證時
for a smoking gun in that room...
阿克利夫國際現在很火
Arncliffe International is on fire.
我正在這里大張旗鼓
I was gonna fire off a bazooka in here,
為我們的最近的IPO做準備
offering up our latest IPO.
IPO的意思是首次公開募股
An IPO is an initial public offering.
是指一家企業首次
It's the first time a stock
將股票向公眾出售
is offered for sale to the general population.
作為負責上市的機構
Now, as the firm taking the company public,
我們來制定發行價
we set the initial sales price
再把股票賣回給我們的朋友  那些
then sold those shares right back to our friends. The...
好吧
Look.
我知道你壓根不懂我在說什么
I know you're not following what I'm saying anyway, right?
沒關系  無所謂
That's okay. That doesn't matter.
關鍵在于
The real question is this.
這合法嗎
"Was all this legal?"
必須他媽的不合法
Absolutely fucking not.
但我們能賺到多得不知道怎么花的錢
But we were making more money than we knew what to do with.
在錢多得不知道怎么花的時候
And what do you do when you're making
你要怎么花呢
more money than you know what to do with?
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
你愿意嫁給我嗎
Will you marry me?
天啊
Oh, my God.
你是答應了嗎
Is that a yes?
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
是的  是的  我確定
Yeah, I'm sure. Yeah, I'm sure.
-你愿意嗎  -愿意
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
我在拉斯維加斯的
I held my bachelor party
米拉奇辦了單身派對
at the Mirage in Las Vegas.
從飛機上就開始縱酒狂歡了
The flight there alone was a bacchanal.
成家前的最后放縱
One last blowout for the gods before I settled down for good.
上百名斯特拉頓人
A hundred Strattonites,
50個妓女
50 hookers,
落地了還有50個
plus 50 more waiting once we landed.
當然也少不了毒品
Oh, and the drugs.
這么說吧  我們飛機
I mean, I tell you, our plane
就像是插上翅膀的藥房
was like a pharmacy with wings.
這個周末一共花了我兩百萬美金
All told, the weekend cost me two million bucks,
包括翻修整個28樓的費用
including the cost of refurbishing the entire 28th floor.
親吻新娘
Kiss the bride.
但婚禮像童話般美好
But the wedding was something out of a fairy tale.
內奧米是我的公爵夫人
With Naomi, my Duchess,
而我就是她帥氣的公爵
me, her handsome Duke,
巴哈馬海洋俱樂部  則是我們的城堡
and The Bahamas Ocean Club, our castle.
當然  在單身派對后  我這個公爵
Of course, after the bachelor party, me, the Duke,
得打點青霉素
needed a few penicillin shots so he could
才能安全地洞房
safely consummate the marriage.
青霉素有治療性病的效果
我是巴瑞·克萊門  正在拍攝婚禮現場
Hey! Barry Kleinman, filming the wedding.
對你兒子說點什么吧
A few words for your son?
喬丹  牢記我的話
Jordan. Remember what I told you.
關于你的陰莖和她的陰道的
It involves your penis and her vagina.
你懂的  你知道自己能做什么  喬迪
And you know, you know what you can do, Jordy.
天啊
Oh, my God!
艾瑪姑姑
Aunt Emma?
真不敢相信您能來
I can't believe you came!
喬丹  喬丹  看看誰來了
Jordan! Jordan! Look who came!
是艾瑪姑姑
It's Aunt Emma.
艾瑪姑姑
Aunt Emma.
-喬丹  你真可愛  -你好嗎
- Oh, Jordan, dear, how lovely. - Hey, how you doing?
真榮幸見到您
It's a pleasure to finally meet you in person.
吃了不少甜甜圈吧
Into the donuts, I see.
他鼻子上沾的可卡因
我   我
Oh, I... I...
這個
Well...
我經歷過60年代  親愛的
I lived through the '60s, my dear.
美國六十年代期間毒品泛濫
好好享受吧
Enjoy the day.
真是個驚喜  我都不知道
She surprised me. I didn't even know.
再走幾步  準備好
Just one more step. Are you ready?
-這是去哪  -別偷看
- Where are we going? - Keep your eyes closed.
一  二  三
One, two, three!
這是什么
What is this?
-你的新婚禮物  -什么
- It's your wedding present. - What?
是你的新婚禮物  親愛的
It's your wedding present, sweetheart.
什么
What?
-你開玩笑吧  -是真的
- Are you serious? - I'm serious.
一艘游艇
A fucking yacht?
游艇正在富翁中流行
For millionaires whose ships have come in,
豪華舒適的游艇才能帶來頂級享受
pricey pleasure boats are for the most fun afloat.
150英尺長的綠色船體
It's no coincidence that its 150 feet of green hull
正是鈔票的顏色  起航
is the color of cash. Anchors aweigh!
天啊  親愛的
Oh, my God! Baby!
-我覺得你會喜歡的  -太瘋狂了
- I think you like it? - You're crazy.
-喜歡嗎  -喜歡
- You like it? - Yes!
接下來三周
For three weeks,
我們乘著內奧米號穿過加勒比海
we sailed the Naomi through the Caribbean,
最后抵達位于長島的家
eventually taking her home to Long Island,
我們在那買了棟房子
where we bought a house.
長島黃金海岸  七英畝的地盤
Seven acres on the Gold Coast of Long Island.
世界上最昂貴的地產
The most expensive real estate in the world.
仆人  廚師  園藝師  應有盡有
With maids, cooks, landscapers, you name it.
甚至還有兩個輪班的保鏢
We even had two guards who worked in shifts.
都叫羅科
Both named Rocco.
18個月之后
簡直是天上人間
It was heaven on earth.
起來  你這個混蛋
Wake up, you piece of shit!
威尼斯是誰
Who's Venice?
誰
Who?
誰  誰
Who? Who?
還問誰  別裝傻了
"Who?" What are you, a fucking owl?
她是誰
Who is she?
昨晚睡的婊子嗎
Some little hooker you were fucking last night?
你他媽說什么呢  沒有
What the fuck are you talking about? No.
不可能  寶貝  沒有
No way, baby, no!
你夢里還喊她名字呢
You were calling her name in your sleep!
你他媽瘋了吧  我沒有
Are you out of your fucking mind? I don't...
我都不知道威尼斯是誰
I don't even know who Venice is.
威尼斯是啥意思
What the fuck does that even mean? Venice.
這是我這輩子聽過的最扯蛋的事了
That's the stupidest shit I've ever heard in my fucking life!
威尼斯
Venice...
威尼斯  親愛的  你在哪
Venice, baby, where are you?
威尼斯
Venice!
你去哪了
Where'd you go?
親愛的  你要玩狠的是吧
Oh, baby. Oh, you're gonna play rough, huh?
-天啊  -你喜歡嗎
- Oh, Jesus Christ! - You like that?
我喜歡  我喜歡
I like it. I like it.
小狼  小狼  小狼  小狼
Wolfie, Wolfie, Wolfie, Wolfie.
小狼?
Wolfie?
是我的安全詞  是我的安全詞
Yeah, it's my safe word, baby. It's my safe word.
我他媽才不管你的安全詞呢
I don't give a fuck about your safe word!
-拜托  -你他媽閉嘴
- Come on! - Shut the fuck up!
閉嘴  小賤貨
Shut up, you little bitch!
你真是個下流的妞
You're a fucking dirty little birdy!
對了
That's right.
對了  我忘了
That's right! I forgot.
我都忘了  寶貝
I forgot, baby.
唐尼和我在威尼斯投資了個酒店公寓
Donnie and I were investing in a condominium complex in Venice.
所以你誤會了
That's why all this confusion.
你還去意大利投資了
Oh, you're investing in Italy?
不是意大利  是加州
Not Italy. California.
-是嗎  加州  -對
- Oh, California? - Yeah.
鬼話連篇的混蛋
You're a lying piece of shit!
公爵夫人  親愛的
Duchess, baby, come on.
你他媽別叫我夫人
Don't you fucking "Duchess" Me.
別叫我夫人
Don't you "Duchess" Me!
你以為我不知道你的小伎倆
Do you really think that I don't know what you're up to?
-你是有孩子的人了  喬丹  -是啊
- You're a father now, Jordan. - Yeah.
-你該像個父親樣  -我知道
- You're a father now. - I know...
可你做事還那么幼稚
And you're still acting like an infant!
去你媽的
God damn it!
寶貝  你得管管你的臭脾氣了
Baby, you know, you got real anger issues.
是誰凌晨三點了
Who is the one who flew in here
才開著傻逼直升機回來
at 3 in the morning on their stupid helicopter
還吵醒了斯凱拉  是你
and woke up Skylar? That was you!
吵醒了斯凱拉  簡直是屁話
Oh, Skylar! Oh, fucking bullshit!
你有注意過我剛給高爾夫場
Does it even matter to you that I just had that driving range
鋪了百慕大草嗎  喬丹
sodded with Bermuda grass, Jordan,
百慕大草  一種暖季型高爾夫用草
-全都被你毀了  -天啊  百慕大草
- and now you fucking wrecked it! - Oh, my God... Bermuda grass.
你連看都不看
No, you didn't research the whole thing
也從來不和高爾夫球場的人打交道
and deal with the fucking golf course people!
天啊
Oh, my God,
你還得和球場的人打交道
you had to deal with the golf course people, too!
真是悲劇啊  親愛的  天啊
What a Greek tragedy, honey! Oh, my God!
你是不是還得親手付他們現金啊
You probably had to pay them in cash with your hands!
辛苦你了
What a fucking burden.
除了整天刷我的信用卡之外
And actually do some work
還得做這么辛苦的事  是吧
besides swiping my fucking credit card all day, huh?
我都跟不上你的職業變化了  親愛的
Because I can't keep track of your professions, honey.
上個月你還是紅酒鑒定家
'Cause last month you were a wine connoisseur.
現在又成了高雅的景觀設計師
Now you're an aspiring landscape architect!
-這么說吧...別  -去你媽的
- Let me get that right... No! - Fuck you!
你敢把水潑來試試
Don't fucking dare throw that fucking water at me.
你敢潑
Don't you fucking dare.
冷靜  親愛的
All right, honey?
你能不能...
Now will you just...
我們談談吧  好嗎
We could talk this out, all right?
動口不動手  知道嗎
We just use our words. You know?
交流
Communicate.
行嗎
Okay?
來吧  親愛的
Come on, sweetheart.
說說話  談談
Talk to me. Talk to me.
別再秀肌肉了  喬丹
Stop flexing your muscles, Jordan.
看著跟腦殘一樣
You look like a fucking imbecile.
寶貝  別這樣
Babe, come on.
你丈夫身材這么好
You should feel happy you got a husband
你該高興啊
who's in such great shape like this, huh?
過來
Come here.
過來  親親我
Come on, give me a kiss.
你看起來美極了
You look so beautiful right now.
-來吧  -親你?
- Come on. - Kiss you?
-你好美啊  -親你?
- You look so beautiful... - Kiss you?
是啊  就親一下
Yeah, give me one...
操
Fuck you!
沒錯  早晨的慣例
Ah, yes, my morning ritual.
起床先跟內奧米
First I'd get up and fight with Naomi
就前一晚的什么傻事吵架
about whatever it is I did the night before.
然后蒸個桑拿
Next was a steam so I could sweat out
排掉留在身體里的毒品
the drugs still in my system.
然后評估一下損失
Then I'd assess the damage.
滴眼藥水
Drown out my eyeballs.
吃點"背痛藥"  開始這一天
Take my "Back pills" To get the day started,
然后想法兒跟內奧米和好
then seek to make up with Naomi.
早上好  爸比
Good morning, Daddy.
給人家的親親呢
Where's my kiss?
小甜心
Hey, sweetheart.
爸比可以跟兩個甜心都親親嗎
Does Daddy get a kiss from both of his little girls, huh?
不行
Oh, no.
爸比不能碰媽咪
No, Daddy doesn't even get to touch Mommy
很久很久
for a very, very,
都不能碰
very long time.
爸比對剛才的話非常抱歉
Daddy's really sorry about what he said in the other room.
那都是氣話
He didn't mean any of it.
爸比不用浪費口舌
Daddy shouldn't waste his time.
從現在起
And from now on,
媽咪在家只會穿
it's gonna be nothing but short,
超短的小裙子了
short skirts around the house.
你知道嗎  爸比
And you know something else, Daddy?
媽咪好討厭穿小內褲啊
Mommy is just so sick and tired of wearing panties.
-是嗎  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
其實
In fact,
她已經把內褲
she's decided to throw them
都丟掉了
all away.
看好了  爸比
So take a good look, Daddy.
以后在家會經常看到哦
You're gonna be seeing an awful lot of this around the house.
寶貝
Oh, baby...
是嗎  媽咪
Yeah, Mommy.
-是啊  -但不許碰
- Yeah... - But no touching.
老天啊
Oh, gosh.
怎么了  爸比
What's wrong, Daddy?
寶貝
Baby.
天啊
God!
你快看
Look at this shit.
好吧  媽咪想和爸比玩游戲
Okay. Mommy likes to play games with Daddy.
媽咪  你有注意過那只
Mommy, have you ever noticed anything odd about Mr.
毛毛熊有點奇怪嗎
Mr. Fuzzy Bear over there?
他的眼睛有點奇怪  是吧
His eyes seem to be a little bit odd, don't they?
是啊  眼睛有點奇怪
Yeah, there's something a little bit different about his eyes.
沒錯  是的  打個招呼  媽咪
Yes! I think it's true. Say "Hi," Mommy.
跟羅科和羅科打個招呼
Say "Hi" To Rocco and Rocco.
打招呼  伙計們你們好
Say "Hi." Hi, fellas.
都看到了嗎
See that, huh?
這么多天來
Of all the fucking days,
她偏偏挑今天來挑逗我
she chooses today to give me blue balls!
今天可是斯特拉頓史上最重要的一天
I mean, today was the biggest day in Stratton's history,
我得理清頭緒
and I needed to be thinking straight.
喬丹
Hey, Jordan!
-歡迎  -史蒂夫來了嗎
- Welcome. - Steve here yet?
今天我們要為史蒂夫·麥登首次公開籌股
This was the day that we launched the Steve Madden IPO.
人都齊了  大家都歡欣鼓舞著呢
Troops are all here, everyone's all rallied, excited.
一切都要按部就班
Everything had to run tight.
不容有差
It had to be perfect.
那熊孩子在做什么
What the fuck is that kid doing?
他在干嘛
What's he doing?
公司史上規模最大的公開募股
The biggest IPO in this firm's history.
他你媽的在做什么
What the fuck is he doing?
他戴的是領結嗎
Is he... Is he wearing a bow tie?
你好
Hi.
感覺怎么樣
How're you doing?
很好
Good.
你擦魚缸呢
You cleaning the fish bowl?
我恰好有空
I just... I had a minute and...
你有空
You had a minute.
非得在今天擦魚缸嗎  今天
And today you needed to clean the fish bowl? Today?
我已經做完工作了  有點空閑時間
I had finished my paperwork and I had a couple of minutes.
好吧  很高興見到你
Okay. Nice to meet you.
非得在發行日
On new issue day?
非他媽的在發行日嗎
On cocksucking, motherfucking new issue day?
你就干這個
This is what you do?
大家聽著
Hey, everybody, listen up!
發行日這天還玩寵物
This is what happens when
就是這個下場
you fuck with your pets on new issue day!
戴著你的小領結
Take your little bow tie, get your shit,
收攤子走人  聽懂了嗎
and get the fuck out of my office! You understand?
滾蛋
Get the fuck out!
各就各位
Everybody on point!
你們是來這賺錢的  各就各位
We are here to make money. Everybody on point.
這兒就是個狼窩  而我愛的也正是這點
A real wolf pit, which is exactly how I liked it.
喬丹  看看我在大廳遇到誰了
Jordan, look what I caught in the lobby.
遇到個天才
I caught a genius.
那就是史蒂夫·麥登
Enter Steve Madden.
偉大的美國鞋匠
The great American cobbler.
炙手可熱的女鞋制造者
Red-hot ladies footwear impresario.
多虧了唐尼
And thanks to Donnie,
我們才能幫他的公司上市
we were taking his company public.
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特爬出原始的泥濘
Stratton Oakmont was crawling out of the primordial ooze.
再也不是井底之蛙了
Pond scum no more.
所以得讓他們見見你
That's why they gotta see your face.
你要鼓舞士氣
You get them fired up so
大家才能拼命賣股票  好嗎
they push the shit out of this stock. Okay?
不僅如此  唐尼和我
And not only that, Donnie and I secretly owned
秘密持有史蒂夫·麥登鞋業85%的股份
85% of Steve Madden Shoes,
這是法律絕對不允許的
which legally speaking was a big no-no,
但我們打算著狠狠撈上一筆
but we'd get filthy fucking rich if our troops got behind it.
我們要鼓舞士氣
Our job was to get them worked up.
但也不能太士氣高漲了
But not too worked up.
大家好
Hello. If...
如果有不認識我的
For those of you who don't know me...
我叫史蒂夫·麥登
My name's Steve Madden.
我們知道你是誰
Yeah, we know who you are.
盒子上都印著你的名字呢
Your name is on the box.
拿鞋子  給他們看看鞋子
Get the shoes. Show them the shoes.
-給他們看看鞋子  -好
- Show them the shoes. - Okay. Yeah.
這鞋子很酷的
Anyway, you know, this shoe is pretty cool.
叫瑪麗璐
This is the Mary Lou,
我的成名作
which is really the shoe that put me on the map.
如果沒有它  我就不會站在這
Without it, I wouldn't be here.
這是給胖妞穿的
It's a fat girls' shoe!
不管你信不信
Believe it or not... Believe it or not though,
瑪麗璐實際上和瑪麗珍同款
the Mary Lou is actually the
瑪麗珍  背帶式平底女鞋
只不過是黑色皮質的
same as the Mary Jane, but it's black leather.
反擊  是誰扔的  是誰扔的
Fight back! Come on! Where you at? Where you at?
好了
All right!
掌聲送給史蒂夫·麥登和他超贊的瑪麗璐
Let's give it up for Steve Madden and his awesome Mary Lou!
舉起來  舉起來  自豪地舉起來
Hold that up. Hold that up. Hold that up proud!
掌聲獻上
Give him a round of applause!
發泄完了嗎
You guys got that out of your systems, huh?
下午過得怎么樣
You having a good afternoon or what?
我要花點時間  告訴你們
I wanna take a moment and tell you why Steve here is so
為什么說史蒂夫與眾不同
absolutely off the fucking wall.
因為他是個創作天才
It's because this man is a creative genius.
史蒂夫的能力和天賦
This ability, this gift that Steve has,
不是緊跟女鞋時尚潮流
it goes beyond just spotting the hottest shoe trends.
而是他  能引領潮流
Steve's power is that he creates trends.
懂嗎
You understand?
史蒂夫這樣的藝術家十年難遇
Artists like Steve come along once every decade.
就像喬治· 阿瑪尼  詹尼·范思哲
I'm talking Giorgio Armani, Gianni Versace,
可可·香奈兒
Coco Chanel,
伊夫圣羅蘭
Yves Saint Laurent.
史蒂夫  過來一下
Steve, come over here for a second.
你們可能沒有意識到
I don't think you all realize
史蒂夫·麥登
that Steve Madden
是女鞋界最炙手可熱的人物
is the hottest person in the women's shoe industry,
北美的每一家百貨商場
with orders going through the roof
他的訂單都多到滿天飛
at every department store in North America right now.
我們竟有幸邀請他來辦公室
We have him here in our office!
謝天謝地  他來了
We should thank our fucking lucky stars this man is here!
我們應該五體投地
We should be on our hands and knees right now,
給他跪舔
getting ready to suck this guy off!
像這樣  知道嗎
Like this! Okay?
我要跪舔你的雞雞  史蒂夫
I wanna suck you off, Steve!
大家都想給你跪舔
Everyone's gonna suck you off!
這就是我們進入
This is our golden ticket
巧克力工廠的金獎券
to the fucking chocolate factory right here!
我要的是
And I wanna meet
威利·旺卡那樣的魔法人物
Willy fucking Wonka, okay?
要像奧柏倫柏人那樣瘋狂一次
I wanna be with the fucking Oompa Loompas like this!
好了  下去吧  下去
All right, get off this fucking stage! Get out of here.
大家都聽好了
All right, I want all of you to focus for a second.
看到那些小黑盒子了嗎
See those little black boxes?
那叫電話
They're called telephones.
告訴你們一個關于電話的小秘密
I'm gonna let you in on a little secret about these telephones.
它們不會自己撥號  知道嗎
They're not gonna dial themselves. Okay?
沒有你們  它們只是快沒用的塑料
Without you, they're just worthless hunks of plastic.
就像上膛的M16
Like a loaded M16
卻沒有扣動扳機的士兵
without a trained Marine to pull the trigger.
而這些電話存在的意義
And in the case of the telephone,
就取決于在座的各位
it's up to each and every one of you,
我訓練有素的斯特拉頓人
my highly-trained Strattonites.
我的殺手們
My killers!
殺手們  不能接受否定的答案
My killers, who will not take no for an answer!
我的戰士們
My fucking warriors,
決不輕易掛斷電話
who will not hang up the phone
直到客戶被拿下
until their client either buys
或者他媽死球
or fucking dies!
讓我來告訴你們一件事
Let me tell you something.
沒錢是裝不了貴公子的
There is no nobility in poverty.
我可能成為一個富人
I have been a rich man
也可能成為一個窮人
and I have been a poor man.
我每次都他媽選擇當富人
And I choose rich every fucking time.
因為作為一個富人
Because at least as a rich man,
當我要面對什么問題時
when I have to face my problems,
我起碼可以坐在加長豪車后座出場
I show up in the back of a limo,
穿著一身兩千美元的西服
wearing a $2,000 suit
帶著四萬美元他媽一塊的金表
and a $40,000 gold fucking watch!
打一架  揍他
Duke it out! Hit him!
從我身上他媽滾下來
Get the fuck off me!
假如這兒有任何人覺得我膚淺或者物質
And if anyone here thinks I'm superficial or materialistic,
那你去他媽的麥當勞找份工作吧
go get a job at fucking McDonald's,
因為那里才是你他媽該去的地方
'cause that's where you fucking belong!
但在你離開這間滿是勝者的房間之前
But before you depart this room full of winners,
我希望你能好好看看你身邊的人  看吧
I want you to take a good look at the person next to you. Go on.
因為在不遠的將來
Because sometime in the not-so-distant future,
你會開著一輛破破爛爛的福特斑馬
you're gonna be pulling up to
在紅燈前停下
a red light in your beat-up old fucking Pinto,
而那個人會開著一輛嶄新的保時捷
and that person's gonna be pulling up right alongside you
停在你旁邊
in their brand new Porsche
身旁還坐著他們漂亮的
with their beautiful wife by their side,
有一對大奶子的妻子
who's got big voluptuous tits.
而你身邊會坐著誰呢
And who're you gonna be sitting next to?
某頭惡心的角馬  滿嘴唇毛
Some disgusting wildebeest with three days of razor-stubble,
穿著件無袖長袍
in a sleeveless muumuu,
擠進你身邊
crammed in next to you
帶著一滿車從他媽折扣批發超市買的雜物
in a carload full of groceries from the fucking Price Club!
那就是將來坐在你身邊的人
That's who you're gonna be sitting next to!
所以你們聽我說  而且聽仔細了
So you listen to me and you listen well.
你是不是還有信用卡賬單沒付清
Are you behind on your credit card bills?
很好  拿起你們的電話然后開始撥號吧
Good! Pick up the phone and start dialing!
你的房東是不是準備趕你出門了
Is your landlord ready to evict you?
很好  拿起你們的電話然后開始撥號吧
Good! Pick up the phone and start dialing!
你女朋友是否覺得你他媽就是個屌絲
Does your girlfriend think you're a fucking worthless loser?
很好  拿起你們的電話然后開始撥號吧
Good! Pick up the phone and start dialing!
我希望你們能賺夠錢去解決這些問題
I want you to deal with your problems by becoming rich!
你們今天唯一需要做的就是拿起那臺電話
All you have to do today is pick up that phone
然后說出我教你們說的話
and speak the words that I have taught you.
然后我就能讓你們變得
And I will make you richer
比美利堅他媽合眾國
than the most powerful
大部分有權有勢的CEO都富有
CEO in the United States of fucking America!
好
Yeah!
他媽的棒極了
Fuck, yeah!
我希望你們上場
I want you to go out there
然后把史蒂夫·麥登的股票
and I want you to ram
塞進你客戶的喉嚨
Steve Madden stock down your clients' throats
直到他們噎住為止
until they fucking choke on it!
直到他們噎死而且買了十萬股為止
Till they choke on it and they buy 100,000 shares!
那就是我想要的
That's what I want.
好  太他媽好了
Yeah! Fuck, yeah.
你們要夠兇殘
You be ferocious!
-你們要夠無情  -好
- You be relentless! - Yeah!
你們要當他媽的電話恐怖分子
You be telephone fucking terrorists!
現在  讓我們把這操蛋的東西踢出去吧
Now let's knock this motherfucker out of the park!
下午一點
At 1:00 p.m.,
我們以每股四塊五美元的價格開市
we opened the stock for sale at $4.50 a share.
到一點零三分  股價就超過了十八美元
By 1:03, it was over $18.
就連華爾街上的大投行也在買
Even the big Wall Street firms were buying.
出售的兩百萬股里面
Of the two million shares offered for sale,
有一百萬是從我的老鼠倉帳戶流出來的
a million belonged to me, held in phony accounts by my ratholes.
一旦價格到了高位
Now once the price hit the high teens...
你知道的  誰他媽在乎別的
You know what? Who gives a shit?
重點向來都是這個
As always, the point is this.
三小時就他媽兩千兩百萬了
$22 million in three fucking hours!
你能相信嗎
Can you believe this shit?
我他媽愛死這個了  寶貝兒
I fucking love this, baby!
這簡直太棒了
It's amazing!
喬丹
Jordan!
巴瑞·克萊門打電話找你
Barry Kleinman's on the phone
-未來影視的  -誰
- from Future Video. - Who?
我不知道  他給你婚禮攝過像
I don't know. He shot at your wedding.
他是有急事
He says it's urgent.
急事  巴瑞·克萊門是哪根蔥
Urgent? Who the fuck is Barry Kleinman?
天吶  你想嫁給我嗎
Oh, my God, you wanna marry me?
你愛上我了嗎
You're in love with me?
是啊是啊  去操你表妹吧
Yeah. Go fuck your cousin!
巴瑞  有事嗎
Hey, Barry, what's up?
聽著  我收到了一張傳票
Listen, I got this subpoena.
傳票  你他媽在說什么呢
Subpoena? What the fuck are you talking about?
是的  是聯邦調查局的人
Yeah, the FBI,
他們想要一份你婚禮錄像的拷貝
they want a copy of your wedding video.
他媽的聯邦調查局
The fucking FBI?
-你他媽逗我呢吧  -聽著
- You fucking kidding me? - Listen to me.
他叫德納姆
His name is Denham.
他是調查局紐約辦事處的一個探員
He's an agent with the New York office.
他想干什么
What's his problem?
他就像個童子軍
Gordon GekkoHe's a Boy Scout.
他覺得你他媽是戈登·蓋柯
He thinks you're fucking Gordon Gekko.
戈登·蓋柯  華爾街金融大鱷  后因內幕交易入獄
他想要我的婚禮錄像做什么
What does he want with my wedding video?
這是對我隱私的一種侵犯
It's like an invasion of my privacy.
你懂我在說什么嗎  這就像...
You know what I'm saying? It's like...
這很具有侵略性  你懂
It's intrusive, you know.
他有你整個核心集團的照片
He's got pictures of your whole inner fucking circle.
照片  以及那些人的名字
Pictures, names of the people.
你知道他想干什么嗎
You know what he's trying to do?
就是他正在干的事  看看你自己
Exactly what he's doing. Look at yourself.
他試圖把你嘮叨死
He's trying to rattle you,
他試圖把你老婆嘮叨死
he's trying to rattle your old lady,
然后她就會朝你叨叨個不停
so she nags you
直到你他媽出庭作證為止
until you become a fucking witness.
他想我自我檢舉揭發
He wants me to rat on myself?
他想我透露我自己的信息
He wants me to give information about my...
聽著  他媽的好消息是
Listen. The good fucking news is,
你知道我認識市里的每個人
you know I know everybody downtown,
我可以打電話給司法部  給緝毒局
I call up the Justice Department, the DEA,
甚至不會有人知道你他媽的存在
nobody even knows you fucking exist,
所以說放松點
so calm down!
他們不知道我的存在
They don't know I exist?
-不知道  -那很好
- No. - That's good.
但你...
But you...
你知道他是誰  是吧
You know who he is, right?
-沒錯  -所以假如我想要問點消息
- Yeah. - So, if I just wanted to get some more information,
就看看他知道了多少東西
just find out what he knows,
你能去他家吧  是嗎
you could go to his house, right?
竊聽一下他的電話  安點竊聽器
Tap his phones a little bit, bug him.
你能搞到點消息...
You could get some information...
你不能這樣搞這些人
You don't fuck with these guys like that.
你不能這樣搞他們
You don't fuck with them like that.
你怎么回事  是瘋了還是怎樣
What are you, nuts or something?
這就是你他媽要干的事情
This is what you fucking do.
不然我付錢給你是干什么的
What do I pay you for?
我是有他媽的偵探執照的  知道嗎
I have a fucking P.I. License, you know?
我是靠這個吃飯的
I make a living at this.
我不再是一名警察了
I'm not a cop anymore.
他們會他媽的把我的執照奪走  明白嗎
They'll take my fucking license away from me, all right?
好吧
Okay.
好吧  要是這樣不行  能不能...
Okay, if I can't do that, can I just...
我能給這家伙打個電話嗎
Can I give the guy a call?
-怎么了  這是  -喬丹  喬丹
- Why? Is that... - Jordan. Jordan.
行行好
Do me a favor?
唯一一個能給這家伙打電話的
The only one who calls this guy
就是你他媽的律師
is your fucking lawyer.
我不能打給他  是吧
I can't call him, right?
-這違反了規定嗎  -我告訴你
- It's against the rules? - I told you,
不管你他媽對他說了什么
whatever the fuck you say to him,
他都會用來對付你  你難道不明白嗎
he's gonna use against you. Don't you understand?
他很聰明  你很蠢
He's smart, you're dumb.
放他媽的屁
Fucking bullshit.
我們今晚是他媽的要好好談談
Are we fucking talking tonight,
還是你打算嗑到暈
or are you gonna get schwacked?
上次你嗑這些該死的藥時
The last time you took these fucking pills,
你把你的頭伸進了他媽的通心粉里
you put your head in the fucking macaroni.
得我去把你抬起來
I had to pick it up.
好吧
All right.
好吧  我不會打給他的
Okay, I won't call him.
伙計們  上船來  踏板就在那邊
Hey, fellas! Come on board. The plank's right around there.
歡迎
Welcome!
真是美好的一天啊
What a nice day.
你好
Hey.
歡迎登船
Welcome aboard.
我是喬丹  歡迎登上內奧米號
Jordan. Welcome aboard the Naomi.
很高興見到你
Pleasure to meet you.
德納姆探員  這位是休斯探員
Agent Denham. This is Agent Hughes.
你好啊
Hi, how are you?
讓我來給你們介紹一下  這位是尼克爾
Let me introduce you. This is Nicole,
這位是海蒂  來吧  別害羞
Heidi. Come on. Don't be shy.
你倆害羞個什么勁啊  別怕
What are you guys all shy for? Don't be scared.
她們是斯特拉頓的朋友
These are friends of Stratton.
-很高興見到你們  -你好
- It's a pleasure. - Hello.
你信息上說你想單獨談談
Your message said that you wanted to speak privately.
沒錯  我是想單獨談談
Right. I do want to speak privately.
給我們點時間唄  女士們
Give us a minute, huh, ladies?
要我幫你們拿什么東西盡管開口
Let me know if I can get you anything.
我們很樂意幫忙的
We'd be happy to help.
你們餓不餓
You guys hungry?
想吃點什么嗎
Want something to eat?
這兒有意面  對蝦  龍蝦
Got some pasta, shrimp, lobster.
我還有威士忌
I got whiskey.
你們想喝什么酒我這兒都有
Any kind of booze you want.
局里不允許我們"出海"的時候喝酒
You know what? The Bureau doesn't allow us to drink while we're at sea.
哈  當然啦
Duh! Of course.
你以前來過這種地方嗎
Ever been on one of these before?
你指船上嗎
A boat?
我六歲就學會開船了
I learned how to sail when I was six.
你沒開玩笑吧  是嗎  真的嗎
No shit. Is that right? Really?
我的意思是像這樣的
I mean on one like this, though?
我的意思是我把前面整個加長
I mean I had the whole front extended
專門用來停直升機
in order to fit the chopper up there.
看見那個了嗎
See that?
不管怎樣  這是給你的
Anyway, this is for you.
這是參加我婚禮的人的完整名單
It's a complete list of every person that was at my wedding.
我理解你想要整個婚禮錄像
I understand you wanted the whole wedding video.
我猜這個能幫你加快進程  對吧
Figured this would help expedite the whole process, right?
-確實如此  -聽著  我的重點是
- There you go. - Look, my point is that
我知道你在調查斯特拉頓
I know you're investigating Stratton.
但我想我一輩子也想不通是為什么
But for the life of me, I can't figure out why.
我知道我們是有點不正統
I know we're a little unorthodox,
我們做事有點大張旗鼓
we're a little loud in the way we do things.
但是你得理解
But you gotta understand,
我們是新入行的  你懂
we're the new guys on the block, you know,
我們在努力讓自己名揚萬里
we're trying to make a name for ourselves.
但我希望你明白  我們不做違法的事
But I want you to understand, we don't do anything illegal.
無論如何也不做
Whatsoever.
你可以去找證監會的人
I mean, you could talk to the SEC.
他們過去六個月來我辦公室拜訪了十五次
They were at my office 15 times over the last six months.
我是說  我沒...我沒什么要隱瞞的
I mean, I got... I got nothing to hide.
你知道證監會只是個民事管理機構
Well, you know the SEC is a civil regulatory agency.
而我們查的是犯罪活動
We pursue criminal activities.
正是這樣  你要查的是真正的犯罪
Exactly! You go after real criminals,
這讓我很好奇你們為什么會調查我
which makes me wonder what the hell you're investigating me for?
我是說  說實話...
I mean, honestly...
你覺得我們做過什么或者在做什么嗎
what is it that you think that we did or do?
我不明白
I don't get it.
我...
Well, I...
喬丹  我不能討論正在進行的調查
Look, Jordan, I can't discuss an ongoing investigation.
沒事  我明白  沒事的  我理解
No, I get that. No, I understand.
雖然這么說
With that said...
其實這案子是被扔在我桌上的
this case got dumped on my desk...
-是這樣嗎  -你懂的  高層
- Did it? - You know, by a higher-up
那些想要作秀的人
who needs to make a show
得借著追查一家新公司為由
of looking into the new company on the block,
-拉上一堆媒體之類的  -新上位那些
- with all the press and everything. - New loud guys.
然后我就變成了來做調查的蠢貨
And then I end up being the schmuck who does the looking.
就是這樣
Exactly.
只是  你懂的...這東西很煩
It's just, you know... it bothers me.
我們是新人
We're the new guy.
我們是去敲華爾街的門的人
We're the one that's banging on Wall Street's door.
我的意思是  你應該...
I mean, you should...
你應該去查查那些大投行在干什么
You should see what's going on at the bigger firms.
我說  我知道所有的內幕
I mean, I know all the information.
是真的  高盛  雷曼兄弟  美林
It's true! Goldman, Lehman Brothers, Merrill...
均為美國大投行
擔保債務憑證
Collateralized debt obligations?
還有什么互聯網概念股
This Internet stock bullshit?
簡直就是他媽的放屁
I mean, it's a fucking travesty.
我能手把手地告訴你
I could take you step-by-step
他們每一步都在做什么
through what exactly is occurring.
你只需要開口問
All you have to do is ask.
我隨時恭候
I'm available.
我就等你這句話了
That's exactly what I wanted to hear.
我不明白像這樣的談話
I don't see why a little sitdown like this
怎么就不能對我們雙方都有利了
can't be profitable for the both of us.
本來就應該這樣  是吧
It should. Right?
這本來就該對我們雙方都有利
It should profit the both of us.
-是應該這樣  -聽著
- It should. - Look.
我會給你我的私人號碼
I'm gonna give you my personal line.
工作日里隨時可以打電話給我
Five days a week, you just call me, feel free.
-我會的  -棒極了
- I'll do that. - Great.
你們確定不喝點什么
Are you sure you guys don't want something to drink?
你們不餓嗎  什么也不要
You're not hungry? Nothing?
-什么都不要嗎  不要嗎  -不用了
- Nothing? No? - Oh, no.
讓我問你幾個問題
Let me ask you,
假如你不想透露太多個人信息
and if you don't wanna get too personal,
你可以隨時叫我閉嘴
just tell me to shut up at any time.
你是不是曾經考慮過弄個經紀人執照
Did you try to get your broker's license at one time?
我不知道自己有沒有聽錯
Did I hear that right?
你是不是也曾想來華爾街分一杯羹
Were you trying to take a stab at Wall Street?
-沒有嗎  -你和誰談過話
- No? - Who you been talking to?
你他媽和誰談過了
Who the fuck you been talking to?
你在調查我  我也聽了你的事跡
Well, you're investigating me. I hear things.
你懂我意思吧
You know what I mean?
你有沒有想過假如你堅持下去了
You ever think about what would've happened
會發生什么
if you would have stayed the course?
你知道嗎  每當我搭地鐵回家
You know what? When I'm riding home on the subway
蛋蛋都他媽汗濕了
and my balls are fucking sweating,
一套西服連續穿了三天...
I'm wearing the same suit three days in a row...
沒錯  我當然想過
Yeah, you bet I do.
我以前就想過這個  誰不想呢  是吧
I've thought about it before. Who wouldn't, right?
沒錯  誰他媽會不想呢
Right, who fucking wouldn't?
你是怎么...
What do you get...
又是一個私人為題  你不用回答
Another personal question, no need to answer...
沒事  沒關系的  喬丹
No, that's all right, Jordan.
你能賺多少啊  五六萬之類的
What do you pull in? 50, 60K? Something like that?
一年嗎  大約
A year? In the ballpark?
我...
Well, I...
這樣說吧
Let's put it this way.
局里至少能給你一把免費的槍
You get a free handgun when you sign up for the Bureau.
這他媽讓我很生氣啊  你懂我意思嗎
No, but it fucking pisses me off. You know what I mean?
你想想  那些建設了這個國家的人
You think about the people that built this country,
像你一樣勤勤懇懇的人
hardworking people like you.
消防員  老師  聯邦探員
Firefighters, teachers, FBI agents.
結果到最后
End of the day,
你們這群人在經濟上被生吞活剝了
you guys get fucking skinned alive financially.
這他媽讓我太生氣了
It fucking makes me angry.
如今  關于華爾街和這個市場
Now the one thing about Wall Street and this market is,
在我看來  我覺得
for me, I feel
能回饋社會是好事  你知道  有些
it's good to give back. You know, there's...
有些情況下我能
There are situations where I can
讓這些人處境好點  明白嗎
make those situations better for people. You know?
你懂我意思的
You know what I mean.
機遇
Opportunity
就是一切
is everything.
太對了
Exactly.
舉個例子  有這么個小孩  是吧
Take for example, I got this one kid, right?
去學校學環境科學之類的
Went to school for environmental science, something like that.
但卻被學生貸款困住了
He was bogged down by student loans.
然后他媽又要做三重心臟搭橋手術
Turns out, his mother needed triple bypass surgery.
-天吶  -沒錯  很慘
- Jesus. - Right. Horrible situation.
是啊
Sure.
但是我們在正確的時候
But we got him into the market
拉他入市  再選一只正確的股票
at the right time and chose the right stock.
我們給予他正確的指導
We gave him the right guidance.
轟  一夜之間  就改變了他整個人生
Boom! Overnight, changed his entire life.
他媽被送進了紐約最好的醫院
Got to put his mother into the best hospital in New York City.
但還是沒用
It didn't work out for her,
假設  她還是去世了  很不幸
granted, she passed away, unfortunately.
但我們至少給了他那個機會
But we gave him that opportunity.
你懂我在說什么嗎
You know what I'm saying?
這取決于建立一個好團隊
It's just about setting up the right team,
然后一夜之間你的人生將得以改變
and then overnight your life can change.
一個實習生能...能...
What does... What does an intern...
一個實習生做這樣一單能賺多少
What does an intern make in a deal like that?
在那種情況下
Well, in that situation,
在那筆特定的交易里  就那一筆
in that particular trade, and it was one trade,
五十多萬美元吧
north of half a million dollars.
而且我會為任何人做這件事  明白嗎
And I'd do that for anybody, you know,
任何需要適當的指導的人
anybody that needs the proper guidance.
能再說一遍嗎  就把剛剛說的再說一遍
Can you say that again, just the way you said it?
一模一樣的
Just the same way.
我不懂你在說什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
算了吧  你當然懂我在說什么
Oh, come on! You know what I'm talking about.
我覺得剛剛喬丹在干的事是...
I think what Jordan just did is he...
-假如我沒弄錯的話...  -不是
- If I'm not mistaken... - No.
你剛剛在試圖賄賂一個聯邦官員
...you just tried to bribe a federal officer.
沒有  理論上我沒有賄賂任何人
No, technically I didn't bribe anybody.
不不  我聽到的可不是這樣的  喬丹
No, no, that's not the conversation I heard, Jordan.
不不  根據美國刑法
No, no, according to the U.S. criminal code,
賄賂必須有個
there needs to be an exact
確切的金額
dollar figure for the exchange of services.
那個在法庭上站不住腳的
That would not hold up in a court of law.
不不  我聽見的可不是這么回事
Nah, it's not how I heard it.
不不不  事實就是如此
No, no, no, that's the truth.
但我想告訴你這個
But I want to tell you this.
你說
Yeah.
那個告訴我你曾經試過
The same gentleman that told me
考經紀人執照的人
that you tried to get your broker's license
也和我說過你是個規矩正直的人
also told me that you are a straight arrow.
他把我仔細調查了一番
He ran a security check on me.
這個嘛...
Well...
沒錯  假如你駕著一艘
Yeah, when you sail on a boat
像是邦德電影里反派開的船
fit for a Bond villain,
那有時你就得扮扮"惡人"   是吧
sometimes you need to play the part. Right?
我覺得你倆是時候滾下我的船了
I think it's time you both get the fuck off my boat.
你說什么
What do you say?
你知道嗎  喬丹  我告訴你一件事
You know, Jordan, I'll tell you something.
大部分我逮捕的華爾街混蛋
Most of the Wall Street jackasses that I bust,
他們都是天生如此
they're to the manor born.
-是嗎  -沒錯
- Is that right? - Yeah.
他們老爹是混蛋
Their fathers are douchebags,
老爹的老爹也是
just like their fathers before them.
但你不一樣
But you...
喬丹  你全是自己打拼出來的
You, Jordan, you got this way all on your own.
是嗎
Did I?
-佩服佩服  小伙子  -小伙子
- Good for you, little man. - Little man?
真心佩服
Good for you.
你居然叫我小伙子
Me, the little man?
而且我跟你說
And let me tell you something.
我跟你說點別的
Let me tell you something else.
老實說  我沒跟你開玩笑啊
Honestly, I'm not bullshitting here,
這艘船可說是我登上過的
this is one of the nicest boats
-最好的船了  真心話  -我看也是
- that I've ever been on, I gotta tell you. - I bet it is.
你知道我還怎么想的嗎
And you know what I was just thinking, too?
如果哪天局里派人封了這艘船
The fucking hero that I'm gonna be back at the office
那我他媽肯定就是大英雄
when the Bureau seizes this fucking boat.
你他媽說是不是這樣  喬丹
Because, I mean, fuckety-fuck-fuck, Jordan,
瞧瞧這艘船
look at this thing!
多漂亮
It's beautiful!
而且你船上還有美妞兒  多好
And you got the beautiful girls there. It's wonderful.
挺好  快他媽給我滾
All right, get the fuck off my boat.
我想我們很快就會
I'm sure we'll be seeing each other
-再見面的  -我同意
- real soon. - I'm sure.
祝你們坐破地鐵
Good luck on that subway
回家干你們臭婆娘的路上一路順風
ride home to your miserable, ugly fucking wives.
我則要讓海蒂
I'm gonna have Heidi lick
就著魚子醬舔我的蛋
some caviar off my balls in the meantime.
你兩個想不想帶些龍蝦回家
Hey, you guys want to take some lobsters for your ride home?
一群混蛋  諒你們也吃不起
Fucking miserable pricks, I know you can't afford them!
一群賤貨
Fucking cheap fucks.
混蛋
Fucking miserable pricks.
兩位  看看我掏兜的時候找著了啥
Hey, fellas! Look what I found in my pocket! Look!
把你們一年的工資都掏出來了
A year's salary right here.
你知道我管這叫什么嗎  優惠券
You know what I call them? Fun coupons!
看見了嗎
See that!
我都嫌多的優惠券
They're fun coupons!
瑞士  瑞士有什么好逛的
Switzerland? What the fuck is in Switzerland?
當然是去逛瑞士銀行
Swiss fucking banks, that's what.
現在得遮遮丑  我必須得把錢藏起來
It was ass-covering time. I had to hide my money.
因特·魯格拉特
Enter Rugrat.
他是在法學院里認識這個瑞士銀行家的
He knew this Swiss banker from law school.
這是干歐洲娘們用的
That's for European pussy!
但他人在日內瓦
But he was in Geneva.
所以這趟長途飛機  我肯定要嗨著過去
And there was no way I was gonna make that flight sober.
我知道我只需適當的藥量
So I knew if I took my drugs right,
就能睡完整個旅程
I could sleep through the entire flight.
但必須要按時按量
But I had to take them just right.
下午四點整  我又吃了幾片
At 4:00 P.M., I popped a few more ludes,
這樣等我開完銷售會議
which started kicking in by the time
藥勁正好上來
I finished my sales meeting.
這是手腳刺癢階段
My tingle phase.
到晚餐時  我再吃幾片
By dinner, I popped a few more
就著幾杯雞尾酒和一兩片安定
on top of some cocktails and a Valium or two.
這是口齒不清階段
My slur phase.
到八點半  我再多吃幾片
By 8:30, I took a few more ludes
這時我差不多就走不動道了
and pretty much lost all my motor skills.
這是口水橫流階段
This was the drool phase.
到十點  我就完全不知道我是誰了
By 10:00, I didn't know who or what the fuck I was.
這是記憶喪失階段
The amnesia phase.
我們在午夜之前登機
We boarded the plane just before midnight.
媽呀  瞧瞧
Wow! Look at you!
-好個美人兒  -請別這樣  先生
- You're beautiful. - Excuse me, sir.
他安眠藥的藥勁上來了  他沒事的
His sleeping pills just kicked in. He's all right.
能出示一下登機牌嗎  先生
May I see your boarding passes, sir?
我們當然有登機牌
We have the boarding passes.
向老天發誓  我真想干她
Jesus Christ, I wanna fuck her.
干嘛呢  輕點
Hey! Fucking relax.
老天  快把你的爪子從我的老二上拿開
Oh, my God! You got your hand on my fucking cock!
別鬧了
Cut it out.
你看他還到處亂摸
He's got his hand on my dick again.
我這是給你系安全帶
I'm just trying to buckle you up.
你摸著他老二了嗎
You got your hand on his dick?
大庭廣眾的可控制著點啊
You gotta stop doing that in public places.
我的天  放手
Oh, my God. Take it off!
快放手
Take it off!
我聽說你頭發里有藏寶圖呢
I heard there's a treasure map under here.
住手
Stop!
-抱歉  先生  -我知道  女士
- Excuse me, sir. - I know, miss.
請您坐下
Please sit down.
-管好他  -請做回您的座位去
- Watch it. - Go back to your seat, please.
-你不高興個什么勁啊  -請您坐回去
- What are you upset about? - Please go back to your seat.
否則我要通知機長了
I will have to call the captain.
先生  請您坐回去
Please, sir, please, sir. Sit down.
坐回去
Please sit down!
-我這就去  別說了  -抱歉
- I'm going! Stop. - Okay, sorry.
我們抱歉  我們這就睡覺去
We apologize. We're gonna go to sleep.
提問  我要求提問
Question. I wanna ask you a question.
系好您的安全帶  先生
Fasten your seat belt, sir.
您不系好安全帶我們就
We cannot take off if you haven't fastened
-沒法起飛  -我真想爽一發啊
- your seat belt. - I'm really horny, too.
坐好  系上安全帶
Sit down. Fasten it.
-那好  我這就坐  -我來給您系
- Right. Okay, I'll sit down... - I will do it for you.
-說啥  -我幫您系
- What? - I'll do it for you.
說人話啊  姑娘
You gotta speak English.
您這異域風情的口音我們聽不懂
We don't understand this language you're speaking.
我要幫他系上安全帶
I will help him with his seat belt.
-你得讓他坐正  -坐好  坐好先生
- You gotta put it on right. - Sit back. Sit back, sir.
-這就對了  -我只要倚著就行啦
- There you go. - All right. I'll just lean back...
快來幫忙
Bitte, Hilfe!
-來幫忙  -來幫忙喲
- Hilfe! - Hilfe!
可惡
Jesus Christ!
該死
Fuck!
唐尼
Donnie...
唐尼  這不好玩  快給我解開
Donnie, this isn't funny. You gotta untie me, buddy.
不行啊
I can't untie you.
機長綁的你  再不然他就要用電棍了
The captain tied you up. He almost fucking tasered you.
為什么
Why?
不怪你  親愛的  別怪你自己
it's not you, sweetheart, don't beat yourself up.
別緊張  他沒事  他只是怕坐飛機
Easy, easy. He's fine. He's just a nervous flyer.
你沖別人大喊大叫
You were screaming at people.
不是吧
Oh, fuck off.
你在地板上滿地打滾
You were on the floor rolling around and shit.
我的天
Oh, Jesus.
你管機長叫什么奴
You called the captain the N-word.
我這么叫他了嗎
I called the captain the N-word?
-他非常不高興  -是嗎
- Yeah, he was very upset. - Really?
-還好我們在頭等艙  -我的天
- Luckily we're in first class. - Jesus.
我說你是不是嗑藥上癮了
Jesus Christ, I think you have a fucking drug problem.
藥在哪  到底在哪
Where are the ludes? Where are the ludes?
我藏得好好的  別緊張
They're up my ass. Don't worry about it.
-都弄好了  -那就好
- I got it. - Okay.
那就好
Thank God.
我的天  等我們
Jesus Christ, what are we
到了瑞士可怎么辦啊  哥們
gonna do when we get to Switzerland, buddy?
大事不妙了
This is bad.
這破玩意兒綁這么緊  我喘不過氣來了
Fucking things are against my chest. I can't breathe.
幫幫忙  撫慰撫慰我  求你了
Come on, do something to calm me down. Please.
好好  你先閉嘴  先閉嘴
Okay, shut the fuck up. Shut the fuck up.
好吧
Okay.
-真舒服  -睡吧睡吧
- That's good. - Go to sleep.
使點勁  哥們
Rub it harder, buddy.
你是好寶貝
You're all right.
我們都愛你  閉上嘴
We all love you. Shut the fuck up!
貝爾福先生  你可以走了
Mr. Belfort, you're free to go.
真的嗎
Really?
-跟你說  唐尼  -咋了
- Hey, Donnie. - Yeah?
等我們到了那邊  你注意點你自己
When we get out there, try not to act like yourself.
到了日內瓦就別混犯渾了  可以嗎
Okay? Let's make Geneva an asshole-free Donnie zone, all right?
你沖著我來干什么
What are you fucking coming at me for?
聽著  你現在坐在加長豪車而不是
Hey, listen. The only reason you're sitting in this limo
瑞士監獄里必須感謝我朋友  懂嗎
and not in a Swiss jail is because of my friend. Okay?
幫個忙
Hilfe!
-到了到了  -大家伙穩著點
- We're here. We're here. - Everyone calm down.
喬丹·貝爾福
Jordan Belfort!
您終于來了
At last.
我從尼古拉斯那聽到了您的許多壯舉
Nicholas has told me so much about you.
喬丹  這位是簡·雅克·索雷爾
Jordan, Jean Jacques Saurel.
-很高興認識您  -幸會幸會
- Pleasure to make your acquaintance. - Nice to meet you.
您說笑了
It's a joke.
你只要坐一坐就知道是什么感覺了
You'll understand when you're in the fucking seat.
你需要大點的沙發  待客用的
You need a bigger couch. For guests.
哈哈  哈哈  我還是沒懂  抱歉
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I don't understand. I'm sorry.
我對你們國家的銀行保密法很感興趣
I'm curious about your bank secrecy laws here.
等下  那個  抱歉喬丹
Wait. Yes. Excusez-moi, Jordan.
瑞士人待客總是得先來十分鐘
Swiss custom requires 10 minutes of...
這個那個的
Blah, blah, blah.
-閑聊  -對就是閑聊  多謝
- Chit chat. - Yeah, chit chat, thank you.
然后再談正事
...before business can be discussed.
是吧
Yeah.
那好
Of course.
那咱們就說正事  您想了解些什么
Let's get down to it. What would you like to know?
在什么情況下  你們有義務
Under what circumstances would you be obligated
和聯邦調查局
to cooperate with an FBI
或者美國司法部之類的部門合作
or a U.S. Justice Department investigation, for example?
看情況
Ca depend.
還得看情況
Ca depend?
沒錯
Oui.
具體看什么情況
Ca depend on what, exactly?
看美國人接下來幾個月會不會
Whether America plans to invade Switzerland
占領瑞士
in the coming months.
要不要我去看看十字架上有沒有跑坦克
Shall I check if tanks are rolling down the Rue de la Croy?
-那是十字街  -對對  十字街
- Yes. Rue de la Croix. - Croix. Croix.
是街不是架  還"十字架"  是街啦
Not Croy. Not Rue de la Croy. It's Croix.
我們在法學院常玩這個來著  不信你看
See, this is what he used to do back in law school. Check me.
-是香檳還是香崩  -沒錯
- Champagne. Champagne. - Yeah.
沒錯  還有炸薯條和炸洋芋
Yeah, yeah. French fries, pommes frites.
-總之這類的  -逗出鳥來了
- And that kind of stuff. - That's funny.
我問的是  你這瑞士廢柴
What I'm asking, you Swiss dick,
你會不會事后坑我
is are you going to fuck me over?
我當然聽明白了  你個美國白癡
I understand perfectly, you American shit.
外國司法部門能夠獲得
The only way the Banque Real de Geneve
日內瓦銀行合作的唯一情況
would cooperate with a foreign legal body
就是他們指控的罪名在瑞士也同樣違法
is if the crime being pursued is also a crime in Switzerland.
但只有很少的瑞士法律涉及您從事的業務
But there are very few Swiss laws which apply to your practices.
從金融角度講
From a financial standpoint,
您現在身處天堂了
you are now in heaven.
我就說他很厲害吧
See, I told you he was fantastic, right?
如果美國司法部
If the U.S. Justice
發傳票給我們  我們會只當它
Department sent us a subpoena, it would become
是廁紙
papier toilette.
擦屁股用的
We would wipe our ass with it.
當然  除非他們是要調查
Unless, of course, it was an investigation
股票詐騙
into stock fraud,
我沒記錯的話  這在你們瑞士也是犯罪
which is a crime here in Switzerland, if I'm correct.
這樣的話你們將有義務與他們合作
Then there would have to be cooperation on your part,
-如果我沒說錯的話  -當然
- if I'm not mistaken. - Yes.
當然會合作
Yes, we would.
如果賬戶是在你名下的話
Assuming the account is under your name.
但如果不是你的名字
If it were another name,
是你的朋友  令親之類的
a friend's, camarade...
表親嗎
Cousin?
表親  肯定也行
Cousin, absolute.
-你是說親戚  -沒錯
- Relative? - Yeah.
你剛才那是哼小調
Was that yodeling I just heard
還是我所理解的那個意思
or did you just say what I thought you said?
就是那個意思
Yes. Yes.
他這是在建議我建個老鼠倉
He's telling me to use a fucking rathole.
但一只美國老鼠絕對沒法
But a U.S. rathole would never get
把那么多錢弄到瑞士來
into Switzerland with all that money.
我還得找個有歐洲護照的老鼠
What I needed was a rathole with a European passport.
喬丹
Jordan.
你好啊  我最親愛的姨媽
Hey. How's my favorite aunt, huh?
歡迎  路上沒堵車吧
Welcome. Was the traffic terrible?
沒有  當然沒有
Oh, no, not at all.
喬丹  快進來
Jordan, come in.
還好說服艾瑪姨媽沒費多少勁
Thank God Aunt Emma didn't need too much convincing.
看來英國人跟瑞士人差別也沒那么大嘛
Turned out the British weren't too different from the Swiss.
只要錢跟上  一切就迎刃而解了
Money talks and bullshit takes the bus.
英式英語里"老鼠倉"怎么說
How do you say "Rathole" In British?
一旦你碰上任何麻煩
If you get into any trouble whatsoever,
我就會馬上站出來  承認是我騙了你
I'll come forth immediately. I'll say that I duped you.
我保證
That I promise.
冒險尤其能讓人倍感青春  是吧親愛的
Risk is what keeps us young, isn't it, darling?
有時我禁不住想
Sometimes I wonder
你是不是讓錢給拿住了  親愛的
if you let money get the best of you, my love.
以致忽視了其他種種
Among other substances.
這么明顯啊
It's that obvious, huh?
天氣一點都不熱  但你卻直冒汗
It's chilly, darling, and you're sweating bullets.
我該怎么說呢
What can I say? I'm...
我是個癮君子
I'm a drug addict.
癮頭非常大
I really am.
白粉  搖頭丸
Cocaine, pills,
這個那個  我都嗑
whatever it is, I'll fucking do it.
這是實情
Now that's the truth.
我是說
I mean...
我還有性癮
I'm a sex addict, too.
這世上肯定還有比性癮更危險的事
Well, there are worse things to be addicted to than sex.
天啊  我跟你說這些干什么  我干嘛
Jesus, why am I telling you all this? Why am I...
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
因為我是個很好說話的人
Because I'm very easy to talk to.
還真是  你的確很好說話
You are. You are easy to talk to.
在我看來
I suppose it's...
這是我的責任
Just my job, you know.
有這么多人依仗著我
All these people dependent on me.
事關數以千萬計的美金  你懂的
Tens of millions of dollars at stake, you know.
但有時我又覺得
Sometimes I feel like I...
我有點貪多嚼不爛了
I've bitten off more than I can chew, you know.
但你的胃口很大
You're a man with large appetites.
是啊
Yeah.
這姐們是在挑逗我嗎
Is she fucking hitting on me?
是啊
Yeah.
還真是這樣
Yeah, I am.
看來是我自作自受了哈
I suppose I put that on myself though, right?
我自己的決定
My decision.
有時候很難
It's just hard to...
很難控制內心的焦慮  你懂嗎
Hard to learn to control the anxiety sometimes, you know?
就是那個
You know, to...
試著放松  放下心事
learn to relax and let go and...
去釋放壓力嗎
to release the tension.
她還真在挑逗我
She is hitting on me.
我的天啊
Holy shit!
沒錯  釋放壓力
Yeah, to release the tension.
看來我們都得
I suppose we...
都得試著做到
We all just need to learn...
順其自然  對吧
learn to do what comes naturally in life, you know?
這哥們他媽是不是在挑逗我
Is he fucking hitting on me?
穩住  親愛的
Stability, dear.
我們是親戚
Family.
你照顧好我的侄女  親愛的
You take care of my niece, my love.
這邊放心交給我
I'll take care of everything over here.
成交
Deal.
爽  真他媽爽
Come on! There you go.
我們貨真價實地干了千金一炮
We had, literally, a fuckload of money.
艾瑪自己可運不了這么多錢
Aunt Emma could never carry all this by herself.
我就琢磨  還有誰有歐洲護照
So I thought to myself, who else has a European passport?
布拉德  你捆得太緊了
Brad, you're making this too fucking tight!
而布拉德作為一個成功的藥販子
Now Brad, as a successful drug dealer,
每年冬天都要在法國南部度假
spent his winters in the south of France,
在那里他遇見了他的妻子  仙黛爾
which is where he met his wife, Chantalle,
她本是斯洛文尼亞的脫衣舞女
a stripper of Slovenian origin
正好就出生在
born, in of all places,
瑞士
Switzerland.
這根本就成不了
Well, this is fucked.
成了才怪
No shit.
她怎么著得跑50趟吧
Like, this will take her like 50 trips.
我知道
I know.
不如這么著吧
Let me ask you something?
她不是還有家人嗎
What about her family? Right?
他們人人都有瑞士護照
I mean, they all got Swiss passports, right.
她有父母  有兄弟  是不是
She's got parents, she's got a brother, right?
他兄弟還有個老婆  這就是五個人了
The brother's got a wife. That's five fucking people.
頂多六七趟  是吧
Six, seven trips, boom, right?
他們跟她一樣都是瑞士的蠢貨
They're all fucking Swiss nitwits like her.
-他們會同意的  -沒準能行
- They'll do it. - We could do that.
至少我還有家人  你個大鼻子蠢貨
At least I have a family, you crooked-nose fuck!
別忘了我的錢
Hey, don't forget about my money.
抱歉你說啥
I'm sorry, what's that?
我忘了提了  他也有
Yeah, I forgot to tell you. He's got some...
-也有些錢要運  -我的錢
- He's got some money. - My money.
我一周之內要進個幾百萬的
I got a couple of mil coming in like a week.
錢進賬 我給你電話  你來取
When it gets in, I'll give you a call, you come pick it up.
你還給我打電話
You give me a call?
等錢來了
When it gets here,
我給你打電話  你來取
I'll give you a call and you'll come pick it up.
我們又不給你干活  老兄
Well, we don't fucking work for you, man!
親愛的  你奶子上貼的全是我們的錢
Sweetheart, you have my money taped to your tits.
明白嗎  說白了  你就是給我干活的
Okay? Technically, you do work for me.
喬丹  我得跟你談談
Hey, Jordan, we're gonna need to talk.
我他媽不干這個  我跟你明說了吧
If I fucking do this, I'm telling you right now,
我才不會去找他
I ain't going to him, okay.
-我又不是給他跑腿的  -我懂
- I'm not a fucking shvartze. - I got it.
我不干上門取件的事  明白嗎
I don't do fucking pickups, all right?
-我明白  -你聽好了
- I got it. - Well, listen to me.
我說在哪碰頭就在哪
We meet someplace that I fucking say.
然后你告訴那個死胖子
And you tell that fucking piece of shit,
-過時不候  -我會說的
- he comes correct. - I will.
他敢闖一丁點亂子  我發誓
He comes in all fucking loopy and fucked up, I swear to God
我把丫的牙打回牙床子里去
I'll mash that douchebag's teeth in.
你他媽要打誰的牙床子
You're gonna mash whose fucking teeth in?
咱倆玩玩看誰打誰的牙床子
Whose fucking teeth are you gonna mash in?
你那破桌子上堆的是我的錢  不是你的
I put the money on that fucking table! Not you!
要不是老子  你他媽能有今天
I'm the reason we have this whole fucking deal!
-他有槍  白癡  -操他媽的槍
- He's got a gun, you fucking idiot! - Fuck his gun!
那堆錢是我的
I put that money in there!
你他媽逼就是個藥販子
You know what? You're a fucking pill dealer.
像你這種人我一撈一大把
I got five more just like you, bro.
繼續說啊  你他媽的狗雜種
Keep talking, you fucking piece of shit!
你他媽逼穿得也像坨屎
You know what else? You dress like shit!
操死你丫的
So fuck you!
-王八操的  -老天
- Fucking motherfucker! - Oh! Jesus!
爽不爽  你個操屁眼的  看誰是基佬
How about that, faggot? Who's a faggot?
你還好吧  兄弟
You okay? Hey, pal.
第二天  艾瑪姑媽飛去了日內瓦
The next day, Aunt Emma flew to Geneva.
帶了兩百萬美元現金
Two million in cash in her carry-on,
對瑞士那邊來說可是九牛一毛
which in the big picture was a drop in the Swiss bucket.
因為在接下來的一個月里
'Cause the following month,
往返歐洲六趟
over the course of six round trips,
仙黛爾的親戚朋友
Chantalle's family and
毫無閃失地將兩千萬美元現金
friends smuggled in over 20 million in cash
偷運進了瑞士
without even a hiccup.
-這還有呢  -是嗎
- And I have some more. - Really?
-給你  -噢  謝謝
- Here. - Oh, thank you.
還有
And here.
-歡迎光臨  -歡迎光臨
- Welcome. - Welcome?
一共四大包
Yeah, like four bags of it.
斯洛伐克瑞士還是斯洛文尼亞瑞士
Are you Swiss-Slovakian or Swiss-Slovenian?
-斯洛文尼亞  -斯洛文尼亞
- Slovenian. - Slovenian?
管它呢  反正你是金發美女
Who cares. You're blonde.
討厭啦
Oh, stop.
我操
Shit.
你就不能把車停好嗎
Just put the fucking car in park,
你個傻逼
you dumb fucking idiot!
這個箱子怎么合不上
I can't close this briefcase.
有一天
One fucking day.
你能不能別嗑藥  哪怕一天
One fucking day, you couldn't keep it together?
我磕嗨了  布拉德
I'm fucked up, Brad.
-你他媽沒開玩笑吧  -真磕嗨了
- Gotta be fucking kidding me. - Fucked up.
-我開玩笑的  -什么
- It's a joke. - It's a joke?
-我好著呢  -我操
- I'm sober. - Jesus fucking Christ!
我他媽騙你呢
It's a fucking joke.
-你他媽傻啊  -我不傻
- Are you fucking stupid? - I'm not stupid.
你車開的歪七扭八的
You fucking drive in here like a fucking maniac,
引來多少注意你知道嗎
you know the attention that that fucking draws?
-我不傻  我很聰明  -聰明
- I'm not stupid. I'm smart. - Smart?
-我一單生意就幾百萬  -沒錯
- I make million-dollar deals. - That right.
還是和聰明的重要人物做的  不像你
With smart important people, unlike you.
他們不會因為怕了就動手打人  明白嗎
People who don't sucker-punch people when they're scared. Okay?
-你是說我怕了  -順便還有
- I'm scared, huh? - And by the way,
你還沒給我一個道歉呢
I haven't gotten an apology yet for that.
你想要我道歉  是吧
You want an apology, okay.
我每天下班后
I check my fucking messages every day
-都他媽要查下收件箱  -是嗎
- when I come home from work. - Did you?
-還有答錄機  都是空的  -沒有嗎
- My answering machine. Zero. - Didn't get one, huh?
我還設置了閃光提醒
I got a blinking light,
因為你屁都沒跟我吭一聲
because I don't have shit from you.
你這張欠扇的嘴
You know what, you got a big fucking mouth, okay?
我叫我老婆隨時候著
I got my wife checking the messages
每45分鐘給我辦公室打個電話  問我
every 45 minutes calling the office, saying,
"布拉德道歉了嗎"
"Has Brad apologized yet?"
"答錄機上有留言嗎"
"Is there an apology message on the machine?"
我又不是傻的  你知道嗎
I don't have jack shit. You know what?
你不能這樣對別人
That's not how you treat people.
你這張嘴太欠扇了
You got a big fucking mouth, you know.
我不和你計較了  趕緊把包給我
I'm gonna give you a fucking pass. Just give me the case.
你還不和我計較
You're gonna give me a pass?
少廢話了行嗎
Look, it's a figure of fucking speech.
我的天  操蛋村的村長
Oh, my gosh. The Emperor of Fucksville
從操蛋村下山來不和我計較了
came down from Fucksville to give me a pass!
操蛋村是吧
From Fucksville, huh?
那操蛋村的村長今天不在
Hey, what are the citizens of Fucksville doing today
操蛋村村民都干嘛呢
when their Emperor's gone?
在暴亂嗎
Is it mayhem?
到處打砸搶燒  強奸婦女嗎
Are people looting and raping?
你下山來了那些傻逼都干什么呢
What are all the little fuckheads doing while you're here?
操你媽的  把包給我
Go fuck yourself! Give me the bag.
你他媽站遠點
You back the fuck up.
你再過來
I'll cause the biggest
我都不知道我今天要干出什么
fucking scene that I've ever caused in my life
驚天動地的大事了
if you come at me again.
-你知道嗎  -你他媽小聲點
- You know what? - Just fucking keep it down.
我覺得
I got...
我不是故意要躲著你
I don't wanna be out of line or anything,
但我覺得你好像喜歡我
but I think you like, like me. Like you...
就像你剛靠近我時...
Like when you come at me...
你今天怎么了  你他媽...
What's the matter with you? What the fuck is...
...你的眼神  我發誓我真的看到了
...and you look at me. I swear I just noticed it.
你他媽好像...
You have like a fucking, like...
眨了下眼  你剛才眨了下眼
Like a twinkle. You have like a twinkle.
你是想親我嗎  老兄
Are you trying to kiss me, bro?
我了個操
Jesus fucking Christ.
-你怎么了  -我有點  我不知道
- What's with you? - I have a... I don't know.
-也不是我恐同  -好吧
- It's not a homophobic thing. - All right...
只是你不是我喜歡的那一型
You're just not the one for me, pal.
明白我意思嗎  我不是...
You know what I mean? It's not...
-我不是那種人  -我聽夠了
- It's not about that for me, you know. - I've heard enough.
當我求你  快點把箱子給我
Please, I'm begging, give me the fucking case.
-我把箱子給你  -快拿來吧
- I'm gonna give you the case. - Give me the case.
-你要幫我個忙  -什么忙
- You gotta do me one favor. - What's that?
你要拿著箱子  直接開車回家
You gotta take this case, you gotta drive straight home,
打開箱子
need you to open up the briefcase,
拿出每一張鈔票
and you take out every single dollar.
別留任何一張在箱子里
Don't leave one dollar inside the briefcase.
當你把錢全拿出箱子
And once you have it all
整齊擺好后
neatly organized outside the briefcase,
你把它拿起來塞進
I need you to take it and I need you to shove it right up
你老婆的拉脫維亞逼里面  明白了嗎
your wife's Latvian cunt, you understand?
-你他媽敢罵我老婆  -淡定  兄弟
- My fucking wife! - Chill! Chill, bro.
操你媽  你這個王八蛋
Fuck. You motherfucking piece of shit!
現在快去吧
How about now?
-快去  快去  -操
- Go, go! - Fuck!
龜孫子  你他媽死定了
Motherfuck! You're fucking dead!
站住  不許動  不許動
Stop! Don't move! Don't move!
快站住  否則我他媽打爆你的頭
Stop, or I will blow you the fuck away!
放下箱子  把手舉起來
Drop the case! Put your hands in the air!
跪下
Get down.
跪下  跪下
Get down on your knees! Get down on your knees!
我操你媽
Motherfucker!
喬丹  我有個驚喜給你
Jordan, do I have a surprise for you!
-什么驚喜  -20粒正宗檸檬片
- What's that? - Twenty real Lemmons.
我認識的一個退休藥劑師
Retired pharmacist's client of mine,
把它在保險箱放了15年了
they've been in the safe for 15 years.
你他媽逗我呢  檸檬片
Are you fucking kidding me? Lemmons?
這能把咱們的腦袋都爽翻天
They're gonna knock us on our fucking heads.
檸檬714就是安眠藥中的戰斗機
When it comes to Quaaludes, the Lemmon 714 was the Holy Grail.
-你敢相信嗎  -我的老天
- Can you believe it? - Oh, my God.
我以為這只是一個神話
I thought they were like a myth.
這藥比當今市面上的任何一種都要強三倍
Three times as powerful as anything available today.
看看這些寶貝
Look at these babies.
唐尼真是懂得怎么慶祝啊
Boy, Donnie really knew how to celebrate.
他說這個要留在特別時機再用
He said he was saving these for a special occasion.
比如過生日  擊掌慶祝時
Like a birthday, or being clap free,
亦或是咱的錢安全抵達瑞士
or our money arriving safely in Switzerland.
于是當晚
So that night,
我撇開所有計劃并清除我體內
I cleared my schedule and I rid my body
任何會影響我爽的東西
of anything that could fuck with my high.
這是歡慶時刻
It was celebration time.
來吧
Okay.
先來一顆  看看怎么樣
Start off with one, see how it goes?
我的藥頭說只能吃一顆
My guy says all we'll need is one.
給你
Here you go.
-干杯  -干杯
- Salud! - Cheers.
說不定我再拉一下就會下去了
Maybe if I pull it again, it'll go down.
史蒂夫  史蒂夫
Steve! Steve!
我要離開這兒
I gotta get out of here!
卡爾  我搞明白了
Carl, I think I got it figured out.
這個肯定是拉一下朝上拉兩下朝下
It must be one pull for up and two pulls for down.
好吧
Okay.
有感覺嗎
Do you feel anything?
沒有
No.
都35分鐘了
It's been 35 minutes.
可能我們磕了這么多年有耐藥性了
Maybe we've built up a tolerance after all these years, huh?
屁用沒有
This is bullshit!
我的新陳代謝飛速運轉  啥感覺也沒有
My metabolism's pumping. I can't feel shit!
時間太長了
They're old.
是不是過期了
You think they lost their potency, huh?
看下瓶子
Check the bottle!
81年1月
January '81.
早他媽過期了
They're fucking duds.
操
Fuck!
我們再...
Let's take...
我們再來兩顆
Let's take two more each.
-喬丹  -怎么了寶貝
- Jordan. - Yeah, baby.
你們倆傻逼干什么呢
What are you two retards doing?
我們在健身  親愛的
We're working out, honey.
波·迪特爾來電話了
Well, Bo Dietl's on the phone.
知道了
Okay.
-知道了  -嗯
- Okay? - Okay.
波  出什么事了
Hey, Bo, what's going on?
喬丹  仔細聽我說
Jordan, listen to me clearly.
我電話上不能和你說  我要和你談談
I cannot talk to you on this phone, I have to talk to you.
快出來  出什么事了
Get out of here. What's going on?
聽我說  快他媽離開你家  喬丹
Listen to me! Leave the fucking house, Jordan,
從公用電話上給我打
and then call me from a pay phone.
我他媽可沒開玩笑  喬丹
This is not a fucking joke, Jordan.
好好好
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
-操  -他說什么
- Shit. - What'd he say?
我也不知道出什么事了
I don't know what the fuck's going on.
-我出去一下  -沒事吧  喬丹
- I gotta go! - Is everything okay, Jordan?
離我家最近的公用電話
The closest pay phone I could get to
在布魯克維爾鄉村俱樂部
was at the Brookville Country Club.
這是一家上流社會大本營
It was a real WASP stronghold,
就在離我家一英里遠處
just a mile down the road from my house.
波  是我  出什么事了
Hey, Bo, what's up, it's me. What's going on?
我在公用電話了  什么事
I'm at a pay phone. What's going on?
仔細聽我說
Listen to me carefully.
你的朋友
Please. Your little friend there,
布拉德  你的小兄弟  進監獄了
Brad, your little buddy, he's in jail.
他為什么進了監獄
What the fuck's he in jail for?
-他干什么了  -我不知道
- What'd he do? - I don't know what he did.
我長島的朋友告訴我
My friends in Long Island told me
他在一家商場門口被抓了
he got picked up in some fucking shopping mall.
他被關進...
He got locked up by...
等等  你說在商場
Wait, wait. Did you... Did you say a shopping mall?
-對  -他和唐尼在一起
- Yeah. - He was with Donnie.
他本來要去幫忙送錢
He was supposed to deliver some money,
-被那死胖子搞砸了...  -聽我說
- then that fucking fat piece of shit... - Listen to me!
我他媽現在就要找他問問
I gotta go fucking talk to him right now!
聽我說  千萬別去  聽我的
Listen to me! Don't go! Listen to me.
德納姆  那個FBI探員
That guy Denham, that FBI agent guy,
有人告訴我他監聽了你的電話
somebody told me he's got your phones tapped.
還有你辦公室和你家的
Your office and your home.
再別他媽用這些電話了
Don't talk on the motherfucking phone!
好了  我操  知道了  知道了
Okay. Fuck! I got it. I got it. I got it.
喬丹
Jordan.
你沒有要賄賂這個FBI探員吧
You didn't try to bribe this fucking FBI agent, did you?
我沒有賄賂他
No, I didn't try to bribe an FBI agent.
我以為你是傻逼啊  沒有
You think I'm that fucking stupid? No.
你他媽說的什么鳥語  我聽不懂
What the fuck did you say? I can't understand you.
再說一遍
Say that again.
我說...
I said...
你他媽說的什么亂七八糟的
What the fuck are you saying?
我說...
I said...
你磕嗨了嗎
Are you fucking high?
喬丹  你他媽磕嗨了嗎
Jordan, are you fucking high?
喬丹  行行好  就呆那兒
Jordan, do me a favor, stay where you are.
不要開車了
Don't get behind the wheel of the car.
我叫羅科過去接你
I'm gonna send Rocco over to pick you up.
喬丹  喬丹
Jordan! Jordan!
放了15年
After 15 years in storage,
檸檬片產生了延遲效果
the Lemmons had developed a delayed fuse.
90分鐘后這些天殺的藥丸才生效
It took 90 minutes for these little fuckers to kick in.
可一旦生效
But once they did...
我直接跳過了刺痛狀態
I mean, I had skipped the tingle phase
進入了流口水狀態
and went straight to the drool phase.
告訴我你在哪  別他媽開...
Tell me where you are! Don't fucking drive...
這些小東西藥性太猛了
These little bastards were so strong,
我發掘了一種全新的感受
I discovered a whole new phase.
腦癱狀態
The cerebral palsy phase.
加油  站起來
Come on, stand up!
好吧  走路是沒戲了
Okay, walking's out.
想想  再想想  還有什么辦法
All right, think, think. What else is there?
有了  我可以爬  像斯凱拉那樣爬
Yes! I can crawl. I can crawl like Skylar!
操  小孩爬起來那么容易
Fuck! The kid makes it look so goddamn easy!
想  操他丫的  再想想
Think, you motherfucker, think!
有了
Yes!
想到了  想到了
I got it! I've got it!
我可以滾  我可以滾
I can roll! I can roll!
喬丹
Jordan.
老天  你人呢
Oh, Jesus. Where are you?
我在鄉村俱樂部
I'm at a country club!
在哪
What?
我在鄉村俱樂部
I'm at a country club!
我他媽聽不懂你說的什么
I don't know what the fuck you're saying.
你趕緊回家來
Look, you need to get home.
唐尼已經失控了  他在另外一條線上
Donnie is out of control! He's on the other line
和一瑞士男在打電話  我不認識
with some Swiss guy. I don't know...
什么
What?
別讓他打電話
Get him off the phone!
我聽不懂你說什么
I can't understand you!
不要
Get him
讓他
off
打電話
the phone!
我他媽聽不懂你說的什么  喬丹
I don't know what the fuck you're saying, Jordan.
你能回來嗎  快點
Can you just get home? Hurry!
我離家還不到一英里
I was less than a mile from home.
我盡量慢慢開
I drove as slow as I fucking could.
連果凍滑得都比我快
I'd seen Jell-O move faster.
我本來要再給你兩百萬
I was gonna give you two million.
我要吃[遲]一些了
I's gonna be lates.
你吃了兩百萬
You ate two million?
遲
Later.
放下電話
Get off the phone.
放下那天殺的電話  傻逼
Get off the fucking phone! Idiot!
別擋路  蠢驢
Get out of the way, asshole!
你恨兩百萬
You hate two million?
你可不能恨兩百萬  唐尼
No, you don't hate two million, Donnie.
奇跡般地  我活著回到了家
By some miracle, I made it home alive,
我和車都沒有蹭到
not a scratch on me or the car.
喬丹
Jordan?
我了個大操
Jesus fucking Christ!
你吃什么了
What did you take?
你有毛病啊你
What's wrong with you?
喬
Jor!
爽歪歪了對吧
It's fucking good, right?
閉嘴
Fucked up!
放下電話
Get off the phone!
你搞什么  喬丹
What the fuck, Jordan?
你女兒在家呢
Your daughter's in the house!
你最好弄清楚
I hope you know that!
他媽的你女兒在家呢
Your fucking daughter's in the house!
太他媽好玩了  唐尼
Yeah, it's real fucking funny, Donnie.
放下電話
Get off the phone!
天啊  喬丹
Jesus Christ, Jordan.
有FBI
The FBI!
嘿
Hey!
我正打著呢
I'm on phone!
你媽逼快放下電話
Get off the fucking phone!
快過來...  給我
Come here! ...the phone.
來  我們上樓去
Come on. We're gonna go upstairs, all right.
我正打著呢
I'm on the phone!
正打著呢
On the phone!
我知道你干的好事
I know what you did,
你個王八操的
you piece of shit!
什么  什么
What? What?
布拉德
Brad!
你個吸雞巴的
You fucking cocksucker!
你都干了些什么好事
What did you do,
你個垃圾
you piece of shit?
操你媽
Fuck you!
我他媽宰了你
I wanna fucking kill you!
抓住你了
I got you!
這他媽怎么回事
What the fuck happened?
我操
Oh, shit!
喬丹  喬丹  你還好嗎
Jordan? Jordan, are you all right?
唐尼  唐尼
Donnie? Donnie?
唐尼
Donnie?
喬丹  他上不來氣了
Jordan, he's not breathing.
哦操  我不知道該怎么辦
Oh, fuck, I don't know what to do.
喬丹  我不知道該怎么辦
Jordan, I don't know what the fuck to do!
我幫不了他了  我的天  喬丹
I can't help him! Oh, my God. Jordan.
天吶  他嗆住了  喬丹  快來幫忙
Oh, my God, I think he's choking, Jordan. Do something.
-天啊  -寶貝  我來了
- Oh, God. - Baby, I got you!
他沒氣了  喬丹  你快來幫忙啊
He's not breathing, Jordan. You gotta do something!
操  天啊  我的天啊
Shit! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
我來了
I got you.
靠邊站
Step aside!
老天啊
Oh, God!
靠邊站  寶貝
Move aside, baby.
快點  快點
Come on! Come on!
來啊
Come on!
喬丹  他沒呼吸了  快想點辦法啊
Jordan, he's not breathing. You gotta do something.
喬丹  他還有家有孩子呢
Jordan, he's a father! He's got fucking kids!
-快想點辦法  -好
- Do something! - Yeah?
羅科  快過來
Rocco, you gotta get over here.
-來啊  -快叫救護車
- Come on. - Call an ambulance!
我他媽也不知道
I don't fucking know!
趕快過來報警
Just get over here! Call 911.
你還好吧  他沒事了
You all right? He's all right.
貝爾福先生
Mr. Belfort?
滾出去  滾
Get the fuck out of here. Fuck.
先生  我們需要問你幾個問題
Sir, we need to ask you some questions.
你他媽開玩笑吧  去你媽
Are you fucking kidding me? Fuck you.
來吧  站起來
Come on, get up.
滾出我的房子
Get the fuck out of my house.
-走吧  -我整晚都在這兒
- Let's go. - I've been here all night.
整晚都坐在這兒
I been sitting here all night.
你們他媽什么意思
What the fuck are you talking about?
-你們帶他去哪兒  -你們帶我去哪兒
- Where you taking him? - Where you taking me?
你們帶他去哪兒
Where you taking him?
你們又沒有搜查證
You ain't got no warrant.
怎么能隨便到別人家里來
Just come up in people's house like that!
你今晚開過你的車嗎  貝爾福先生
Did you drive your car tonight, Mr. Belfort?
怎么說呢
Well?
看來我并沒有安然無恙地到家
Maybe I hadn't made it home okay.
快他媽讓開
Get out of the fucking way!
我擦
Fuck!
你今晚開過這輛車嗎
Did you drive that car tonight?
-有  -好的
- Yeah. - Yeah, right.
我可是有家室的
I'm a family man!
有家室的  親愛的
Family man. Honey!
我沒把自己撞死
It was a miracle I wasn't killed,
或者撞死別人真是個奇跡
or that I didn't kill anybody else.
警察帶我去問了話  但他們沒法起訴我
The cops took me in for questioning, but they couldn't charge me.
他們沒法證明我開了車
They had no proof I was even behind the wheel.
與此同時
Meanwhile,
布拉德因為蔑視法庭坐了三個月牢
Brad did three months in jail for contempt,
因為他不肯供出唐尼
because he wouldn't rat Donnie out.
結果就是  我安然無恙
The result, I was scot-free.
但我也受到了前所未有的監視
But I had eyes on me like never before.
你真是走運  喬丹
You're a lucky man, Jordan.
居然能活著  還不用坐牢
You're lucky to be alive, let alone not in jail.
你知道我不相信運氣的  對吧
You know I don't believe in luck, right?
但是是時候了
But it's time.
拜托讓我跟證監會談好條件
Please, let me call the SEC and cut a deal
在你運氣用光以前
before your luck runs out.
跟爸爸揮揮手
Wave to Daddy.
嗨
Hey.
你好啊  甜心
Hey, sweetie.
都有什么條件  如果我...
What kind of terms would you be talking about if I...
這很難說
I don't know.
你得坦白一些違反證券規則
You plead guilty to a handful of securities violations,
操縱股價  高壓銷售
stock manipulation, high-pressure sales tactics.
都是這樣的小罪  你懂的
Ticky-tack shit like that, you know.
你得付幾百萬的罰款
You pay a couple million dollars in fines,
作為交換  證監會永遠不會再煩你
in exchange, the SEC fucks off till the end of time.
那斯特拉頓呢
And Stratton?
斯特拉頓會怎么樣
What happens to Stratton?
沒別的辦法...你必須收手  對吧
There's no way... I mean... You got to walk away. Right?
讓唐尼管事就行
Let Donnie be in charge.
沒錯  唐尼
Right. Donnie.
FBI可沒那么好對付
Now the FBI is another animal completely.
他們會繼續追查你的犯罪行為
They'll still be pursuing you for criminal wrongdoing.
不過  只要你自愿離職
However, with you stepping down voluntarily,
我猜你的好朋友德納姆探員
my guess is that your best friend Agent Denham
也就無計可施了
will be standing around with his dick in his hand.
喬丹
Jordan.
你還有什么好考慮的
What do you have to think about?
你打敗了他們
You beat them.
你贏了
You won!
你一輩子都不用工作了
God knows you never have to work again.
你還想怎么樣  在牢里度過余生嗎
What're you gonna do? Spend the rest of your life in jail?
-你想那樣嗎  -不想
- Is that what you want? - No.
-當然不想  -那不就得了
- Of course not. - Okay.
你已經掙了全世界的財富
Okay! You got all the money in the world.
難道還想把所有人的錢都掙光嗎
You need everybody else's money?
-當然不是  爸  -所以啊
- Of course not, Pops. - Well?
-可這是我一手創造的  -這我知道
- You know, I built it. - I know you built it.
你創造了這些  現在你得保住它們
You built it, so now preserve it.
你知道
You know,
五年前  當我和唐尼·亞速一起創立
five years ago, when I started Stratton Oakmont
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的時候  我就知道
with Donnie Azoff, I knew the day
總有一天我要離開這里
would eventually come where I'd have to be moving on.
現在我非常沉重地宣布...
And it's truly with a heavy heart that I'm here to say that...
那一天終于來了
That that day is finally here.
我想...我想謝謝你們所有人
I wanna... I want to thank you all for your...
謝謝你們多年的忠誠與敬仰
Your years of loyalty and admiration.
但重點是
But the point is this.
在唐尼的領導下
Under Donnie's leadership,
再加上尼基·克斯考夫和羅比·范伯格
along with Nicky Koskoff and Robbie Feinberg
加入領導層
moving into key management positions,
這里只會比原來更好
this place really, is gonna be better than ever!
我保證  好嗎
That I promise you. Okay?
為他們鼓掌吧  來吧
Give them a round of applause. Come on.
這里就是埃利斯島  各位
This is Ellis Island here, people.
我不管你是誰  從哪里來
I don't care who you are, where you're from,
不管你的祖先是坐他媽的五月花號
whether your relatives came over on the fucking Mayflower
還是從海蒂坐輪胎漂過來的
or on an inner tube from Haiti,
這里就是你的希望之地
this right here is the land of opportunity.
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特就是美利堅
Stratton Oakmont is America!
你們都認識幾米·貝爾澤吧
All of you know Kimmie Belzer, right?
是的
Yes, we do.
去你的
Fuck you.
別這樣  幾米
Come on, Kimmie.
你們可能不知道的是
What you probably didn't know is,
幾米是這里最早的經紀人之一
Kimmie was one of the first brokers here,
斯特拉頓最初的二十名員工之一
one of Stratton's original 20.
你們大部分人認識的幾米
Now most of you met Kimmie,
是現在這個美麗優雅的女性
the beautiful sophisticated woman that she is today.
穿著三千塊的阿瑪尼套裝
A woman that wears $3,000 Armani suits.
開著嶄新的奔馳
Who drives a brand-new Mercedes-Benz.
冬天在巴哈馬度假
A woman who spends her winters in the Bahamas,
夏天在漢普頓避暑
and summers in the Hamptons!
我遇到的幾米可不是這樣的
That's not the Kimmie that I met.
我遇到的幾米身無分文
The Kimmie that I met didn't have two nickels to rub together.
她是個窮困潦倒的單親母親
She was a single mom on the balls of her ass
有個八歲的兒子
with an eight-year-old son.
她已經欠了三個月的房租
Okay? She was three months behind on her rent.
她來我這兒找工作的時候
And when she came to me and asked me for a job,
只想要五千塊的預付工資
she asked for a $5,000 advance,
來付她兒子的學費
just so she could pay her son's tuition.
我是怎么做的  幾米
And what'd I do, Kimmie?
告訴他們
Go on, tell them.
你給我寫了一張
You wrote me a check
兩萬五千塊的支票
for $25,000.
沒錯
That's right.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你知道我為什么這么做嗎
And you know why that is?
因為我相信你
It's because I believed in you.
因為我相信你  幾米
It's because I believed in you, Kimmie,
就像我相信今天在場的每一位
just like I believe in each and every one of you here today.
-我他媽愛你  喬丹  -我他媽愛你
- I fucking love you, Jordan! - I fucking love you.
我他媽愛你  我愛你
I fucking love you! I love you.
我他媽也愛你 我他媽也愛你
I fucking love you, too! I fucking love you, too!
我愛你們所有人
And I love all of you!
我從心底愛你們所有人
And I love all of you from the bottom of my heart.
-我他媽也愛你  -真心的
- I fucking love you, too. - I mean that.
你最屌  你他媽最屌了
You are the shit. You are the fucking shit.
真是諷刺啊
It's a shame, you know.
這么多年來  我一直告訴你們
For years, I've been telling
不要接受別人的拒絕  對吧
you guys never to take no for an answer, right?
繼續努力  不要掛下電話
You know, to keep pushing, to never hang up the phone
知道你得到你想要的
until you get what you want.
因為那是你應得的
Because you all deserve it.
而我就要簽的那個混蛋協議
You know, this fucking deal that I'm about to sign,
禁止我參與證券行業
barring me from the securities industry,
禁止我進入斯特拉頓
barring me from Stratton,
我的家
my home.
這他媽算什么啊
What the fuck is that, you know?
我來告訴你它是什么  它是...
I'll tell you what it is. It's...
是我接受別人的拒絕
It's me taking no for an answer, you know.
是他們...
It's them...
他們說服了我  而不是反過來
It's them selling me, not the other way around.
是我變成了偽君子
It's me being a hypocrite is what it is.
所以...
So...
你猜怎么著
You know what?
我不走了
I'm not leaving.
我他媽不走了
I'm not fucking leaving!
你他媽升不了職啦
You're not getting a fucking promotion!
演出繼續
The show goes on!
這是我的家
This is my home!
他們得拆了這地方
They're gonna need a fucking wrecking ball
才能把我弄走
to take me out of here!
讓他們派國民警衛隊來吧
They're gonna need to send in the National Guard
或者他媽的特警隊
or fucking SWAT team,
因為我哪兒也不去
'cause I ain't going nowhere!
去他們的
Fuck them!
喬迪  喬迪
Jordy! Jordy!
喬迪  回來
Jordy! Get back here!
喂
Hey!
給我
Give me that.
這算什么
What is this?
叢林大狂歡嗎  上帝啊
Ramar of the Jungle, for Christ sake?
帕迪  你走運了  愛爾蘭小子
Paddy D, mazel tov, you Irishman.
喬丹·貝爾福撕毀了和證監會的協議
Jordan Belfort just welched on his deal with the SEC.
可以繼續追查他了  狩獵愉快
He is back in the ocean. Happy hunting.
我們開始了盛大的狂歡
It was our time to party big.
正好布拉德也出獄了
And just as Brad was released from jail, too.
我道歉  賠他入獄期間的損失
I apologized, even offered to pay him for his time in the can.
但他拒絕了  說他不干了
But he said no, that he was out.
他不想再跟我們有瓜葛
He didn't want any part of us.
可惜的是
Sad thing was,
兩年后他就死了
two years later he was dead.
死于心臟病  才35歲
Massive heart attack. Thirty-five.
和莫扎特去世的年齡一樣
Same age Mozart died.
他們倒也沒什么共同點  不過...
Not that they have a hell of a lot in common, but...
算了  我也不知道怎么會想到這些的
Anyway, I don't know why that came to mind.
沒過幾天  傳票就開始滿天飛
Within days, subpoenas started flying.
要求出示文件  做口供  應有盡有
Notices to produce documents, depositions, you name it.
唐尼都給弄得缺水了
Donnie couldn't drink water fast enough.
美國政府要給我們傳票
United States government wants to give me a subpoena?
咱們斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特就這么對付傳票
Here's what we do with subpoenas at Stratton Oakmont!
操你媽的美國  操你媽
Fuck you, USA! Fuck you!
操你媽  操你媽
Fuck you! Fuck you!
操你媽
Fuck you!
喬丹·貝爾福
Jordan Belfort.
奧爾登  這名字不錯
Alden. That's a nice name.
謝謝夸獎
Thank you very much for that.
-這算什么名字  -我的名字
- What kind of name is that? - That is my name.
我不記得
I do not recall that.
我不記得  好嗎
I do not recall that. Okay?
明先生  謝謝你能過來
Mr. Ming, thank you for coming in today.
這些點心你們還吃嗎
Are you gonna finish the rest of that Danish?
-我能吃點心嗎  -當然  吃吧
- Can I have that Danish? - No, no, go ahead.
他們審問了所有人
They interrogated everybody.
我血壓低  甲狀腺的問題
I got a low blood sugar, thyroid thing.
審問持續了幾個月
It went on for months.
簡直是在騷擾我們
It was a total fucking harassment.
讓他問問題吧
Tell him to proceed with the questions.
但沒有一個斯特拉頓人崩潰
But not a single Strattonite cracked.
格拉迪斯·卡雷拉呢
Gladys Carrera?
沒印象
Doesn't ring a bell.
抱歉  無可奉告
Sorry, I have no recommendation of that.
沒有
No.
沒想法
No idea.
我不記得那筆轉賬了  你們有牛奶嗎
I don't recall that transaction. You guys have any milk?
絕對沒有
Absolutely not.
你給佛朗西斯·索特吉打了很多通電話
Francis Sortigi you called so many times,
我覺得你應該記得
I just thought you might remember that.
你記得這些嗎
Would you remember any of those?
-我不記得  -這個阿杜卜勒...
- I do not recall any of that. - This Abdul...
我不...不  我不記得
I do not... No, I don't recall.
那通電話打了很久
It was a long phone call.
我想知道你還有沒有印象
I just wondered if you have any memory of that.
好了  我們已經
Okay. You know we've talked
跟這里的好幾名員工談過了
to several of the employees at this firm,
沒人記得史蒂夫·麥登首次公開募股的事
and nobody can recall anything about this Steve Madden IPO.
我覺得挺奇怪的
I think it's odd.
你記得運輸公司嗎
Do you recall Cartage Corporation?
你記得嗎
You do recall it?
不  我完全不記得
No, I don't recall that at all.
抱歉  我想問你的頭發是真的嗎
Excuse me. I have to ask. Is that your real hair?
你想談這個嗎
Are you gonna say anything about that?
要對我的頭發品頭論足嗎
Are you gonna comment on my hair?
我們是來談這些...談私人問題的嗎
Is that how we're doing... Is this personal questions?
我只是好奇你的發型
I'm just wondering why you would wear something like that.
抱歉  我不記得那家公司
Sorry. I don't recall that company.
還需要什么嗎  先生
Can I get you anything else, gentlemen?
親愛的  我有一種罕見的病
Yes. Sweetheart, I have a rare condition
必須每15分鐘喝一杯  拜托了
which requires me to drink one of those every 15 minutes, please.
我們被明確告知不能出國
We were specifically advised not to leave the country.
所以我們帶著老婆去了意大利
So, we took our wives to Italy.
我們覺得在海外辦公會更安全
We figured we were safer working from overseas
只要給魯格拉特下命令就好
giving orders to Rugrat.
沒人能逮捕我們  也沒人能證明
Nobody could arrest us and nobody could prove
我在游艇上操控著斯特拉頓
I was still running Stratton from a yacht.
嘿  魯格拉特
Hey, Rugrat.
你好啊
Bonjour.
你這禿頭鷹  還好嗎
You bald-headed eagle, how you doing?
唐尼  唐尼  聽著
Donnie, Donnie, listen!
我們有麻煩了
We have a problem, okay.
你的朋友史蒂夫·麥登正在拋售股份
Your friend, Steve Madden, is unloading shares.
你說什么呢  誰告訴你的
What are you saying? Who told you that?
-怎么了  -是真的  唐尼
- What's going on? - He's doing it, Donnie!
他說史蒂夫·麥登在拋售股份
He said that Steve Madden's unloading shares.
誰跟你說的  真是胡扯
Who told you that? It's bullshit!
快把電話給我
Give me that goddamn phone.
-怎么了  -別聽他的...
- What's going on? - Don't listen...
喬丹  聽著  我正盯著屏幕呢
Jordan, look. I'm watching the screen
有大量的史蒂夫·麥登股票被拋售
and huge chunks of Steve Madden are being sold, okay.
不是我們賣的  所以只能是史蒂夫
It's not coming from us, so it's gotta be Steve.
只有他有那么多股份
He's the only person with that many shares.
我是唐尼  打給我  好嗎
It's Donnie. Call me back, all right.
唐尼  你的小朋友想害我  你知道嗎
Donnie, your little friend is trying to fuck me, you know that.
你的小朋友想害死我
Your little friend is trying to fuck me right in the ass.
-現在就給他打電話  -我們還不確定
- Get him on the phone now! - We don't know anything yet.
別急著下結論
Let's not jump to conclusions.
盡管我掌握了百分之八十五的
Even though I owned 85%
史蒂夫·操蛋·混球·麥登鞋業的股份
of Steve-cocksucking- motherfucking-Madden Shoes,
但股權都是在他名下的
the shares were in his fucking name.
這混蛋知道調查局在找我麻煩
This motherfucker knew I was in trouble with the feds
想要趁火打劫
and was trying to take advantage.
說話啊  你準備怎么辦
Talk to me, man. How do you wanna play this?
我要你現在就打給所有的客戶
I want you to get all our clients on the phone right now,
讓他們開始賣史蒂夫·麥登的股票
and have them start selling Steve Madden.
我們得把他媽的股價降下來
We're gonna drive that fucking price down!
聽到了嗎  你他媽閉嘴
Do you hear me? Shut the fuck up!
他是你的高中同學
This is your fucking friend from high school.
要是那個小混球想弄我
If that little fucking prick thinks he can fuck with me,
我們就把他的公司弄成低價股  懂了嗎
we'll turn his company into a penny stock! You hear me?
-聽到了嗎  -聽到了
- You got it? - Yes. I got it!
在了解情況之前
Let's just not jump to
先別急著下結論
conclusions before we know what's going on.
泰德船長
Captain Ted!
把電話掛了  所有人
Hang up your phones! Everybody, hey!
掉頭  我們回家
Turn the boat around! We're going home!
寶貝  寶貝  怎么了
Baby! Baby, what happened?
我...
I just...
親愛的  出什么事了
Sweetheart, what's going on?
艾瑪姑姑
Aunt Emma...
等一下
Just wait.
我不行
I can't...
怎么了  你怎么哭了
What's going on? Why you crying?
-她死了  -誰  誰死了
- She's dead! - Who? Who's dead?
我剛接到貝蒂表姐的電話
I just got a call from my cousin Betty.
然后呢
Yeah?
艾瑪姑姑死了
Aunt Emma is dead.
-你他媽在開玩笑吧  -沒有
- Are you fucking kidding me? - No.
你認真的嗎
You're serious?
天啊  寶貝  這真是...
Oh, my God! Baby, that's...
我操
Oh, fuck!
親愛的  真是...
Oh, sweetheart, that's just...
去你妹的心臟病
Fucking heart attack!
砰  啪  嗝屁
Boom, snap, gone.
從此遠離塵世
Shuffled off her mortal coil.
我的兩千萬困在瑞士的銀行賬戶里了
And $20 million stuck in a Swiss bank account.
上次見到她  她還好好的呢
The last time I talked to her she was fine!
-她也沒那么老  -天啊  寶貝
- She's not that old. - Oh, God! Baby, oh, God!
太他媽糟糕了
That's so fucking terrible!
我操
Oh, fuck!
真是糟糕
It is terrible.
你姨媽是個端莊美麗的女人
Your aunt was such an elegant, attractive woman.
請接收我對你和你家人的慰問
My condolences to you and your family.
是啊  我們都崩潰了
Yes. We're absolutely devastated.
謝謝你的慰問
Thank you so much for your condolences.
那她的賬戶要怎么處理
Now where does that leave us in regard to her account exactly?
是要被審查還是怎樣
Does it go into probate or what?
這個你不需要擔心  喬丹
Not to worry, Jordan. Not to worry.
你姑姑在死之前
Your aunt, before she died,
簽了份文件  任命你為繼承人
signed a document naming you as her successor.
真的嗎
She did?
太好了  這是個好消息
Fantastic! Well, that's good news!
這個嘛  暫時還不是
Well, not as of yet.
什么叫做暫時還不是
What does that mean? Not as of yet?
我聽不清你說什么
I can't seem to hear you.
這里的信號太差了  你在說英文嗎
I must have bad reception. Are you speaking English?
-快  現在  快動身  -快
- Very... Now. Fast. Very fast. - Fast?
我要現在就動身去瑞士嗎
I have to get to Switzerland now?
說英語  給老子說英語
Speak English! Fucking speak English!
安靜點  讓我講完
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey. Hey! Quiet, okay?
帶上西裝  帶上小雞雞  給我滾過來
Take your suit, take your dick, okay, and move your ass! Please.
好的  我立刻過去
Okay. Move my ass! Yes!
我得說  這些瑞士人真夠狡猾
I gotta say, these Swiss were some sneaky motherfuckers.
就在幾分鐘內  他找到了一個
Within minutes, he had me set up with a forger
可以偽造艾瑪姑姑簽名的人
who could fake Aunt Emma's signature.
你個美國廢物
You American shit!
我必須明天前到那里  否則損失兩千萬
I just had to get there by tomorrow, or lose $20 million.
我們要去摩納哥
We're going to Monaco!
-摩納哥  現在嗎  -是的  寶貝
- Monaco? Now? - Yes, baby.
我們先去摩納哥  然后去瑞士
We're going to Monaco, so then we can go to Switzerland, okay?
-但是她的姑姑剛去世  -我知道
- But her aunt just died. - I realize that.
但我要去瑞士辦事
But I have business in Switzerland.
我必須現在就去瑞士
I need to go to Switzerland right now.
就這樣定了  抱歉
Bottom line. Sorry.
我們要趕去倫敦
We gotta get to London.
為什么  為什么
Why? Why?
要參加葬禮啊
The funeral!
寶貝  你聽我說
Yeah, but, babe. Look, look...
我是這世上最愛你姑姑的人
I loved your aunt more than anyone in the entire world.
我真的很愛她
I really did.
但她死了  寶貝
But she's dead now, sweetie.
她死了  哪都不能去
She's dead and she's not going anywhere.
等我們去到倫敦  她依然是死的
She'll still be dead by the time we get to London, okay?
泰德船長  聽好了
Captain Ted! Captain Ted, all right, look.
我們現在改去摩納哥  知道嗎
We're going to Monaco. Monaco now, okay?
摩納哥  好的
Monaco, right.
我們先去摩納哥  然后再轉去瑞士
We're going to Monaco so that we can drive to Switzerland
就能免去那些出入境手續了
so they don't stamp our passports.
辦完事后  我們再開回摩納哥
Take care of business here, we'll drive back to Monaco,
坐飛機到倫敦  參加葬禮
take a flight over to London to catch the funeral
三個辦事日后回到紐約
and be in New York in three fucking business days!
這就是計劃
That's the fucking plan.
我們可能會遇到海上風暴
I just want you to know that we might run into some chop.
小小的風暴  我們能搞定的吧
Chop? We can fucking handle chop, right?
我們的游艇足足有170英尺長
I mean, it's a 170-foot yacht.
不不不  我們哪兒也不去
No, no, no. We're not going
除非他說安全
anywhere unless he says it's safe, all right.
-別擔心風暴  -那很安全
- Don't worry about the chop. - It's safe.
你壓根就不懂什么是風暴
You don't know shit about chop.
就你懂  你什么時候成風暴專家了
Oh, really? And you do? You're a fucking expert on that.
要不我把你的信用卡額度減半  怎么樣
I'll chop your fucking credit card in half. How about that?
小小的風暴沒事的  相信我
Chop is fine. Trust me. Chop is fine.
不用擔心風暴  對吧泰德船長
Is chop fine, Captain Ted?
如果我們開慢點的話  就不用怕了
Yeah. I mean, if we take it slow.
對的  我們開慢點就好了
Yeah, we're gonna take it slow.
就是有點不舒適罷了  安全的
It's a little uncomfortable. Tell them it's safe.
還是安全的
It's gonna be safe.
我們把艙口封了  確保夾板安全
We'll batten down the hatches and secure the deck.
可能會打碎幾個碟子
And we're looking at a few... maybe a few broken dishes.
就打碎幾個碟子
Few broken dishes.
打碎幾個碟子是什么概念
What's a few broken dishes?
聽起來很安全嘛  不會有事的
Does that sound fucking awesome or what?
才不是
No. Not really.
我們一定會玩得很開心的
We're gonna have a fucking good time!
讓我們現在就出發去摩納哥
Let's go to fucking Monaco now!
趕緊動起來  起程吧
Let's fucking move! Let's go!
穩住
Hold on!
現在是什么情況
What the fuck is going on out here?
摩托艇翻倒在甲板上了
The Jet Skis just went overboard!
我的天啊  寶貝  你還好嗎
Oh, Jesus Christ! Honey, you okay?
大風警報  大風警報
Gale warning! Gale warning!
海浪已升至20英尺高  并持續上升
The waves are 20 feet high and building!
掉頭吧  我們走別的路線
Turn around, let's go the other fucking way.
-不行  -掉頭
- We can't! - Go!
現在掉頭的話  會翻船的
We'll get broad-sided. It'll tip over!
我是個潛水大師  你聽到嗎
I am a master diver. You hear that?
我是個潛水大師
I'm a master diver!
沒有人會死
No one's gonna fucking die!
有我在  寶貝  有我在  相信我
I got you, baby. I got you. Trust me, okay?
我愛你
I love you.
我愛你  寶貝  抓緊了
I love you, baby. Just hold on tight.
好的
Okay.
唐尼
Donnie!
堅持住  寶貝
Hold on, baby!
唐尼
Donnie!
-什么  -堅持住  寶貝
- What? - Hold on, baby.
把安眠酮拿來
Get the fucking ludes.
我不想死  喬丹
I don't wanna die, Jordan!
我干了那么多壞事
I did a lot of bad shit.
我要下地獄了  喬丹
I'm going to hell, Jordan!
我死定了  這次真的死定了
I fucked up! I fucked up so bad!
到樓下把安眠酮拿來
Get the ludes! Downstairs!
你說什么
What are you saying?
該死的
Fuck!
去把安眠酮拿來
Get the ludes!
我下不去  下面被淹了  喬丹
I can't go down there, Jordan. It's flooded.
下面的水有三尺深
It's three feet of water down there!
我不要清醒得死去
I will not die sober!
把那些該死的安眠酮拿來
Get those fucking ludes!
好的
Okay!
-快去  -好的
- Go! - Okay.
-他要去哪里  -抓緊  寶貝
- Where's he going? - Hold on, baby!
唐尼  他瘋了嗎
Donnie! Is he fucking crazy?
他只是去警告其他人
He's just warning everybody!
天啊
Jesus Christ!
抓穩了
Hold on!
離窗戶遠點
Get away from the window!
大浪要打過來了
Rogue wave!
求救
Mayday!
我是內奧米號的船長泰德·比切姆
This is Captain Ted Beecham aboard the yacht Naomi!
-我們要沉了  -我拿到了
- We are going down! - I got 'em!
我拿到了
I got 'em!
給我一顆  緩解下情緒
Give me one for the nerves!
我們要沉了
We're going down!
求救  求救
This is a fucking Mayday!
我們要求立即救援
We require immediate assistance!
抓緊了
Hold on!
小心
Watch out!
被意大利人救起來的好處就是
The nice thing about getting rescued by Italians
他們會喂飽你  給你喝紅酒
is that they feed you, make you drink red wine,
最后還會跟你跳舞
then you get to dance.
你看到了嗎
Did you see that?
那架飛機是我叫來接我們的
That was the plane I sent to come get us.
你一定想不到  一只海鷗撞上了機翼
I shit you not, it exploded when a seagull flew into the engine.
飛機在空中爆炸  死了三個人
Three people killed.
你希望上帝給你指引嗎
You want a sign from God?
這次之后  我終于得到了指引
Well, after all this, I finally got the message.
你夢想過財政獨立
Do you dream of becoming financially independent
卻每個月都有還不完的債嗎
but struggle every month just to pay your bills?
你想要擁有這樣一棟房子
Would you like to own a home like this,
卻只能勉強付得起房租嗎
but can barely afford to pay your rent?
我是喬丹·貝爾福
My name is Jordan Belfort,
創造財富  并沒有什么秘密
and there's no secret to wealth creation.
無論你是誰  來自哪里
No matter who you are, no matter where you came from,
都可以在幾個月內
you too can become financially independent
實現財政獨立
in just a matter of months.
你需要的是一套策略
All you need is a strategy.
在我24歲那年
When I was 24 years old,
我做了個決定  我不僅要生存還要發達
I made a decision not just to survive, but to thrive.
一開始  我沒想過這一切會成真
At first I didn't feel like deals like these were possible.
但我們現在有了房子  還掙了三萬三
But we have the house and we have a $33,000 profit.
我現在相信了
I certainly believe now.
好好想想
Think about it for a second.
如果你沒勇氣撥打喬丹·貝爾福熱線
If you don't have the guts to attend Jordan Belfort's
參加他們的研討會
Straight Line Persuasion System Seminar,
又怎么可能創造財富呢
then how do you expect to make any money?
如果你想成為百萬富翁
If you want to be a millionaire someday,
鼓起勇氣  做個決定吧
have some guts. Make a decision.
喬丹·貝爾福的方案很適合我
Jordan Belfort's setup worked for me
因為我很努力工作
because I worked hard for it.
如果對你不起作用  那就證明你太懶了
And if it doesn't work for you, it's because you're lazy.
你只配在麥當勞工作
And you should get a job at McDonald's.
沒有人能在財政獨立上拖你后腿
There's nobody holding you back from financial freedom.
也沒有人能阻止你掙大錢
And there's nobody stopping you from making millions.
坐在家里  無所事事
Don't just sit at home,
只會讓你想要的生活與你失之交臂
or the life of your dreams will sail right past you.
我改變了這些人的命運  也能改變你的
I changed all these people's lives and I can change yours, too!
來參加我的研討會吧
So come to my seminar!
你夢想中的生活
The life of your dreams is only...
好久不見  喬丹
Good to see you again, Jordan.
你被逮捕了
You're under arrest!
開什么玩笑
You gotta be joking!
你別開玩笑了
You're kidding me.
放開我
Hey, get the fuck away from me!
把攝像機關了
Turn that camera off.
我他媽在拍宣傳片呢
I'm fucking shooting a fucking infomercial here,
你們這群混球
you fucking cocksucker!
-去你的  你個混球  -關掉攝像機
- Fuck you, you motherfucker! - Shut the fucking camera off.
別碰我  聽到了嗎
You don't got shit on me, you hear me!
都給我滾
Go fuck yourself!
我掙的都是老實錢  你們這群混球
I'm making an honest living, you fucking piece of shit!
喬丹  讓我給你點法律建議
Hey, Jordan, let me give you a little legal advice.
給我閉嘴
Shut the fuck up!
去你的  你個混球
Oh, fuck you, you fucking prick!
我掙的都是老實錢  你們這群混球
I'm making an honest living, you motherfucker!
我改過自新  成了電視名人
I clean up my act. I did rehab. I'm a TV personality.
兩年滴酒不沾了  卻發生這事
I'm sober for two years. And this happens!
魯格拉特在邁阿密被逮捕了
Rugrat goes and gets busted down in Miami.
我是瑞士人  不是共和黨人
I'm Swiss, I'm not communist.
猜猜誰也被捕了  索雷爾
And guess who the fuck with? Saurel.
-你要揍我嗎  -不  先生
- You gonna beat me? - No, sir.
我了解你們國家  你們會揍我的
Yeah, I know your country. You're gonna beat me.
這是什么鬼幾率
I mean, what are the fucking odds?
日內瓦有上萬個瑞士銀行家
There had to be 10,000 Swiss bankers in Geneva,
魯格拉特就找了一個
and Rugrat gets the one dumb
讓自己在美國本土上被逮捕的笨蛋
enough to get himself arrested on U.S. Soil.
我知道
I know.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
更扯淡的是
Even more fucked was that
他被逮捕  跟我一點關系都沒有
he got busted for shit that had nothing to do with me.
跟我沒有半毛錢關系
It had nothing to fucking do with me.
說是一起通過海外龍舟賽
Something about laundering drug money
進行的販毒洗錢事件
through offshore boat racing
一個叫洛奇·青木的人
and a guy named Rocky Aoki,
紅花餐館創始人
you know, the founder of Benihana.
紅花餐館
Benihana.
紅你個頭啊
Beni-fucking-hana!
為什么
Why?
為什么啊  老天爺
Why, why, God?
你為什么那么殘忍
Why would you be so cruel
要我和一家鐵板燒連鎖餐廳
as to choose a chain of fucking hibachi restaurants
一起倒臺
to take me down?
長話短說  索雷爾把我供了出來
Long story short. Saurel rats me out.
但他首先供出了布拉德的老婆  仙黛爾
But not before he rats out Brad's wife, Chantalle,
結果發現
who, it turns out,
她每次去瑞士  都要跟他通奸
he'd been fucking every time she went to Switzerland!
-不不不  這不可能  -是的是的
- No, no, no, it's impossible. - Oui, oui, oui.
好吧
All right!
一起合謀證券欺詐罪
One count engaging in conspiracy to commit securities fraud.
兩起證券欺詐罪
Two counts securities fraud.
一起合謀洗錢罪
One count engaging in conspiracy to commit money laundering.
21起洗錢罪
Twenty-one counts money laundering.
一起妨礙司法罪
One count obstruction of justice.
保釋金是一千萬
Bail is set at $10 million.
唐尼叔叔來咯
Uncle Donnie's here!
洛奇  過得還好吧
Rocky. How you doing?
我恨死那只狗了
I hate that fucking dog.
是啊  老了  變得毫無節制
Yeah, he's getting old and decrepit.
又開始在家里隨地大小便了
Starting to shit in the house again.
-我也是  -抱一個  兄弟
- Me, too. - Come here, buddy.
-很高興見到你  兄弟  -我也是
- It's good to see you, pal. - Yeah, you, too.
很高興見到你  坐吧
Good to see you. Sit down. Oh, man.
過得怎樣  兄弟
How you doing, brother?
你懂的
You know.
糟透了  兄弟
Shitty, pal.
但還是能撐住的
But I'm hanging in there.
看看我的新腳鏈
My new piece of jewelry. Check that out.
不能踏出家里半步
Can't leave the house, you know?
都快得幽居病了
Starting to get cabin fever already.
該死的魯格拉特
Fucking Rugrat.
那帶假發的死基佬
That wig-wearing faggot.
就不該相信那混球  真想殺了他
I can't believe that fucking guy. I wanna kill him.
對天發誓  我真想掐死他
Swear to God, I want to choke him to death.
不負責任的賤貨
Irresponsible little prick.
我要告訴你一件事
I'll tell you one thing.
不管是誰的生日
I'm never eating at Benihana again.
我都不去紅花餐館吃飯了
I don't care whose birthday it is.
內奧米在哪  她還好吧
Where's Naomi? How's she doing?
在哪邊
That's her in the house there.
你跟她打招呼  估計她也不會理你
You could say hi, but she probably won't wave back.
親愛的內奧米
Naomi, sweetheart!
她怎么了
What's up her ass?
-她在生我的氣嗎  -不  你懂的
- Is she mad at me? - No, you know...
為了交保釋金
We probably have to mortgage the house
我們應該要把房子抵押了
in order to make bail.
或許還要賣些東西
Probably end up selling the
才能給律師們發工資
thing in order to pay for all the lawyers.
說實話  這真是一場噩夢  兄弟
It's been a nightmare, buddy, to tell you the truth.
要不然能怎么辦呢  對吧
What are you gonna do, right?
斯特拉頓才是重點  情況如何
Anyway, how's Stratton? That's more important.
士氣如何
How's morale?
現在要合法掙錢  他們都氣壞了吧
They all pissed off 'cause they have to make money legally now?
喬丹
Jordan.
我把創始人都找來了
I got the founding partners together.
跟他們說明了情況
I talked to them about everything.
有我在呢
And I got you.
有你在是什么意思
What do you mean, you got me?
房子和錢的事都別擔心  有我在
The house, money, don't worry about it. I got you.
-好了  -我愛你  兄弟
- All right. - I love you, buddy.
-我也會為你這樣做的  -我知道
- You know I'd do it for you, right? - I know.
-你知道的  對吧  -我知道
- You know that, right? - I know.
真想親遍你全身
I could fucking kiss you all over.
好了  夠了  夠了
All right, enough, enough.
想喝啤酒嗎  兄弟
You want a beer, pal?
你在喝什么
What are you drinking?
不含酒精的東西
I got this non-alcoholic shit.
那是什么
What's that?
不含酒精的啤酒
A non-alcoholic beer. It's got no alcohol.
-是啤酒嗎  -是的  不含酒精
- It's a beer? - Yeah, with no alcohol.
如果你喝多了
But if you drink enough,
如果你喝很多的話  還是會醉嗎
if you drink a lot, they get you fucked up?
不會的  不含酒精  這才是重點
No, there's no alcohol. That's the fucking point.
我不是科學家
I'm not a scientist.
不知道你在說什么
I don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
你想喝啤酒的話  我可以給你拿
I can get you a beer if you want a fucking beer.
我知道  但是我不喝酒了  記得嗎
I know, but I don't drink. You remember?
我已經戒酒了
I don't drink anymore.
你想進屋里吸點發酵粉嗎
Oh, you wanna go inside and blow some lines of baking powder?
或者是蘇打粉
Or baking soda.
無法想象再也不能嗑嗨的日子啊
Can't imagine ever not enjoying getting fucked up.
-是啊  -我愛死那些日子了
- Yeah. - I love it.
戒酒的日子怎樣
How's being sober?
-糟糕透了  -很無聊  對吧
- Fucking sucks. - Boring, right?
無聊到我想自殺了
So boring. I wanna kill myself.
有個詞  我們不太想用
There's a term, and we don't like to use it
除非在特殊情況下
unless circumstances dictate,
我認為這個案子夠特殊的了
and I think they do dictate in this case,
那個詞就是  格林納達
and the term is "Grenada."
你聽說過格林納達嗎
Have you ever heard of Grenada?
沒聽過
No. No, I haven't.
格林納達是個很有趣的小島國
Grenada's very interesting because it is a small island nation
1983年的時候被美國侵略
that was invaded by the United States of America in 1983.
大約有九萬人
It's about 90,000 people.
換句話說
And essentially, it means
這個案子我們不可能輸
this case is unloseable.
懂嗎
Okay?
也就是說
So, you know,
就算我們光著褲子走上法庭
we can come in, we can have our dick hanging out of our pants.
也沒有人會在乎
Nobody gives a fuck.
我贏定了
I'm gonna win.
而你呢
You, sir,
就是格林納達
are what's known as a Grenada.
你就等著判刑吧
You're looking at real prison time.
洗錢至少要吃20年牢飯
Money laundering can get you as much as 20 years.
如果不是抓到你往海外塞錢
And our case couldn't be stronger if we caught you
這案子也不會那么簡單
shoving cash in your mattress.
真的嗎
Is that right?
喬丹
Hey, Jordan. Jordan.
你要在牢里等死  直到孩子大學畢業
Your rotting away in jail till your kids get out of college,
那并不是我們的目的
that's not our ambition here.
還有其他人參與洗錢的勾當
There's other people involved in this, too.
我們認為他們也應該被送上法庭
We think they need to see their day in court as well.
我怎么覺得你們是要提條件呢
Why do I sense there's an offer in the air?
你看他多聰明  你是心靈感應大師嗎
Look at him. He's got a sense. What are you, Kreskin?
全面配合  也就是過去七年間
Full cooperation. He provides us with a comprehensive list
所有同謀的詳細名單提供給我們
of all the co-conspirators spanning the last seven years,
還要同意帶竊聽器
and he also agrees to wear a wire.
等會
Wait...
你剛才說讓我"帶竊聽器"嗎
did you just say "wear a wire"?
竊聽器
A wire.
什么意思
What does that mean?
你想讓我告密  是嗎
You want me to rat? Is that it?
不  我想讓你合作
No, I want you to cooperate.
不  你就是想讓我告密
No. You want me to rat, right?
沒錯  就是讓你告密
Yes. We want you to rat.
我們還就他媽的想讓你干這件事  告密
That's fucking exactly what we want you to do. To rat.
克里斯蒂的派對怎么樣
How was Cristy's party?
不錯
Fine.
那就好
Good.
寶貝  我今天又去見過律師了
Babe, I spoke to the lawyers again today.
我有非常非常好的消息要告訴你
I have some really, really great news.
看來這件事完全不會涉及到你  親愛的
Turns out you're completely off the hook, honey.
這我早就知道
I know that already.
沒錯  也是
Right. Exactly.
你本來也就沒做過什么錯事  對吧
You never did anything wrong in the first place, right?
鬧了半天  聯邦調查局
It turns out, all the FBI really
真正想讓我做的就是跟他們合作
wants from me is to cooperate.
你知道嗎
You know?
因為我手上掌握了很多
Turns out I have so much
關于股票市場和華爾街的內幕
information about the stock market and Wall Street,
我可以給政府省好幾年的心
I could save the government years of heartache,
更別提數以百萬的經濟損失了
not to mention countless dollars.
但是更好的還在后頭呢  寶貝
But it gets even better, babe.
如果我決定跟他們合作的話
Because if I do decide to cooperate,
我只能只需要蹲個短短四年就行了
I might only be looking at four short years,
這樣一來
in which case, you know,
我們可以重新來過  也許把房子賣了
we could start fresh, maybe sell the house.
我要交的任何罰款
And any fines that I'd have to pay
也是等到我刑滿出獄后才用交
wouldn't be due till after I serve my term,
所以我們還會剩下很多錢
so we'd still have plenty of money left over, you know?
當然了  唯一讓我有點不爽的就是
The only thing that of course bummed me out a little bit
他們想讓我
is this whole idea of
提供關于我朋友的信息
having to give information about my friends.
你不是說過"華爾街上無朋友"嗎
Like you said, "There's no friends on Wall Street." Right?
是的  是的  沒錯
Right. Right. Exactly.
這件事也有好的一面  親愛的
There's a silver lining to that, too, honey.
因為他們說最終
Because they said eventually...
最終所有人
eventually everyone's
都必須提供關于這個案件的信息
gonna have to give information on this case.
所以到了最后
So, at the end of the day,
我告密的事也不算什么了
it might not even be a factor. You know?
這是好消息  對吧
Well, that's good news. Right?
沒錯  沒錯
Yeah, yeah.
我真為你高興
I'm really happy for you.
什么叫為我高興啊  親愛的
What do you mean, happy for me, sweetheart?
你應該為咱倆高興啊  對吧
You should be happy for the both of us. Right?
-沒錯  -好的
- Yeah, right. - All right.
過來  寶貝
Come here, baby.
親親我  甜心
Give me a kiss, sweetheart.
喬丹
Jordan...
來吧  寶貝
Oh, come on, baby.
我都好久沒跟你做愛了  求你了
I haven't made love to you in so long. Please.
-喬丹  不要  -親愛的  求你了
- No. Jordan, stop it. - Come on, honey, please.
不要  喬丹  夠了
No! Jordan, stop it!
我第一眼看到你就愛上你了
I've loved you since the moment I saw you.
我他媽的恨死你了  喬丹
I fucking hate you, Jordan.
-給我下去  -寶貝  別這樣
- Get off me! - Baby... don't do that.
你知道我有多愛你  對吧
You know how much I love you, right?
別這樣對我了  親愛的  求你了
Stop that, sweetie. Please.
你想上我嗎  喬丹
You wanna fuck me, Jordan?
你想上我嗎
You wanna fuck me?
很好
Good.
來吧
Go ahead.
盡管來上我吧
Go ahead and fuck me.
我要你狠狠地上我
I want you to fuck me real hard.
我要你把這當成是最后一次一樣操我
I want you to fuck me like it's the last fucking time.
-你為什么要這么動  -來啊
- Why are you moving like that? - Come on.
別動
Please hold still.
因為我想讓你射給我啊  寶貝
'Cause I want you to come for me, baby.
來啊  寶貝
Come on, babe.
射給我啊  寶貝啊
Come for me, baby.
我要你把這當做是最后一次一樣
I want you to come for me
狠狠地射給我
like it's the last fucking time.
-是嗎  -是
- Yeah? - Yeah.
來啊  寶貝  射給我  寶貝
Come on, baby. Come for me. Come for me, baby.
來啊  寶貝
Come on, baby.
-你喜歡這樣  -是啊
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-寶貝  射啊  -你想讓我射給你
- Yeah, baby, come. - You want me to come for you?
是
Yeah.
-你想讓我射給你  -是
- You want me to come for you? - Yeah!
你想讓我射給你嗎
Huh? You want me to come for you?
天啊  寶貝
Oh, God, baby. Yeah!
天啊  天啊
Oh, God. Oh, God.
天啊
Oh, God.
上帝啊
Jesus.
寶貝
Oh, baby.
真是爽死了
That was so fucking great!
天啊
Oh, God!
這是最后一次了
That was the last time.
什么意思  寶貝
What do you mean, baby?
我是說  剛才那就是我們的最后一次了
I mean that was the last time we ever have sex.
你在說什么呀
What are you talking about?
我要離婚
I want a divorce.
你這是什么意思  你要離婚
What do you mean, you want a divorce?
你在說什么啊  你要離婚
What's that supposed to mean, you want a divorce?
放開我  我要跟你離婚
Get off me! I want a divorce.
你剛剛才跟我上完床
You just made love to me.
你他媽的是什么毛病啊
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我不愛你了  喬丹
I don't love you anymore, Jordan!
你不愛我了
Oh, you don't love me?
你已經不愛我了
You don't love me anymore, huh?
你還真會挑時候啊
Well, isn't that just fucking convenient for you!
我現在被聯邦政府起訴
Now that I'm under federal indictment,
腳脖子上還綁著個電子監控器
with an electronic bracelet around my ankle,
然后你他媽的決定不愛我了
now you decide you don't fucking love me anymore.
-是嗎  -不  不
- Is that right? - No, no.
你到底是什么人啊  說啊
What kind of person are you? Tell me.
是你娶的我
You married me!
你這話是他媽的什么意思
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
喬丹  接下來這么安排
Jordan, this is how it's gonna go.
孩子的監護權歸我
I'm gonna take custody of the kids.
你同意離婚  我還可以讓你探望孩子
If you agree to the divorce right now, I will allow visitation.
-好嗎  你別想著跟我爭  -天啊
- Okay? Don't try to fight it. - Oh, my God.
我們好聚好散  也能給咱倆省點錢
It'll save us both a lot of money
而且我覺得你以后用錢的地方還多著呢
and I got a feeling you're gonna need it.
你別想帶走我的孩子  親愛的
You're not taking my kids, sweetheart. You hear me?
我已經找律師問過了
I've already talked to the lawyer.
他說就算你不被定罪
He said even if you don't get convicted,
孩子的監護權歸我的可能性也很大
I've got a good chance of getting them.
我告訴你
I got news for you.
你他媽的別想帶走我的孩子
You're not fucking taking my children,
你這個惡毒的蕩婦
you vicious fucking cunt, you!
操你  你他媽的臭婊子
Fuck you, you fucking bitch!
你他媽的別想帶走我的孩子
You're not fucking taking my goddamn fucking kids!
聽見了嗎  操你
You hear me? Fuck you!
你他媽的別想帶走我的孩子
You're not fucking taking my fucking kids!
該死的臭婊子
Fucking bitch!
該死的雞
Fucking whore!
他媽的臭婊子  該死的雞
Fucking bitch! Piece of shit fucking whore!
看看你的德行  喬丹
Look at yourself, Jordan.
你變態
You're sick!
你就是個變態
You're a sick man!
操你  我告訴你  你別想帶走孩子
Fuck you! I told you, you're not taking my fucking kids!
你認為我會讓我的孩子待在你身邊嗎
You think I would let my kids near you?
看看你這個德行
Look at yourself!
你知道我的律師怎么說嗎
You know what my lawyer said?
我律師說你要蹲二十年大牢  喬丹
My lawyer said that you're going to prison for 20 years, Jordan.
二十年啊  你別打算再見到孩子了
Twenty fucking years! You're never gonna see the kids again!
你以為我再也見不到……
You don't think I'm not gonna see my...
不  我才不會讓你接近我的孩子呢
No, I'm not fucking letting you near my kids!
你以為我再也見不到我自己的孩子了
You don't think I'm gonna see my fucking kids again, huh?
你他媽的別碰他們
Don't you fucking touch them!
你他媽的別碰我
Don't you fucking touch me!
寶貝  爸爸帶你出去玩  好嗎
Sweetheart? You're coming on a trip with Daddy, all right?
你要跟爸爸出去玩了
You're coming on a trip with Daddy.
你別他媽的碰她  喬丹
Don't you fucking touch her, Jordan.
我對天發誓  我他媽的會宰了你的
I swear to God, I will fucking kill you!
沒事的  寶貝
It's all right, baby.
爸爸帶你出去玩  好嗎
You and Daddy are gonna go on a little trip together, okay?
-咱倆一起去玩  -瓦奧萊特
- A little trip together. - Violet!
瓦奧萊特
Violet!
-去拿鑰匙  去拿鑰匙  -好的
- Get the key! Get the key! - I got it!
喬丹  你他媽的趕緊
Jordan, you open this fucking door
-把門打開  開門  -系上安全帶
- right now! Open the door! - Put your seat belt on.
好了  把腿放進來
There you go. Get your legs in.
我要帶她走了
I'm taking her with me!
我告訴你  我要把她帶走了  臭婊子
I told you I'm taking her with me, you fucking bitch!
你阻止不了我  你阻止不了我
You're not gonna stop me! You're not gonna stop me!
咱們去玩  寶貝
We're going on a little trip, honey.
不  不
No! No!
你給我滾開
Get the hell out of here!
別煩孩子
Leave that baby alone!
瓦奧萊特  車庫門  把車庫門關上
Violet! Garage door! Close it!
媽咪
Mommy!
-給我下車  -把門給我打開
- Get out of here! - Open the fucking door!
媽咪
Mommy!
不
No!
天啊  上帝啊
Oh, Lord! Oh, my heavens...
去抱孩子
Get the baby!
內奧米  去抱孩子
Naomi, get the baby!
-媽咪  -寶貝  沒事了
- Mommy. - Honey, it's okay.
沒事了
It's gonna be okay.
喬丹先生已經瘋了
Oh, Mr. Jordan has lost his mind.
-寶貝……  -沒事的  親愛的
- Baby... - It's all right, honey.
她沒事吧
She all right?
Is she all right?
你搞什么呀
What's the matter with you?
她沒事吧
Is she all right?
第一自然段
Paragraph one.
被告將對美國聯邦地方法院
The defendant shall plead guilty
美國東區地方法院
to all counts of the indictment currently pending against him
對其提起的一切指控
in the United States District Court
認罪
for the Eastern District of New York.
第二自然段
Paragraph two.
講話自然點
Talk normally.
被告將參與臥底行為……
The defendant shall participate in undercover activities...
呼吸自然點
Breathe normally.
包括隨身佩戴錄音設備  也就是竊聽器
... including wearing a recording device, also known as a wire...
五分鐘以后  你就會忘記它的存在了
After five minutes, you'll forget you even have it on.
配合調查……
...in conjunction with the investigation...
太他媽的殘忍了
Fucking brutal.
少抱怨了
Quit your bitching.
第四自然段  被告嚴禁繼續
Paragraph four. The defendant must not commit,
或是試圖繼續犯下任何進一步的罪行
or attempt to commit, any further crimes.
拜托  直接讓我簽了這該死的文件吧
Please. Let me just sign the fucking thing already.
謝謝
Thank you.
簽在這就行了
Just here?
那就行了
That'd be good.
謝謝
Thank you.
我根本別無選擇
It wasn't even a choice.
接下來的六個小時里  我列了張名單
For the next six hours, I came up with a list.
朋友  敵人  商業伙伴
Friends, enemies, business associates.
所有曾認識我的人或是
Anybody who'd ever known me or
從我這里得到過一丁點股票建議的人
taken so much as a stock tip.
狼哥  狼哥
Wolfie! Wolfie! Wolfie!
名單上的第一個人就是唐尼
The first name on the list was Donnie.
喬丹  你知不知道
Jordan, do you know how
你能回來是件多好的事
good it is to have you back in this office?
你不在的時候一切都感覺不一樣了
It's not the same when you're gone.
很悲傷的感覺  你明白嗎  像是
It's sad, you understand? It's like...
該死的史蒂夫·麥登
That fucking Steve Madden, huh?
我無法……
I can't...
我對天發誓  我連想都不能想這件事
Swear to God, I can't even think about it.
我每次一想到他  我就氣得血液沸騰
Every time I think about him, my blood boils.
我都不能說他的名字
I can't even say his name.
-我明白  -太惡心了
- I know. - It's, like, disgusting.
我跟他一起長大  他卻這樣背叛我
I grew up with this guy and he betrays me like that.
他后來有沒有……
He ever get back to you about that...
有沒有跟你說過那個賬戶的事
about that account?
別說對自己不利的話
我戴著竊聽器呢
你記得的
You remember.
差不多有四五百萬的  對吧
It was like four or five mil, something like that, right?
他應該要退還四五百萬  對吧
He was supposed to kick back four or five mil, was it?
實際上  我那個時候
Actually, I was...
我那時候嗑藥磕得一團糟  喬丹
I was fucked up, Jordan,
-所以我什么都不記得了  -是啊
- so I don't really remember. - Yeah.
是啊  你個傻瓜
Yeah, right. Stupid.
如果他打來  你就通知我  好嗎
Well, if he calls you, you make sure and contact me, okay?
-當然了  -好
- Yeah. Of course. - Yeah.
當然  當然
Of course, yeah. No, of course.
最后那塊黃獅魚你還吃不吃  伙計
You gonna eat that last piece of yellowtail, bud?
不吃了  都給你吧
No, it's all yours.
我能蘸這個嗎
Can I get this?
那么  還有什么……
So, what else is...
內奧米和其它一切都還好嗎
Well, how's Naomi and everything?
你也知道
You know how it is.
她現在恨死我了
She hates my fucking guts.
希爾迪怎么樣  她還好嗎
How's Hildy? Good?
她還活著  所以活的也很糟
She's still alive, so my life is fucked, you know?
明白
Yeah.
喬丹先生
Mr. Jordan.
喬丹先生  有客人找您
Mr. Jordan, you got a visitor.
什么
What?
有客人找您
You've got a visitor.
你馬上穿好衣服
I need you to get dressed.
為什么  這是搞什么
Why? What the fuck's going on?
你要去蹲監獄了
You're going to jail.
好吧
All right.
我去穿衣服
I'll get some clothes on.
我們幫你
We'll give you a hand with that.
好吧
Okay.
聯邦調查局
FBI!
所有人坐下
Everybody sit down.
把手舉起來  不許出聲
Put your hands where they can be seen, and shut up!
你他媽的別碰我
Don't you fucking touch me.
你他媽的放開我
Get your fucking hands off me!
不許離開你們的座位
Don't get out of your seats!
這他媽的可是香奈兒
It's fucking Chanel!
我告發了所有人
I gave up everyone.
作為回報
And in return,
我在內華達的一個我從來沒聽說過的
I got three years in some
鬼地方蹲了三年
hellhole in Nevada I'd never even heard of.
就像我父親瘋狂麥克斯曾經說過的
Like my pops, Mad Max, had said,
"惡有惡報"
"The chickens had come home to roost."
隨便他什么意思吧
Whatever the fuck that means.
我希望法官大人認同
I hope Your Honor would agree
貝爾福先生在跟聯邦調查局合作方面
that Mr. Belfort has distinguished himself
有出色的表現
in terms of his cooperation.
在貝爾福先生的協助下
Mr. Belfort has helped the government win convictions
政府給二十四余名重罪犯定了罪
of over two dozen serious offenders
并且追回了成百上千萬美金
and helped them recover millions of dollars
用以補償受害者
to be made available for restitution to their victims.
法庭對被告的判決為
The sentence of the court shall be
在聯邦監獄關押三十六個月
36 months in federal prison.
請把被告押回去
Please remand the defendant.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
沒關系
That's okay.
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特  貝爾福獲刑
我承認  當我們到監獄的時候
I'm not ashamed to admit it.
我快嚇死了
When we arrived at the prison,
我不覺得這有什么丟人的
I was absolutely terrified.
貝爾福  站起來
Belfort, on your feet.
但實際上我用不著害怕
But I needn't have been.
有那么很短的一瞬間
You see, for a brief fleeting moment,
我忘了自己曾富得流油了
I'd forgotten I was rich.
而我住在消費的世界里
And I lived in a place where everything was for sale.
你難道不想學一下怎么把它們賣掉嗎
Wouldn't you like to learn how to sell it?
聽好了  我這輩子見過不少混蛋
So listen. I've met some bad motherfuckers in my life.
搖滾明星  專業運動員  黑幫分子
I'm talking about rock stars, professional athletes, gangsters.
真的是一些壞得透頂的混蛋
I'm telling you, some real bad motherfuckers.
但是這家伙  我的好朋友
But this guy, my good friend,
喬丹·貝爾福先生真的是
Mr. Jordan Belfort, is the single
我這輩子遇見過的最最最最最壞的混蛋了
baddest motherfucker I have ever met.
所以我現在希望你們
So I want you right now
向我的好朋友  世界上最棒的銷售員
to give a warm Auckland, New Zealand welcome
獻上新西蘭奧克蘭最誠摯的歡迎
for my good friend and the world's greatest sales trainer,
有請喬丹·貝爾福先生
Mr. Jordan Belfort!
謝謝你們
Thank you.
向我推銷這支筆
Sell me this pen.
這是……
It's...
這是一支很棒的筆
It's an amazing pen.
對于專業人士來說  這是一支……
For professionals, it's a...
向我推銷這支筆
Sell me this pen.
這是支好筆
Well, it's a nice pen.
你可以用這支筆
You can use the pen
記下生活的點點滴滴  這樣一來你就能
to write down thoughts from your life so you can...
向我推銷這支筆
Sell me this pen.
那個……
Well...
這支筆很好用  我個人也很喜歡
This pen works and I personally love this pen...